<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>React on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/react/</link><description>Recent content in React on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 10:22:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/react/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Html to React</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/09/html-to-react/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 10:22:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/09/html-to-react/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing new development in my offtime and i&amp;rsquo;m totally enjoying the challenges and hurdles. I wanted to share an interesting problem that I solved, it is a small part on a project that is not public yet (as of 2021 SEP).
Problem I have a htmlString that I have to convert to react elements.
but why?&amp;hellip; the main reasons were
I have a react wrapper, that enhances the dom-elements.</description></item><item><title>Frontend Updates &amp; Rinku Project Upgrade</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/05/react-updates-rinku-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 20:21:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/05/react-updates-rinku-upgrade/</guid><description>Hi!, Like I mentioned in my last update, I took a break from everything ( a month and 3 weeks), the reason behind me missing my post on past month(april). I still had to do office work though, but its&amp;rsquo; alright because it was fun. The time off that I took was the best decision in a while, It helped me rethink priorities.
Like I said in march post 2021, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting with new Time management in mind.</description></item><item><title>Publishing Npm Package</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/11/publishing-npm-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 11:47:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/11/publishing-npm-package/</guid><description>Personal Update: I finally managed to change my github username with all its dependencies to aghontpi, it was less work than I expected. Gosh, Its been 6 months already..since I decided to change my username. Incase my future self is wondering, its still work from home, probablly will go chennai after new years&amp;rsquo; i.e 2021.
This month was boring as hell in terms of office work, since I had to work on Extjs, I introduced some flare into it, but making it similar to react, because of this, it much easier to work on.</description></item><item><title>Rinku</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/07/rinku/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 19:22:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/07/rinku/</guid><description>Hi! hope you are doing well future me!,
I&amp;rsquo;m well in the comfort of my home, the pandemic isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet, the cases are increasing day by day, infact today, as I am wiriting this, newly infected patients is over 6.5k. The past few weeks has been productive, I&amp;rsquo;m loving what I am doing, learning new stuff, doing a little of reversing at times, Oh snap, I forgot, my harddisk died on me, it was not fun(thank god important stuff were already on a server backed up), had to replace that with an ssd.</description></item></channel></rss>