<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>npm on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/npm/</link><description>Recent content in npm on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:25:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/npm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom CSS Utility - npm package - Open source</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/11/nov-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/11/nov-2025/</guid><description>Intro For my projects, I use reset.css and a set of utility classes without external libraries. (which I learnt from my prev company, I learnt a lot from there, when I joined a big company.. it was not the same, enterprise wise its different yea..sure but it has its pros and cons), I move them from project to project. This eliminates it and makes it easier to maintain and view the docs.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Dnd Email Editor</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/10/open-source-dnd-email-editor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 10:48:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/10/open-source-dnd-email-editor/</guid><description>I created a drag and drop email editor, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it for the past month. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun to work on, I completed it for first release, I&amp;rsquo;ll shed some light on the challenges I faced and how I solved them.
Why&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; What&amp;rsquo;s why build this?
No free editors/open source editors that does the job,
but why not profit?
Not interested, I believe in Open Source.</description></item><item><title>Publishing Npm Package</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/11/publishing-npm-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 11:47:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/11/publishing-npm-package/</guid><description>Personal Update: I finally managed to change my github username with all its dependencies to aghontpi, it was less work than I expected. Gosh, Its been 6 months already..since I decided to change my username. Incase my future self is wondering, its still work from home, probablly will go chennai after new years&amp;rsquo; i.e 2021.
This month was boring as hell in terms of office work, since I had to work on Extjs, I introduced some flare into it, but making it similar to react, because of this, it much easier to work on.</description></item></channel></rss>