<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jellyfin on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/jellyfin/</link><description>Recent content in Jellyfin on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:49:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/jellyfin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Set Up Nginx and SSL for My Media Server and Torrent</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/12/how-i-configure-nginx-for-my-server-and-torrent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:49:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/12/how-i-configure-nginx-for-my-server-and-torrent/</guid><description>Context This post is a nginx configurations of my How I replaced Netflix and started using my media server for over 2 years now
config of jellyfin We already run jellyfin inside podman and expose the service on port 8096, so we use nginx to handle requests to domain &amp;lsquo;media.bluepie.in&amp;rsquo;, which connects to jellyfin podman instance.
I point my domain (through domain provider) to the ip address of the server im running my jellyfin instance, then use nginx to serve the requests, the nginx configs are located inside config folders and are included in main file.</description></item><item><title>How I Replaced Netflix and Have Been Using My Media Server for Over 2 Years</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/11/self-hosted-netflix-replacer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/11/self-hosted-netflix-replacer/</guid><description>Feasibility Can I host Netflix on my own? of course yes, many open source software offers similar functionality, you can set it to work only inside your home network or make it available throughout the internet.
I already own a server, I rent out a server for hosting my development activities, so why not use that server as a media server, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to run just inside the home LAN, I want it to be exposed to the internet, of course with required security measures.</description></item></channel></rss>