<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bluepie&#39;s Journal on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/</link><description>Recent content in Bluepie&#39;s Journal on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:25:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom CSS Utility - npm package - Open source</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/11/nov-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/11/nov-2025/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my projects, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://meyerweb.com/eric/tools/css/reset/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reset.css&lt;/a&gt; and a set of utility classes without external libraries. (which I learnt from my prev company, I learnt a lot from there, when I joined a big company.. it was not the same, enterprise wise its different yea..sure but it has its pros and cons), I move them from project to project. This eliminates it and makes it easier to maintain and view the docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted a minimal CSS utility that provides just basic features to get started quickly without the bloat of larger frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-did&#34;&gt;What I did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the background and the context, I was in the process of changing the UI/Frontend of an existing project. I moved all the reset css to a file, then wrote all the utilities to a separate file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the idea of publishing the same, so I moved all the scss code from the main project, put it inside a new folder, initialised it with a package config and bundled it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://rollupjs.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rollup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this current state, I could not make it public because&amp;hellip; first I had to decouple the existing logic from the codebase to the project, then I looked at the docs and with help of ai, wrote helper functions and saw the standard and fixed my implementations and made it ready for publishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-build-them&#34;&gt;How I build them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightforward, if you look at them.. gosh the tooling came a long way since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gulpjs.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;gulp js&lt;/a&gt; tooling era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt; &amp;quot;clean&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;rimraf dist docs/.vitepress/dist&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;build:theme&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;rollup -c&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;docs:dev&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;vitepress dev docs&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;docs:build&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;pnpm run build:theme &amp;amp;&amp;amp; vitepress build docs&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;docs:preview&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;vitepress preview docs&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;format&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;prettier --write .&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;build&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;pnpm run clean &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pnpm run build:theme &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pnpm run docs:build&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-install-use-it&#34;&gt;How to install &amp;amp; use it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;; it&amp;rsquo;s here &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/minimal-css-utility&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.npmjs.com/package/minimal-css-utility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the following command with npm or other package managers, or you can even use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Glossary/CDN&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CDN&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;link
rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot;
href=&amp;quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/minimal-css-utility/dist/min.css&amp;quot;
/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;npm install minimal-css-utility
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then import this in your main css file,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;@import &#39;minimal-css-utility/dist/min.css&#39;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;css-scoping&#34;&gt;CSS Scoping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added the support to have css scopes, what this means is I can have multiple css frameworks and work on the same codebase, my project won&amp;rsquo;t interfere with anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more on how to implement it here. I&amp;rsquo;ve added an example here for &lt;a href=&#34;https://react.dev/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;react&lt;/a&gt;, but it should be the same for vanilla or other frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/getting-started/scoping.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/getting-started/scoping.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-docs&#34;&gt;The docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://vitejs.dev/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vite&lt;/a&gt;, I saw the documentation system by them, it was quite nice to navigate through the docs and easy to setup, I find that sometimes I have to navigate to the codebase and look up a particular css class and probably change it, So I put the docs inside the same folder and wrote the generation scripts inside the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.npmjs.com/cli/v10/configuring-npm/package-json&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;package.json&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing the docs was very fun, Include my css file and use it&amp;hellip; like how a user would. Because of this&amp;hellip; I was able to figure out
multiple wrong implementations, I was using them with wrong implementations all this time everywhere, I didnt realise it was wrong since I was just copying and moving these source files from one place to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;check source examples here:
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aghontpi/minimal-css-utility/blob/main/docs/utilities/sizing.md?plain=1&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aghontpi/minimal-css-utility/blob/main/docs/utilities/sizing.md?plain=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;check some of the rendered examples there,
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/utilities/positioning.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/utilities/positioning.html&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/layout/grid.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/layout/grid.html&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/utilities/flexbox.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bluepie.in/minimal-css-utility/utilities/flexbox.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing the above gave me the idea that this is how I would test this: visually identify the issues after taking build, I can just skim through the docs of the places where I made changes in source code of utility classes and check only those affected places in docs, since I used the build from the css utility class, these changes would come here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked up online, major big css frameworks employ similar and better versions of what I just said and there are testing frameworks that just do that, for ex: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/garris/BackstopJS&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BackstopJS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-like-the-most-from-the-docs&#34;&gt;What I like the most from the docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the search functionality a lot, click search button or use the shortcut and starting to type, you see only the relevant information and takes me right to the spot, what and where I was looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/nov-2025/docs-ref.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-release-future-versions&#34;&gt;The release &amp;amp; Future versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, it&amp;rsquo;s on npm and github, If I use additional things to my custom ui, I will add it here, make a new release, so it can be upgraded with version specific installs from npm. so it wont break anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;npm: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/minimal-css-utility&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.npmjs.com/package/minimal-css-utility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;github: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aghontpi/minimal-css-utility/releases&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aghontpi/minimal-css-utility/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-updates&#34;&gt;Personal updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last month&amp;rsquo;s feeling of just an excel sheet because it happened to a person close to me. Their problem is still not resolved it&amp;rsquo;s the second half of Nov.. like heck?. the people who were in charge wrote a lame-ass email of the same thing after 1 month of delay, basically they came back after enjoying diwali and holidays, enjoying their leaves, personally I think I thought.. they just didn&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with all this. The managers who were idiotic saying to a person who was in that situation &amp;ldquo;Now you are the one to help us&amp;rdquo;, just after hearing the announcement, the numbness of that lady is outstanding, I hope she gets what she deserves, karma will come back for her. After the vz announcement you will read below, for me atleast to see they are having the same kind of feeling they put the person within a short span of time was a suprise. I dont know/biast on whats the outcome will be, but yea was a suprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amplified by this month&amp;rsquo;s announcement of VZ, search Vz, Nov, 2025 (me) you will remember and find it in news articles. Do you remember all the people packing? Im sure you do, For me, I was thinking I was doing my job, makeing progress every day, handling my releases well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ugly of corporate world, a lot of vendors make the company shit, the developers dont know what they are doing, they are just here for the paycheck with the minimal/ no amount of work, there is no engineering happening even in higher and lower levels, seeing all the frenzy when an announcement is made for budget cuts and etc, they started putting effort again.. I was expecting a level of standard and I can&amp;rsquo;t put a single word to explain it.. again going back.. I think its better for me to just be my own boss, I can&amp;rsquo;t expect these people to have the same level of dedication, integrity..etc&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>&#34;Slop Generators - Make no mistake, they cannot think&#34;, as of Nov 25th, 2025</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/10/oct-2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 19:36:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/10/oct-2025/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quote-i-liked-from-asahi-linux&#34;&gt;Quote I liked from Asahi Linux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read the quote, in an open source AI contribution page, exact word for word, &lt;a href=&#34;#Quote I liked from Asahi Linux&#34;&gt;quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://asahilinux.org/docs/project/policies/slop/#its-just-matmul&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://asahilinux.org/docs/project/policies/slop/#its-just-matmul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is very easy to get caught up in the hype that bad actors have built around Slop Generators. The anthropomorphic presentation of Slop Generators as &amp;ldquo;agents&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;assistants&amp;rdquo; is a very deliberate attempt to manufacture consent for their integration into workforces at the expense of human interaction. The implication of some higher degree intelligence or sentience is very much deliberate, and it is very much false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, they cannot think. They cannot reason. They cannot take into account context. They don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;know&amp;rdquo; things or have a sense of humour or any of the other human-centric qualities bad actors would have you believe of them. Slop Generators are a chain of matrices in a stochastic system. The output of a Slop Generator is nothing more than a statistical calculation, where the next word to be generated is decided by an opaque probabilistic function dependent on previously generated words. This is fundamentally the same mathematics that is used to predict the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Slop Generator cannot assess the veracity of its claims, nor can it ever tell you that it simply does not know something. Slop Generators are often confidently incorrect as a result, and require brow-beating to admit a mistake. They are therefore highly inappropriate tools in contexts where truth and correctness are of utmost importance, and when the user is not already highly knowledgeable and confident in the problem area. This presents a bit of an issue for Slop Generators; if the user is already highly knowledgeable and confident in the problem area, then why ask the Slop Generator in the first place?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;coming-to-reality&#34;&gt;Coming to reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspecting UI source code of the websites I visit, also the open source projects I see, I see the source code of them as well, it&amp;rsquo;s easy as of Oct 2025 to identify if it was generated by AI. Unless explicitly told not to generate things with Tailwind, it mostly will be Tailwind with its absurd twisted ways of using it. When you see it, you will know it&amp;rsquo;s not written by a human or even reviewed by a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to accept the fact, AI is everywhere, using it is productive, yes, but there has to be some oversight, otherwise.. it gets to the point of no return, when at one point in the future, everything is so convoluted by AI, humans can&amp;rsquo;t jump in between and fix it. I think of it like compilers, before people used to write machine code, then compilers came along and simplified the process of writing code by providing a sort of language that we can use to write the programs and code in. Now will the same happen with AI? Will it become some sort of a compiler for programs? At the current state.. I don&amp;rsquo;t see it happening, but when you describe it, the output it does produce, so it&amp;rsquo;s a compiler?? Weird to think about it.. isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In news articles I see posts in between embedded in them, those are just random stories that are obviously AI generated.. just inserted so that people fall for it and click them. Next time I see it, I will take a screenshot and put it here.. heck sometimes even the news articles are entirely written by AI, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if they are getting reviewed by actual people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;will-i-use-ai-to-write-this-journal-for-me&#34;&gt;Will I use ai to write this journal for me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;m proud of is not using AI to write this blog/journal for me, I think there will be a time where written media, written by individuals will be sought after, because increasingly, the AI generated content is everywhere, eventually it might mimic human writing too. An update, I&amp;rsquo;ve found this after I wrote this: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/vrTrOCQZoQE?si=ytVmNdmNRWPk6yBx&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/vrTrOCQZoQE?si=ytVmNdmNRWPk6yBx&lt;/a&gt; (a video from Computerphile mentioning the same)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking and experimenting with AI. In some posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve used AI to generate featured image for the post, the one at the top, but I stopped and went back to me making one, then used them to check spelling and grammar. I think on 1 or 2 posts I used to change some paragraphs or write a poem which conveys another meaning as well, but that is about it, I stopped writing after I did that, I literally stopped writing for several months after I did that, like I lost motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who uses AI to crank out articles in medium, like importnat things you should know in spring boot, using AI in spring boot, top &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; most useful commands in git..etc and people read and like it too.. like how? U can ask ai the same thing.. but the thing is now AI can crawl things on the web, so its not like articles that people write are going to waste, its read by AI crawlers and given back to the users. Most people have transitionsed to using AI for getting their answer, they dont read blog/ go to forums anymore, unless its a specific niche or they have time to do the research, asking ai is faster and its giving an easy way out, and people&amp;rsquo;s brain will subconsioursly/ consiously choose the lazy route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;identifying-if-its-ai&#34;&gt;Identifying if its AI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that, if you inspect the source code of the applications, it can be easily identified that it&amp;rsquo;s AI, take Tailwind, at least till now, if you see some Cthulhu level sh** in your UI logic in Tailwind, it&amp;rsquo;s probably AI generated. I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I graduated just before the cusp of AI, enough to know what it&amp;rsquo;s like before AI and after AI, I have git commits and open source projects to prove!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are just a row in an Excel sheet, I read this so long ago from Hacker News, since then I&amp;rsquo;ve read countless articles from Hacker News and elsewhere. Someone close to me, got the same treatment, they got the boot/ asked to resign because of some government rules that does not apply to them, the people who validated it are incompetent, If they had put the minimal amount of effort, checked the facts, they would have easily known its not true.. Welp.. I feel they and a lot of others are just leeches in the company. I see a lot of people like this who just coast or do nothing in the company and just get salary every month. Sometimes I feel like why am I even working here, what was my goal? why don&amp;rsquo;t I become my own boss?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, the only thing that matters is your integrity, what you feel about it and how you process it and how you justify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, let&amp;rsquo;s end with a less serious note, I got a new monitor setup for my room, tried using 4k with my mac, it was god tier, I had so much space to work with, I got a 55inch mini led 144hz 4k display (monitor, but its a tv at that size), I sit reasonably far from the monitor, Everything is crystal clear, the responsiveness is awesome, you have to switch to pc mode (it has vrr). I loved working on that, when I came back to my chennai setup 27inch monitor, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t adapt to it for a week. I have so much productivity in that. Let me show you. Played some games on 4k, it was really good, if I was a small kid I would literally spend my whole day, but big buddy me, got responsibilities and grownup duties, I played ghost, its one of the best games imo, no comments on the 2nd ghost game though. I bought amazing spider man remake, played for a couple of hours, it was good, need to finish it after I retire? IDK maybe before that..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/oct-2025/my-desk-setup-2025.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was day 1 after my new setup, my desk is still a mess&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Better Downloader Self Hosted</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/09/september-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 22:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/09/september-2025/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Need a better downloader that is on a server somewhere, it should have segmented downloads, It can have mutliple connections to a single download file that can maximize download speeds, The second problem to solve is that the media server if something has to be downloaded and watched, it has to be a torrent file, if its a direct file, the server, currently I have to login to a server and download with wget or aria2 via terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding the right solution to selfhost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aria2/aria2&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aria2/aria2&lt;/a&gt; existence, I used to use this long ago when downloading things directly to server. it has a lot of features that I looked for and on top of that even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Command-line interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download files through HTTP(S)/FTP/SFTP/BitTorrent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Segmented downloading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and believe me there are lots more, check the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aria2/aria2&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github repo link&lt;/a&gt;.. i&amp;rsquo;ve provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-frontend&#34;&gt;The frontend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thought process is this, this is a command line utility, how will I use it with gui..? there are already similar projects which are called frontends for an already existing terminal utilites. so a quick google search, lead me to this project. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mayswind/AriaNg?tab=readme-ov-file&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mayswind/AriaNg?tab=readme-ov-file&lt;/a&gt; , I liked the ui and it proviced all the configs and how it can configured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iimage showing aria2 initial configuration&lt;/em&gt; notice the port of the service, its 443, since im running on https and behind reverse proxy. Notice the secret token, this is important, without this, the FE will fail to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/september-2025/initial-configuration.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;need-a-way-to-run-it&#34;&gt;Need a way to run it,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was ready to spend hours on this to configure, figure out how to integrate these too separate programs.. but then since it has a lot of popularity.. 10k+ starts on github, I searched for any existing solutions, that it might already have, which lead me to the finding of this project: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hurlenko/aria2-ariang-docker&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hurlenko/aria2-ariang-docker&lt;/a&gt;, Now I have an existing project that I can self host. I just need to run it on my server with custom configurations and reverse proxy it on my existing server which has nginx running. at some point I have to check out and configure caddy.. but thats for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image showing aria2 download options&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/september-2025/download-link.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;configurations&#34;&gt;Configurations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use podman to run all the services instead of docker, so based on the docker image, I came up with the following command to run it on my server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Docker/ Podman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;podman run -d \
--name=aria2-ui-idm \
-e ARIA2RPCPORT=6800 \
-e RPC_SECRET=&amp;lt;REDACTED&amp;gt; \
-p 5050:8080 \
-p 6800:6800 \
-v /mnt/torrents:/aria2/data \
-v /var/oled/aria2/config:/aria2/conf \
--restart unless-stopped \
docker.io/hurlenko/aria2-ariang:latest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next comes the nginx config, I use the following nginx configuration to reverse proxy the requests to the aria2 container. Port 5050 is the web ui port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-conf&#34;&gt; # Proxy requests to the Ariang Web UI
location / {
proxy_pass http://127.0.0.1:5050;
proxy_set_header Host $host;
proxy_set_header X-Real-IP $remote_addr;
proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $proxy_add_x_forwarded_for;
proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-Proto $scheme;
proxy_read_timeout 999999999;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the frontend has to connect to the aria2 rpc service, which is exposed on port 6800 on the container, so we are proxying that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-conf&#34;&gt; # Proxy WebSocket requests to the Aria2 RPC service
location /jsonrpc {
proxy_pass http://127.0.0.1:6800/jsonrpc;
proxy_http_version 1.1;
proxy_set_header Upgrade $http_upgrade;
proxy_set_header Connection &amp;quot;upgrade&amp;quot;;
proxy_set_header Host $host;
# Set a long timeout for the RPC connection
proxy_read_timeout 999999999;
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also configured ssl on the server, but ignoring it here on explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FE layer connect with the terminal utility through post request or websocket, we have to configure the first time we land on the Frontend UI, these requests have to be authenticated and have a secret token, that must be configured on the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image showing download options&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/september-2025/downloading-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;image showing segmented download&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/september-2025/downloading-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In combination with media server, torrent and downloader, Its easier for me to get anyting on the media server/ download anything that I need, I&amp;rsquo;ve also configured copy party on my server, so Its easy to manage, download/ uplaod files on my server now, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about it someday. A long waiting requirement that I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off..is finally done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-updates&#34;&gt;Personal updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought of holding off marriage, due to recent events, I think its best that I didn&amp;rsquo;t rush through marriage and take decisions drastically (I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this section on oct 15&amp;rsquo;th 2025). As for my counter part, she agreed on the same, though I initially asked her to wait, she also thinks waiting for now is the best way forward.. for people who dont&amp;rsquo; follow or in some weird case.. if I dont follow.. read back the previous posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to look back to this one day in the future and add comments/ updates and see how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using the best thinking models and not burn money (Jul 31st, 2025)</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/07/july-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 23:53:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/07/july-2025/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a dilemma, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay open ai the monthly 20$ subscription, but I want to use the latest and greatest model on some of the problems I have to reduce time. How can I achieve this? I&amp;rsquo;ve already mentioned in a previous writing last year.. that I use open api keys. I started using mobile and desktop clients with just the api keys. Couple months ago OpenAI also reduced the pricing of o3 model by 80%, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the ai very actively, trying to burn my credits as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deciding-on-a-budget&#34;&gt;Deciding on a budget.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to load my account with 6 dollars, on an estimate I thought I&amp;rsquo;d run out of credits within half a month. I can use o4-mini thinking for most tasks and o3 thinking model for only tough tasks questions. Nowadays I always default to thinking model o4-mini, it&amp;rsquo;s very cost effective. I told myself, I&amp;rsquo;m getting this alternate to one KFC ultimate savings bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ui&#34;&gt;The UI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chatgpt UI is clean and gives more control for devs, I like this UI, unfamiliar people might need to get used to it. It even shows the thinking tokens, at the time of writing.. only the openai web portal and the official api client shows the thinking tokens, if you use third party clients (more about this later on this post) for chat api.. we will not get the thinking tokens, we will just see the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/OpenAI-api_view.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-the-right-models-for-the-right-usage&#34;&gt;Using the right models for the right usage,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exclusively used openAI models alone, I stopped using google AI Studio and claude&amp;hellip; more context. I used google AI studio and claude occasionally to validate my solutions.. like my writing from last month about Ratelimiting with firestore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In chatgpt we have different models, For most of my use cases I use o4-mini, at the time of writing (31st july, 2025).. the latest thinking models from Open AI are O3 and o4 mini-high, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a table to compare the pricing from openAI portal &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/api/pricing/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpenAI API Pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(maybe below pricing details act like a snapshot in future&amp;ndash;for me or anyone&amp;ndash;looking back 10/20/..etc years from future)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinking models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Input Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cached Input Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Output Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;OpenAI o3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most powerful reasoning model with leading performance on coding, math, science, and vision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$2.00 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.50 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$8.00 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;OpenAI o4-mini&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Faster, cost-efficient reasoning model delivering strong performance on math, coding and vision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$1.10 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.275 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$4.40 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non thinking models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Input Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cached Input Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Output Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GPT-4.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Smartest model for complex tasks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$2.00 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.50 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$8.00 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GPT-4.1 mini&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Affordable model balancing speed and intelligence&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.40 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.10 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$1.60 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GPT-4.1 nano&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fastest, most cost-effective model for low-latency tasks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.100 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.025 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.400 / 1M tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always use thinking model.. cuz I think I am biased towards that, I need to change my view on this lol, my thinking is if reasoning model should be always better.. but I have seen videos from bytecloud (youtube) and reddit, that sometimes..it&amp;rsquo;s not always the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reason-i-don-t-use-openrouter&#34;&gt;Reason I don&amp;rsquo;t use OpenRouter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I don&amp;rsquo;t use OpenRouter is because of the money topup with tax, let me explain. When I load money in OpenAI api, I have a trick and can load all the money without tax, but when I try the same thing with OpenRouter.. it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. so that&amp;rsquo;s the only reason I&amp;rsquo;m not using OpenRouter. One thing to point out is I do use OpenRouter but I&amp;rsquo;m not loading money into it.. There are free reasoning models on OpenRouter, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried them like &amp;ldquo;DeepSeek: DeepSeek V3 0324 (free)&amp;rdquo; which is completely free and works great, but it&amp;rsquo;s just for testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-perplexity&#34;&gt;About perplexity,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perplexity made a stunt in India as far as I know.. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about other countries, they partnered with Airtel (a telecommunications company), they made a offer for all existing airtel users of all plans irrespective of prepaid/ postpaid/ broadband/ DTH&amp;hellip;etc and no restrictions on plans, that the users can claim perplexity Pro for 1 year at no charge. I always thought OpenAI, Anthropic (claude) &amp;amp; Google all caught up to Perplexity&amp;rsquo;s features.. and thought its userbase is declining, cuz the main feature of perplexity is the search integration with AI, all others major companies now have that option, I personally think this is a desperate move with fleeting userbase.. To harvest more data and use it? or show userbase is high to investors, though they said they had future funds for many more years.. idk im looking too deep into this. I tried to use it for some applications, it was okayish but not useful all the time. Recently you would have known I switched all my mobile numbers and broadband to jio.. not all, I still had one private number and my mom&amp;rsquo;s number didn&amp;rsquo;t get port over cuz of some complication due to I was not there while doing the porting (now she is on a year plan in airtel, still 10 months left I think)..so I used my mom&amp;rsquo;s number to claim the reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&amp;rsquo;t think they are using the models that is selected in pro mode under the hood.. at least not all the time, because the results are bad, when compared with the result of Open AI o3 (at the time of writing from before), the results form Open AI are better, You have to trust my word on this one, I didn&amp;rsquo;t save my responses, but maybe I can do that as part of another writing, or maybe you can have a personal test as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-in-office&#34;&gt;AI in Office&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In office at the time of writing this, I/ you work at VZ, we have gemini pro included (2.5 pro is the one that latest from google gemini) and github copilot. You can use it for any amount without limits. In github copilot there are lots of limitations inside the enterprise.. many public features are not even available inside, like mcp servers and custom chat modes, all the publicly available models, and even sometimes when the output of the AI is being generated.. the message from model gets flagged and the output is removed from the chat.. saying it contains public code and asking us to retry with different prompt. The company (leaders/ managers) is also hardly pushing for using AI for everything.. Even before they are saying.. I&amp;rsquo;m already on the train, I was on the first members to get access to github copilot and was using ever since. I was one of the beta testers for copilot inside vz as well, I still have that public github public account that we were testing it with. I provided many feedbacks during that time.. don&amp;rsquo;t know if its valuable for them or not.. during this period I changed entire teams/ organisations and went on promotion etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-openai-with-third-party-clients&#34;&gt;Using OpenAI with third party clients,&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried several self hosted opensource AI solutions so I can host on my server and then I can configure different API keys, be that may OpenAI, google or Anthropic. I tried running them in local but none of them satisfied my requirements, at the very end I choose to look for clients, apps on mac and iphone and found opencat &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencat.app/en/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;open cat&lt;/a&gt;, its lightweight and really fast and met all my requirements I use the free tier of the app, I can always mod the application as well if I want.. instead of paying monthly/ one time subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can configure different default models, currently I have o4 mini as the default model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display:flex; gap:10px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/open-cat-1.PNG&#34; style=&#34;height:500px; min-width:231px;&#34; alt=&#34;OpenCat screenshot 1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/open-cat-2.PNG&#34; style=&#34;height:500px; min-width:231px;&#34; alt=&#34;OpenCat screenshot 2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display:flex; gap:10px; margin-top:60px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/open-cat-3.PNG&#34; style=&#34;height:500px; min-width:231px;&#34; alt=&#34;OpenCat screenshot 3&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/open-cat-4.PNG&#34; style=&#34;height:500px; min-width:231px;&#34; alt=&#34;OpenCat screenshot 4&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So about the the 6$ I loaded up for AI usage, I got two months of usage out of it.. which is a lot compared to the 20$ monthly price tag by Open AI for chatgpt plus or more costlier tiers. The key is to be smart for on which model to use and how to consume them.. even if over reliant on ai models on certain tasks, use them smart by not exceeding the budget. During these two months I&amp;rsquo;ve also used it to create images and experimented with audio as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used around 300 requests, that accounts for about 2 million input tokens, again these are a mixture of all models.. like I said I only preferred to use reasoning models.. but a combination of different reasoning models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/openai-ai-input-token-usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage based on month-wise, openai&amp;rsquo;s month-wise usage report is weird, you can&amp;rsquo;t see the entire graph, you are literally given a sliding window of only one month..where you can see the requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My 6$ I was able to use it for 2 months and more.. I only counted till 5$, If I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it exclusively and the experiment it would have lasted even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/month-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/july-2025/month-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing to not use the time tracker from last month&amp;rsquo;s suggestion, its bit of a hassle, in between I tried to write everything physical (pen and paper), because I was forgetting the tasks too focused on one thing and forgetting, As an adult I have a lot of things to do all the time. Gotta reason with my decisions and spend time on things appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into reverse engineering in the last 30 days, it started off because I wanted to place designs on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/autocad/overview&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AutoCAD&lt;/a&gt;, My usage is only minimal, so I don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay for it (even the civil engineers that live here don&amp;rsquo;t pay for autocad), but I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to use cracks from the internet for the latest versions, I can crack it myself with enough effort and use it, the one thing that is different is.. I have to mod the apps on mac (previously I wrote on how to mod apps for macOS, but that was done on intel or x86 architecture from a 2022 post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aghontpi.github.io/2022/02/modding-a-macos-app/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;modding a macos app&lt;/a&gt;), that too on arm/ apple silicon. That was a learning curve for me, I also have to bypass the &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT204899&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SIP&lt;/a&gt; on macOS, disable it by booting into recovery mode/ keeping it active and patching it, debugging applications and cracking is only possible with disabling SIP because macOS won&amp;rsquo;t allow to debug application if that is turned on. I can do static analysis patch it that way, sign it with my custom certificate and run it..etc, I want to write about it separately.. Long story short, I made a patch that after checking if trial expired, instead of quitting, I made it so..its doesn&amp;rsquo;t quit. I also blocked internet for the cad software and patched the function that checks if trial license to false. This made the application work and I can use it without internet and all features work, the application does not quit, not does it complain about not having a license &amp;ndash; So going back to reverse engineering was lot of fun and I still want to do it..everyday, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find time everyday to do more things. One thing I found out was I need cad architecture, its only available on windows, my civil friend told me to use that software to design. I daily drive a apple silicon mac nowadays, so I had to run windows on it, surprisingly there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parallels.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Parallels&lt;/a&gt;, I tried the trial version and I tried windows 11 arm version on it and installed architecture trial (x86 version of this software) inside it and it worked, got no errors. Since I&amp;rsquo;m running that inside a VM I don&amp;rsquo;t have to patch it myself and spend another whole lot of time, I can use patches from the internet.. but the one thing that I have to patch is Parallels. currently its on trial period and works well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing helps alleviate a lot of things, future me reading. hope you got through this situation, My current plan is to write more. Also writing without ai support make me write more things. The things I&amp;rsquo;m writing are more of a personal journal so I don&amp;rsquo;t care about the quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building an IP Based Firebase Ratelimiter</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/06/building-an-ip-based-firebase-ratelimiter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/06/building-an-ip-based-firebase-ratelimiter/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a project that I wrote 7 years ago, its still running on firebase.. no hickups (I had to occusionally update to a new node lts environment).. but it still worsks, at the time of writing/ implementing, ratelimiter was not implemented, So everyonce in a while I see the request logs and I see some IPs hitting the server with 1000s of requests, judging from the rquest.. its easy to distinguish them as bots and scanners. I have to weed them out, but I have to write it in a way that will not use unnecessary firestore reads and writes. (yea I also used firestore for this probject)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;constraints-before-going-in&#34;&gt;Constraints before going in&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to make sure the firestore reads and writes are minimal, one read + one write per request, make sure automatic TTL purging keeps the firestore collection small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no Redis / Memcached layer here, so I can&amp;rsquo;t use them..(using them would be the best solution)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;schema-thats-need-to-be-changed-in-firestore&#34;&gt;Schema thats need to be changed in firestore&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new collection called &lt;code&gt;ip_throttle&lt;/code&gt;, we will use the document ID as the client IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-txt&#34;&gt;ip_throttle/
└─ {ipAddress} # document ID == client IP
• count number # requests in current window
• windowStart timestamp # start of the rolling window
• expiresAt timestamp # TTL field (auto‑deleted)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can leverage the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/firestore/native/docs/ttl&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Firestore TTL&lt;/a&gt; to automatically delete documents after the marked time, I have to mark my field &lt;code&gt;expiresAt&lt;/code&gt; in the TTL policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/june-2025/ttl_policy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;configurations-needed&#34;&gt;Configurations needed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follwing new configurations are needed, these doen&amp;rsquo;t involve code changes, In 5 minutes, we have 100 requests per IP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;firebase functions:config:set \
ratelimit.window_seconds=3600 \
ratelimit.max_hits=100
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For local emulation we can utilise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;firebase functions:config:get &amp;gt; .runtimeconfig.json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;implementing&#34;&gt;Implementing.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadsys I dont care if the project was in TS or not, I just choose js and go with it, back then I was still using TS, so I have to write the code in TS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ts&#34;&gt;
// abstraction to Firestore
const db = getConnection();
export async function rateLimiter(
ip: string,
windowSeconds = 3600, // just incase config does not exist
maxHits = 100 // just incase config does not exist
): Promise&amp;lt;boolean&amp;gt; {
const now = Timestamp.now();
const ref = db.collection(&amp;quot;ip_throttle&amp;quot;).doc(ip);
return db.runTransaction(async (tx: Transaction) =&amp;gt; {
const snap = await tx.get(ref);
// this is the first request we get from this IP
if (!snap.exists) {
tx.set(ref, {
count: 1,
windowStart: now,
expiresAt: Timestamp.fromMillis(
now.toMillis() + windowSeconds * 1000
),
});
logger.info(`IP ${ip}: first hit, record created.`);
return true;
}
const data = snap.data()!;
const ageMs = now.toMillis() - data.windowStart.toMillis();
// if the window has expired, reset it
if (ageMs &amp;gt; windowSeconds * 1000) {
tx.set(
ref,
{
count: 1,
windowStart: now,
expiresAt: Timestamp.fromMillis(
now.toMillis() + windowSeconds * 1000
),
},
{ merge: true }
);
logger.info(`IP ${ip}: window reset.`);
return true;
}
// if the request is within the window and within limit.
if (data.count &amp;lt; maxHits) {
tx.update(ref, { count: FieldValue.increment(1) });
logger.debug(`IP ${ip}: allowed (${data.count + 1}/${maxHits}).`);
return true;
}
// if the request is over the limit
logger.warn(
`IP ${ip}: throttled (${data.count}/${maxHits} in ${windowSeconds}s).`
);
return false;
});
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now to configure in router and sending out the response&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ts&#34;&gt; // existing code
const cfg = process.env;
const windowSeconds =
Number(cfg.RL_WINDOW_SECONDS) ||
Number(cfg.RATELIMIT_WINDOW_SECONDS) ||
3600;
const maxHits =
Number(cfg.RL_MAX_HITS) ||
Number(cfg.RATELIMIT_MAX_HITS) ||
5;
// check for ratelimit
if (!(await rateLimiter(ip, windowSeconds, maxHits))) {
res.status(429).json({ error: &amp;quot;Too many requests. Try again later.&amp;quot; });
return;
}
// original code
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-action-in-production&#34;&gt;In action in production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/june-2025/ip_throtle_in_action.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented is simple, effective and horizonally scalable all within firebase. No extra services, minimal reads and writes. I was able to implement and deploy to production in one single sitting. I had validated this with ai thinking models to find downsides, so it gave me a motivation to complete it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-updates&#34;&gt;Personal updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like with tradition, I have the personal updates here, I moved the personal section from top to the end of the post over the years. I wana write/ share soo much more.. remind myself more. Been travelling back and forth from work location &amp;amp; home, Been busy with work a lot, though I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take it too seriously, but when its a new skill, im all up for it, even if its people or project management, the one thing that pains is that there is a onshore team and sync with them is a pain (currently at the time of writing this you work in VZ), evey week, every months feels like an instant, its monday.. then its already friday, then its friday night start.. then its sunday night again with an instant. Feels like a cycle, The older I get, time does feel to go a lot faster. I even stopped playing the occasional gaming on the side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My timer tracking project (didnt make it open source yet) was a lot helpful over the months, but I think im lossing a grip on it, its too micro managementy, everytime I do something, I have to open and start and end it, feels like..its taking lot of time just to do that between each teask. So what I&amp;rsquo;ll do is stop using the time tracking app that I built for 1 or 2 months and see how I fare, If I can still be productive without it and can remeber and complete tasks, then its great..future me how is it going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I have commitments now and that too is a time sink, Im not keeping tabs on how much time Im spending, I think to myself on heindsight at the end of the week or during self refelction, small small actions, small pieces of time each day over the week.. adding up.. is a lot of time. but I can&amp;rsquo;t ignore it can I, now I know why my friends&amp;rsquo; changed behaviours is attributed to. Its nobody&amp;rsquo;s fault, thats just life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI slop is all over the place with the internet, its the worst. Manytimes I wonder.. I think for some/ many tasks, If people didn&amp;rsquo;t just overrely on AI, they can complete the job/ task way faster. Again on some tasks, its way easier with AI and reduces lot of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another trend Im noticing is, people are too much relient on AI to write a feature in a product or entire codebase/product. When something comes up later on the project, they don&amp;rsquo;t know howt to fix it, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it inside office projects (migration of entire codebase with AI and the people sturggle later), on the internet and word of mouth. Future me.. how its it going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the thing on may.. I&amp;rsquo;d be lying If I said its good/ going great. It is what it is, Trust on the process, I have to keep doing what I do, keep going, keep moving forward, things will fall in place, For now.. For this moment, I know, I have to make the right decision (Future me remember?) and the right decision I know is to stay without making any rash decisions..me reading..what happpended?..hope I/we are in a better place then..when are you reading this? 20&amp;rsquo;s, 30&amp;rsquo;s, 40&amp;rsquo;s?.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MVP vs SLC - Fixing Duplicate Tabs</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/05/fixing-duplicate-tabs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 21:22:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/05/fixing-duplicate-tabs/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been running into duplicate-tab problems across both my personal and office browsers. I needed a simple application that can detect duplicates and show a minimal UI to merge, close, or keep them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mvp-vs-slc&#34;&gt;MVP vs SLC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve followed the MVP approach for years, but this time I went with SLC: &lt;strong&gt;Simple, Lovable, Complete&lt;/strong&gt;. Rather than shipping a bare-bones, bug-ridden MVP, I wanted something small and meaningful that people genuinely love—and that feels complete out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the main user of this tool, my core requirement was clear&amp;hellip; whenever I open a tab that already exists—no matter which window(same profile, different profile&amp;hellip;etc) it’s in—I want to be notified immediately, so I can either jump to the original or keep both if I really need two copies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;designing-the-initial-version&#34;&gt;Designing the initial version&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first release, I kept everything ultra-lightweight (under 30 KB) and focused on a few key flows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Duplicate-Tab Detection&lt;br /&gt;
– I scan all open tabs using the Chrome Tabs API.&lt;br /&gt;
– If the current tab matches an existing URL, I show a toast that lets you &lt;strong&gt;Merge (Switch &amp;amp; Close)&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Keep &amp;amp; Go Back&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
– Dismissing the toast with the X still updates a badge counter showing your total duplicates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Badge &amp;amp; Popup Panel&lt;br /&gt;
– The badge counter turns red when duplicates exist.&lt;br /&gt;
– Clicking the extension icon opens a popup listing every open tab.&lt;br /&gt;
– From that panel you can &lt;strong&gt;Close&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Save &amp;amp; Close&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Save all &amp;amp; Close&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Session Save / Restore&lt;br /&gt;
– One-click &lt;strong&gt;Save all tabs &amp;amp; Close&lt;/strong&gt; to snapshot your session.&lt;br /&gt;
– Later, press &lt;strong&gt;Reopen all tabs&lt;/strong&gt; to bring everything back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-version-v1-3-0-and-beyond&#34;&gt;Next version: v1.3.0 and beyond&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;v1-3-0-highlights&#34;&gt;v1.3.0 Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Clickable Tabs&lt;br /&gt;
– You can now click any tab in the extension UI to navigate directly.&lt;br /&gt;
• URL Handling&lt;br /&gt;
– Fixed duplicate detection for URLs lacking &lt;code&gt;http://&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;https://&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
• Group Counts&lt;br /&gt;
– Every tab group shows a count badge.&lt;br /&gt;
• Fullscreen Dashboard Link&lt;br /&gt;
– “Open in fullscreen-mode” in the popup reuses an existing fullscreen window.&lt;br /&gt;
• Save All &amp;amp; Close / Restore All&lt;br /&gt;
– Quickly snapshot or restore entire sessions.&lt;br /&gt;
• HTML Import / Export&lt;br /&gt;
– Share sessions as HTML files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;source-code-and-chrome-web-store&#34;&gt;Source code and Chrome Web Store&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source code:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aghontpi/Tab-Options&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aghontpi/Tab-Options&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome Web Store:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/tab-options/kafdoidjnnbjciplpkhhfjoefkpfbplj&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/tab-options/kafdoidjnnbjciplpkhhfjoefkpfbplj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox Add-on:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/tab-options-open-source/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/tab-options-open-source/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes small things you do, doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a big thing.. but it does have a significant impact on our lives. The feeling of why am I even doing this..like your brain is somehwere else but still gotta push through everyday..if its study/ work..etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a lost soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When its hard, try foucs on things and writing. Read the book I got, thats all I got now, as im writing now at 2:01am. Its tough, My left eye twitching, everytime during the day when my eye twitch (which ______ said might be because of stressed about thinking about something, but I think it might be because you are going through something), I think you are going through the same stress &amp;amp; punishment but about 1000x more.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sub-Second Serverless Spring Boot/Reactor: Millisecond Cold-Starts via GraalVM</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/04/reducing-spring-reactor-java-project-cold-start-to-milliseconds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 10:18:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/04/reducing-spring-reactor-java-project-cold-start-to-milliseconds/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run several backend services built on different frameworks and languages, One of them being Spring Boot and Spring Reactor on my own Linux server. Recently, I asked myself: why not host these services on Google Cloud Run? Cloud Run offers a free tier for the first 2 million requests per month, but if I leave an instance running (with a minimum instance count), it costs around ₹200–₹500 monthly—something I&amp;rsquo;ve paid before. The problem is cold-start latency: a traditional Spring Boot/Reactor application can take over 15 seconds to start. My users will never wait that long. Once a Cloud Run instance starts, it stays alive for about 15 minutes of inactivity before shutting down. We can’t force users to endure a 15-second delay on first request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TL;DR — A &lt;strong&gt;Spring WebFlux&lt;/strong&gt; app compiled with &lt;strong&gt;GraalVM native-image&lt;/strong&gt;:
• cold-starts in ≈ 100 ms&lt;br /&gt;
• uses ≈ 90 MB RSS&lt;br /&gt;
• when deployed on Cloud Run behind Firebase Hosting, serves up to &lt;strong&gt;2 million requests/month for free&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-care-about-cold-starts&#34;&gt;Why Care About Cold-Starts?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If my Spring service gets only 10 000 requests a month, do I really need to pay for a min-instance on Cloud Run?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer: No. Even if each cold-start lasts 5 s, that’s only &lt;em&gt;125 vCPU-s&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;250 GiB-s&lt;/em&gt;, which is well below the free monthly quotas of 180 k vCPU-s and 360 k GiB-s. But latency matters for user-facing APIs: a 3–5 s delay is acceptable for CRON jobs, not for UI interactions. Enter &lt;strong&gt;GraalVM Native Image&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spring-boot-3-native-the-easy-path&#34;&gt;Spring Boot 3 Native (the Easy Path)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Spring Boot 3.4.x and the GraalVM build tools plugin, creating a native image is nearly zero-effort:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# build.gradle
plugins {
id(&amp;quot;org.springframework.boot&amp;quot;) version &amp;quot;3.4.1&amp;quot;
id(&amp;quot;org.graalvm.buildtools.native&amp;quot;) version &amp;quot;0.10.2&amp;quot;
}
# build and deploy
./gradlew clean bootBuildImage -PBP_NATIVE_IMAGE=true \
--image-name=gcr.io/$PROJECT/webflux-native
gcloud run deploy webflux-native \
--image gcr.io/$PROJECT/webflux-native \
--region us-central1 \
--platform managed \
--memory 512Mi \
--min-instances 0 \
--allow-unauthenticated
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Cold-start: 40–120 ms (0.25 vCPU)&lt;br /&gt;
• Memory on Cloud Run: 70–90 MB&lt;br /&gt;
• Code changes: none—your usual &lt;code&gt;@RestController&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Mono&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Flux&lt;/code&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spring Boot plugin runs the Ahead-Of-Time (AOT) engine, generates reflection hints automatically, and hands them to GraalVM. No manual JSON is required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quarkus-vs-micronaut-vs-spring-boot-native&#34;&gt;Quarkus vs Micronaut vs Spring Boot Native&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Framework&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Native Image Size&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cold-start (0.25 vCPU)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;DI Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Reactive API&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Migration Effort&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spring Boot 3 Native&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;70–85 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40–120 ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spring DI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reactor (Mono/Flux)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;★☆☆☆☆&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quarkus 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45–60 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25–80 ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CDI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mutiny / Vert.x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;★★★★☆&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Micronaut 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45–55 MB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20–60 ms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Compile-time DI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reactor, RxJava&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;★★★☆☆&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my code already uses WebFlux, Spring Boot Native was a five-minute flip. The others are powerful but require annotation and API rewrites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cost-breakdown&#34;&gt;Cost Breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Requests: first 2 million/month free (then \$0.40/M)&lt;br /&gt;
• CPU: first 180 000 vCPU-s/month free&lt;br /&gt;
• Memory: first 360 000 GiB-s/month free&lt;br /&gt;
• Idle min-instance: \$0.0000025/vCPU-s + \$0.0000025/GiB-s&lt;br /&gt;
• Egress: first 1 GB free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;br /&gt;
10 000 requests × 300 ms active ≈ 3 000 s total CPU time → ~63 000 free units → cost = \$0.00.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping one min-instance warm (0.25 vCPU / 512 MiB) costs ≈\$3.50/month—still trivial compared to user-facing latency improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-domain-binding&#34;&gt;Custom Domain Binding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bound my service to a custom domain in Cloud Run—a new feature available in the &lt;code&gt;us-central1&lt;/code&gt; region. DNS setup was straightforward, and Cloud Run automatically provisions an SSL certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-graalvm-for-my-existing-app&#34;&gt;Using GraalVM for My Existing App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have a mature Spring WebFlux application, so the GraalVM native-image path is the simplest. I chose GraalVM Community Edition 21:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install GraalVM JDK 21 and the &lt;code&gt;native-image&lt;/code&gt; component (or rely on Paketo buildpacks).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the &lt;code&gt;org.graalvm.buildtools.native&lt;/code&gt; plugin to &lt;code&gt;build.gradle&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;./gradlew clean bootBuildImage \
-Pprofile=cloudrun \
--no-daemon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deploy with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;gcloud run deploy my-service \
--image gcr.io/$PROJECT/my-service:latest \
--region us-central1 \
--allow-unauthenticated \
--min-instances=0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiccup-runtime-hints-for-reflection&#34;&gt;Hiccup: Runtime Hints for Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GraalVM performs aggressive tree-shaking and needs explicit hints for any reflection usage. In my case, I use &lt;code&gt;jjwt&lt;/code&gt; for JWT handling. Without hints, the native binary would fail at runtime, although development mode wouldn’t show errors. I provided a small registrar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;class JjwtRuntimeHints implements RuntimeHintsRegistrar {
private static final Class&amp;lt;?&amp;gt;[] JJWT_TYPES = {
DefaultJwtParser.class,
DefaultClaimsBuilder.class,
StandardSecureDigestAlgorithms.class,
StandardKeyOperations.class,
SignatureAlgorithm.class,
StandardEncryptionAlgorithms.class,
StandardKeyAlgorithms.class,
StandardCompressionAlgorithms.class,
KeysBridge.class
};
@Override
public void registerHints(RuntimeHints hints, ClassLoader cl) {
for (Class&amp;lt;?&amp;gt; type : JJWT_TYPES) {
hints.reflection().registerType(
type,
MemberCategory.INVOKE_PUBLIC_CONSTRUCTORS,
MemberCategory.INVOKE_PUBLIC_METHODS,
MemberCategory.DECLARED_FIELDS
);
}
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just enough to satisfy &lt;code&gt;io.jsonwebtoken&lt;/code&gt; internals—they get scanned at native-image build time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-artifact-sizes-and-cold-start&#34;&gt;Final Artifact Sizes and Cold-Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Docker image: 109 MB raw&lt;br /&gt;
• Compressed in registry: 76 MB&lt;br /&gt;
• Cold-start observed: 0.603 ms (including initial PostgreSQL connection to a remote host)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april-2025/artifactory-size.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april-2025/startuptime.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ci-cd-github-actions-workflow&#34;&gt;CI/CD: GitHub Actions Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I automated build &amp;amp; deploy with a GitHub workflow on every push to &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch, it will also work on pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;name: Build and Deploy Backend to Cloud Run
on:
push:
branches: [ main ]
paths:
- &#39;backend/**&#39;
- &#39;.github/workflows/backend.yml&#39;
....
- name: Authenticate to GCP
uses: google-github-actions/auth@v2
with:
credentials_json: ${{ secrets.GCP_SA_KEY }}
- name: Activate Service Account
run: gcloud auth activate-service-account \
--key-file=${{ secrets.GCP_SA_KEY }}
....
- name: Set up GraalVM 21
uses: graalvm/setup-graalvm@v1
with:
java-version: &#39;21&#39;
distribution: &#39;graalvm-community&#39;
....
- name: Build Native Image Locally
working-directory: backend/
run: |
./gradlew clean bootBuildImage \
-Pspring.profiles.active=cloudrun \
--imageName &amp;quot;${{ steps.image_details.outputs.path }}:${{ steps.image_details.outputs.version }}&amp;quot;
- name: Push Versioned Image
run: docker push &amp;quot;${{ steps.image_details.outputs.path }}:${{ steps.image_details.outputs.version }}&amp;quot;
- name: Tag &amp;amp; Push Latest
run: |
docker tag &amp;quot;${{ steps.image_details.outputs.path }}:${{ steps.image_details.outputs.version }}&amp;quot; \
&amp;quot;${{ steps.image_details.outputs.path }}:latest&amp;quot;
docker push &amp;quot;${{ steps.image_details.outputs.path }}:latest&amp;quot;
- name: Deploy to Cloud Run
uses: google-github-actions/deploy-cloudrun@v2
with:
service: opentasks-service
region: us-central1
...
project_id: ${{ secrets.GCP_PROJECT_ID }}
env_vars: |
...
SPRING_R2DBC_URL=${{ secrets.R2DBC_URL }}
SPRING_R2DBC_USERNAME=${{ secrets.R2DBC_USERNAME }}
secrets: |
...
SPRING_R2DBC_PASSWORD=db-pass:latest
flags: |
--memory=512Mi
--min-instances=0
--concurrency=250
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explanation of key parts:&lt;br /&gt;
• Triggers on pushes to &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; or manual dispatch.&lt;br /&gt;
• Authenticates with a GCP service account.&lt;br /&gt;
• Sets up GraalVM 21 community edition.&lt;br /&gt;
• Build the native image locally via &lt;code&gt;bootBuildImage&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
• Pushes both versioned and &lt;code&gt;latest&lt;/code&gt; tags to Artifact Registry.&lt;br /&gt;
• Deploys to Cloud Run with zero minimum instances, custom environment variables, and resource flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By combining Spring Boot 3’s native-image support with GraalVM, I reduced my service’s cold-start time from 15 seconds to under 1 second, fitting in under 100 MB of memory. This lets me use Cloud Run’s free tier without sacrificing user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.spring.io/spring-boot/docs/current/reference/html/native-image.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Spring Boot Native Reference Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.graalvm.org/latest/reference-manual/native-image/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GraalVM Native Image Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/run/pricing&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Cloud Run Free Tier &amp;amp; Pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m cutting down things over the past 15 days, focusing on items that I want to pursue. Thinking a lot… almost every day, making it a habit. My mind is too cluttered, and for reasons I’ll share in future posts. Future me… how is it going? Did everything go well? Did you make peace with your choice? When I was in hometown, a friend told his dad what’s going on with me since I seemed off when I visited him. I had a good conversation with him… maybe that is what I needed? He said something that made me think: explore your thoughts with friends/others—don’t keep it a secret. That’s how you get an idea/improve the idea; you will get the push you need. I feel this is true to some extent, but the other is also true. Again, future me, what do you think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some of my free time, I’ve been playing Ghost of Tsushima. It helps me take my mind off things. The game is beautiful; I’m taking it slow. In more ways, it’s helping me relax and gives me a boost when I want to focus. I’m keeping it under control, though, not treating it like a time sink. When I was younger, I remember I used to lock in and play for days. Heck—the last game I got addicted to was Division 2. I used to plan and play raids with people, but I eventually lost touch with most of the guild members. Thinking back, my first game guild was from a game called Elsword. As everyone was getting busy with life and not logging into the game, we planned to disband the guild and had a last-day party with everyone. I have a video of that on my old hard drive. I was back from class and late to the party, and “Pandemonium,” the guild master, was waiting on me. We had a blast, and it was a nice sunset. Hopefully I can recover it and post it here… I had fond memories of that guild. Coming back to Division 2, I constructed a huge-ass essay on how it’s affecting my life, posted it to the guild and Discord servers, and left the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april-2025/Ghost-Of-Tsushima-april-2025.mp4&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DIY RO - Water Purification</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/03/diy-water-purification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 22:30:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/03/diy-water-purification/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water hardness in my home (Gobi) is around ~600 ppm. In Chennai where I live, it’s around 800 ppm (metro water). Half the people get purified water for their drinking; there is business for those who supply water, while the other half get a water-purification system installed in their homes by a vendor/company that produces it. We can build a DIY homemade purifier. It’s a new challenge, a chance to learn new things, and cheaper than buying ready-made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water “hardness” is simply the concentration of dissolved calcium and magnesium ions in water. It is usually expressed in mg/L or ppm as CaCO₃.&lt;br /&gt;
• Soft: 0–60 ppm&lt;br /&gt;
• Moderately hard: 61–120 ppm&lt;br /&gt;
• Hard: 121–180 ppm&lt;br /&gt;
• Very hard: &amp;gt; 180 ppm&lt;br /&gt;
Hard water leaves scale in pipes and appliances and can affect taste, so reducing hardness is one of the main goals of an RO unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;components-needed&#34;&gt;Components needed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to things that are needed for the DIY setup, I need to buy the following items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;S.No&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Qty&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rate (₹)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Amount (₹)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Why it’s used&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wall-mount plate (12″)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;140.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;140.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Base plate to fix the RO unit on the wall&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BlueShell booster pump&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;850.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;850.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Raises pressure so the RO membrane works efficiently&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BlueShell 100 GPD RO membrane&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;850.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;850.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Main purification element that removes dissolved salts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GAC inline cartridge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Granular activated-carbon pre-filter for chlorine removal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CTO 10″ carbon block&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Carbon block for chlorine, taste, odour removal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Membrane housing (1812)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;130.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;130.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Holds and seals the RO membrane&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Accord 1.5 A SMPS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24 V DC power supply for pump &amp;amp; UV lamp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UV-chamber set (11 W)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 set&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;UV-C sterilization of product water after RO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Handheld TDS meter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tests input/output water quality (ppm)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tubing cutter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Gives clean, square cuts on RO tubing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alkaline remineralizer (4″)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adds minerals and raises pH after RO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10″ filter housings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;360.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold sediment, CTO and GAC cartridges&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;¼″ RO tubing (≈ 5 m)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 coils&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Connects all filters, pump, membrane and faucet&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two-side connectors&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Straight unions to join tubing sections&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pump elbows&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;90° elbows for pump inlet/outlet to tubing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Membrane elbows&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elbows that screw into membrane housing ports&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Housing elbows&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elbow fittings for pre-filter housings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Inlet-valve set&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 set&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shuts off/isolates the water supply to the RO unit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Post-carbon cartridge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 pc&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;“Polishing” filter that improves taste after RO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;C-clamp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hardware for mounting the wall plate/housing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X-clamp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2 pcs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Additional mounting support for the RO assembly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PTFE (Teflon) tape&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 rolls&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seals threaded joints to prevent leaks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;General-purpose tape&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 roll&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Miscellaneous binding/labelling&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total value of cash-memo items: ₹4,360&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill of the items bought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/diy-water-filteration/water-purification-parts-bill-part1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/diy-water-filteration/water-purifiation-parts-bill-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-all-the-parts-are-plumbed-step-by-step&#34;&gt;How all the parts are plumbed – step-by-step&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have 3 big housings. We put the following filters inside them and connect them sequentially. Using similar housing to the spun filter, we fit the other filters and connect them up until the motor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/diy-water-filteration/spun-filter-with-housing.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sediment (Spun) filter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The very first stage. It traps visible particles such as sand, rust and silt so that none of the downstream cartridges get clogged prematurely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CTO 10″ carbon-block filter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Removes chlorine, taste and odour. Chlorine must be taken out here because it can irreversibly damage an RO membrane.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GAC (pre-carbon) filter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A second carbon stage that “polishes” the water and adsorbs any remaining organic chemicals that slipped past the CTO block.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Booster pump (motor) + low-pressure cut-off&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Right after the pre-carbon filter the water enters the BlueShell booster pump.&lt;br /&gt;
• The pump raises the feed-water pressure to ~80 psi so that the RO membrane can work efficiently.&lt;br /&gt;
• Placing it here ensures that only pre-filtered, de-chlorinated water passes through the pump head, protecting the pump and its check-valves from grit or chlorine attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RO membrane housing with 100 GPD membrane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Under high pressure the semi-permeable membrane now removes dissolved salts, heavy metals, fluoride, nitrates, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This (following image) is how we fit the RO membrane; we need to make sure the waste-water port is not the one we use.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Another thing to note: The waste (concentrate) port coming out of the housing is fitted with a flow-restrictor to maintain the required pressure differential.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/diy-water-filteration/ro-membrane-how-to-attach.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-carbon (polishing) filter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first stage on the product-water side. It adsorbs any residual gases and improves the taste and smell of the permeate coming out of the RO membrane.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alkaline remineralizer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Adds back healthy minerals (calcium, magnesium, potassium) and gently increases the pH so the water is no longer slightly acidic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UV-C chamber (11 W)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The final barrier. Ultraviolet light disinfects the remineralized water, inactivating any bacteria, viruses or cysts that might have slipped through or grown in the storage tank.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the UV outlet the water goes to the water storage through pipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-also-got-a-ph-tester-measured-the-colour&#34;&gt;I also got a pH tester, measured the colour.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tester uses a liquid reagent: add 2 drops to 5 ml of water and compare the resulting colour to the chart in the pH tester.&lt;br /&gt;
• Raw inlet water: pH ≈ 7.4 (greenish)&lt;br /&gt;
• RO permeate before remineralizer: pH ≈ 6.3 (yellow)&lt;br /&gt;
• Final water after remineralizer: pH ≈ 7.2 (light green)&lt;br /&gt;
This shows the remineralizer is doing its job—bringing the pH back close to neutral so the water is neither acidic nor alkaline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-setup&#34;&gt;Final setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/diy-water-filteration/diy-water-purification-end.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mounting&#34;&gt;Mounting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mounted everything with a zip-tie to a window in the kitchen. When everything is connected, leave it running for 20 mins; you can immediately detect the change. The TDS of the purified drinking-water bottle that we buy is about 25 ppm, I get 19 ppm with this setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central Pollution Control Board India&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cpcb.nic.in/wqm/BIS_Drinking_Water_Specification.pdf&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://cpcb.nic.in/wqm/BIS_Drinking_Water_Specification.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel like everything is stagnant… even though there’s small progress. If you are working for big corpora, you are just a row in an Excel sheet. The feeling resonates more and more reading trending Hacker News and things that happen around in personal experience. As for me, as always trying to make time for open source and my hobbies… in the increasing midst of responsibilities coming towards me. I also almost got into a marriage arranged by my dad, forced to go see them… the girl &amp;amp; girl’s family like me and are trying to convince me into marriage, my dad doing all his best to set this up, fighting with me, etc. The girl is good too, perfect for family, they are a distant relative, born in 2000… But there are other plans/God has other plans. ~future me reading this… what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talked to an old friend; he said he discovered a private office Wi-Fi password written on a note and has been using it secretly. That reminded me of the first time I cracked a WPA endpoint in 2015. It felt great back then. We had BSNL broadband—“unlimited” but stuck at 60 kbps. I used to combine my connection with my neighbor’s Wi-Fi for maximum speeds. Those were fun times; I even made a mod of an application that combined network connections&amp;hellip;Long story short, he reminded me of Wi-Fi hacking. When I got back home to Gobi, I brought out my old Wi-Fi packet-injecting dongle and Linux laptop to chennai. I found a couple of neighbors’ Wi-Fi networks. After shutting down my unreliable Airtel connection in Chennai, I switched to unlimited mobile data (from previous posts), so I decided to use their Wi-Fi (nobody uses wpa3.. even the new routers comes with wpa2, you can easily capture the handshake and crack it.. I used hashcat, its super fast and reliable). While on their network, I logged in to their router, checked their device list, and configured Wi-Fi settings for a longer range on 2.4 GHz by switching between 20 Hz and 40 Hz channels.. Some of the closest Wi-Fi access points are 5 GHz and offers low latency too.. By seeing the device list, I was able to mimic their device name and avoid being caught. For example: “smart-camera.”.. to be fair, I would just use them for internet..nothing more..nothing less.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>JWT Authentication with Refresh Tokens in Spring WebFlux</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/02/jwt-auth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/02/jwt-auth/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; I’m documenting this so that I can refer back to it in the future. Recently, I’ve been working with Spring WebFlux, and although I’ve previously used JWTs, this is my first time writing about them. I often forget the implementation details when switching between languages or frameworks, so I’m recording this while it’s still fresh in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JSON Web Tokens (&lt;strong&gt;JWTs&lt;/strong&gt;) are a compact way to prove a user’s identity between two parties—usually a browser and your API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;token-life-cycle&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token life-cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A JWT is &lt;em&gt;self-contained&lt;/em&gt;: it carries the user’s ID, roles, and an &lt;strong&gt;expiry&lt;/strong&gt; inside the token itself.&lt;br /&gt;
To balance security and convenience I use &lt;strong&gt;two clocks&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it limits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typical value&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens when it hits zero&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access expiry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How long the current token stays valid&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;15–30 min&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Client must call &lt;code&gt;/auth/refresh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refresh expiry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How long the &lt;em&gt;refresh token&lt;/em&gt; can mint new access tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;7–30 days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;User must log in again&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;/login ──► access + refresh token
│
(before access expiry)
▼
/refresh ──► new access token
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the &lt;strong&gt;refresh expiry&lt;/strong&gt; passes, even the refresh endpoint refuses to issue new tokens—forcing a fresh login.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-blocks&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building blocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model&lt;/strong&gt; – database tables for users &amp;amp; login history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repository&lt;/strong&gt; – Reactive CRUD interfaces provided by Spring Data R2DBC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service&lt;/strong&gt; – business logic (password checks, audit log)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auth manager&lt;/strong&gt; – validates credentials or JWT claims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filter&lt;/strong&gt; – extracts the Authorization: Bearer … header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security config&lt;/strong&gt; – wires it all together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;essential-code&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;entity-classes&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entity Classes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These classes represent database tables as Java objects using Spring Data R2DBC. &lt;code&gt;@Table&lt;/code&gt; maps the class to a table, and Lombok annotations (&lt;code&gt;@Data&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;@Builder&lt;/code&gt;, etc.) generate getters, setters, constructors, and a builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;@Table(&amp;quot;users&amp;quot;)
@Data @Builder @NoArgsConstructor @AllArgsConstructor
public class UserEntity {
@Id private Long id;
private String username;
private String password; // hashed
private String roles; // e.g. &amp;quot;USER,ADMIN&amp;quot;
private boolean enabled;
}
@Table(&amp;quot;login_history&amp;quot;)
@Data @Builder @NoArgsConstructor @AllArgsConstructor
public class LoginHistory {
@Id private Long id;
private Long userId;
private LocalDateTime loginTime;
private String ipAddress;
private boolean successful;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;repositories&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repositories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring Data’s &lt;code&gt;ReactiveCrudRepository&lt;/code&gt; provides reactive CRUD operations. By extending these interfaces, Spring auto-generates the implementation at runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public interface UserRepository
extends ReactiveCrudRepository&amp;lt;UserEntity, Long&amp;gt; {
Mono&amp;lt;UserEntity&amp;gt; findByUsername(String username);
}
public interface LoginHistoryRepository
extends ReactiveCrudRepository&amp;lt;LoginHistory, Long&amp;gt; {}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;jwt-filter-excerpt&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JWT filter&lt;/strong&gt; (excerpt)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ServerAuthenticationConverter&lt;/code&gt; is a Spring Security WebFlux interface for converting HTTP requests into &lt;code&gt;Authentication&lt;/code&gt; objects. In this converter, we extract and validate the JWT token from the Authorization header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;@Slf4j
public class JwtAuthConverter implements ServerAuthenticationConverter {
@Override
public Mono&amp;lt;Authentication&amp;gt; convert(ServerWebExchange exchange) {
String header = exchange.getRequest()
.getHeaders()
.getFirst(HttpHeaders.AUTHORIZATION);
if (header == null || !header.startsWith(&amp;quot;Bearer &amp;quot;)) return Mono.empty();
try {
String token = header.substring(7);
Jws&amp;lt;Claims&amp;gt; claims = JwtUtil.validateTokenAndGetClaims(token);
String username = claims.getBody().getSubject();
List&amp;lt;String&amp;gt; roles = claims.getBody().get(&amp;quot;roles&amp;quot;, List.class);
List&amp;lt;GrantedAuthority&amp;gt; authorities = roles.stream()
.map(SimpleGrantedAuthority::new)
.collect(Collectors.toList());
return Mono.just(new UsernamePasswordAuthenticationToken(
username, null, authorities));
} catch (Exception ex) {
log.warn(&amp;quot;Invalid token: {}&amp;quot;, ex.getMessage());
return Mono.empty();
}
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;security-configuration-simplified&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security configuration&lt;/strong&gt; (simplified)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;@Configuration&lt;/code&gt; class defines beans for Spring’s application context. &lt;code&gt;@EnableWebFluxSecurity&lt;/code&gt; activates WebFlux security support. We configure a &lt;code&gt;SecurityWebFilterChain&lt;/code&gt; bean to set up CSRF, CORS, endpoint permissions, and insert our JWT filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;@Configuration
@EnableWebFluxSecurity
public class SecurityConfig {
@Bean
public SecurityWebFilterChain securityWebFilterChain(ServerHttpSecurity http) {
JwtAuthWebFilter jwt = new JwtAuthWebFilter(new JwtReactiveAuthManager());
jwt.setServerAuthenticationConverter(new JwtAuthConverter());
return http
.csrf(ServerHttpSecurity.CsrfSpec::disable)
.cors(ServerHttpSecurity.CorsSpec::disable)
.httpBasic(ServerHttpSecurity.HttpBasicSpec::disable)
.formLogin(ServerHttpSecurity.FormLoginSpec::disable)
.exceptionHandling(e -&amp;gt; e.authenticationEntryPoint(
(exch, ex) -&amp;gt; {
exch.getResponse().setStatusCode(HttpStatus.UNAUTHORIZED);
return exch.getResponse().setComplete();
}))
.authorizeExchange(ex -&amp;gt; ex
.pathMatchers(
&amp;quot;/api/v1/auth/login&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;/api/v1/auth/refresh&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;/api/v1/auth/validate&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;/actuator/**&amp;quot;)
.permitAll()
.pathMatchers(&amp;quot;/api/v1/task/**&amp;quot;).authenticated())
.addFilterAt(jwt, SecurityWebFiltersOrder.AUTHENTICATION)
.build();
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reactive-authentication-manager&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reactive authentication manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing &lt;code&gt;ReactiveAuthenticationManager&lt;/code&gt; allows custom authentication logic in WebFlux. This manager checks credentials, handles disabled accounts, and records login attempts via the &lt;code&gt;UserService&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;@Component
@RequiredArgsConstructor
public class DatabaseReactiveAuthManager implements ReactiveAuthenticationManager {
private final UserService users;
@Override
public Mono&amp;lt;Authentication&amp;gt; authenticate(Authentication auth) {
String username = auth.getName();
String rawPwd = auth.getCredentials().toString();
return users.findByUsername(username)
.switchIfEmpty(Mono.error(new BadCredentialsException(&amp;quot;User not found&amp;quot;)))
.flatMap(u -&amp;gt; {
if (!users.checkPassword(rawPwd, u.getPassword()))
return users.recordLoginAttempt(u, false, null)
.then(Mono.error(new BadCredentialsException(&amp;quot;Bad password&amp;quot;)));
if (!u.isEnabled())
return Mono.error(new DisabledException(&amp;quot;Account disabled&amp;quot;));
List&amp;lt;GrantedAuthority&amp;gt; roles = Arrays.stream(u.getRoles().split(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;))
.map(String::trim)
.map(SimpleGrantedAuthority::new)
.collect(Collectors.toList());
return users.recordLoginAttempt(u, true, null)
.thenReturn(new UsernamePasswordAuthenticationToken(
username, null, roles));
});
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;configuration-properties&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuration properties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These YAML properties configure Spring Security’s JWT support, specifying the signing &lt;strong&gt;secret&lt;/strong&gt; and token lifetimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;security:
encryption:
secret: _&amp;quot;encryption_secret&amp;quot;_
jwt:
expiration-time: __1_440_000__ # 24 minutes (ms)
refresh-expiration-time: __604_800_000__ # 7 days (ms)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tip – generate a strong secret:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-py&#34;&gt;# This one-off command uses Docker to generate a bcrypt hash for a random 32-byte secret
docker run --rm python:3.9-slim \
python - &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&#39;PY&#39;
import bcrypt, os
print(bcrypt.hashpw(os.urandom(32), bcrypt.gensalt()).decode())
PY
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recap&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two expiries&lt;/strong&gt; keep sessions short yet user-friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reactive filter &lt;strong&gt;parses&lt;/strong&gt; the token and attaches &lt;strong&gt;authorities&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A database auth manager handles &lt;strong&gt;login&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;password checks&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;audit logs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spring WebFlux security is glued together with one concise &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;SecurityWebFilterChain&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jwt.io/introduction/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JWT.io Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jwtk/jjwt#readme&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JJWT (Java JWT) Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup JioFiber at home, disconnected Airtel in Chennai, and ported all my SIMs to Jio except mom’s. Jio offers unlimited data (4G/5G) on individual plans for $8.77 per month. Nowadays I don’t have enough time to do anything. No no no…not gonna start a rant here…lol. Talked to a friend about old WiFi hacking days…(more in the next few posts).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unlimited Photos Storage Without Root - Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/01/unlimited-photos-storage-without-root/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:11:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/01/unlimited-photos-storage-without-root/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is a continuation of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/2024/04/rooting-my-pixel/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rooting My Pixel&lt;/a&gt;. Over the past months, I’ve been using my rooted phone to bypass storage limits and enjoy unlimited Google Photos storage. However, using a rooted device isn’t without its challenges—if someone gains physical access to my phone, my data becomes vulnerable. Banking appsa and even general purpose applications refuse to run on rooted devices because they detect system tampering. In some cases, the Play Store won’t allow you to install certain apps at all. To get around these restrictions, I rely on LSPosed modules that help conceal root access, allowing these apps to function without issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-update-dilemma-keeping-root-intact&#34;&gt;The Update Dilemma: Keeping Root Intact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time my Pixel receives an update, I’m forced to patch the boot image, a critical step for Magisk to continue functioning properly. The process generally involves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloading the stock image for my Pixel model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracting the boot image.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patching the boot image using Magisk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flashing the patched boot image back onto the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping any of these steps means Magisk (and its modules) won’t load, breaking the tweaks I depend on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-not-disable-updates&#34;&gt;Why Not Disable Updates?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem tempting to simply disable updates, but the monthly Pixel updates often include important stability and OS fixes. For instance, the December 2024 Android 15 update introduced a bug where Wi-Fi and mobile internet would disconnect automatically after a period of inactivity, a problem that’s been widely discussed on Reddit, Google Forums, and other communities. I’m now waiting for the January patch that should resolve this issue. The takeaway? Staying updated is crucial despite the extra work it sometimes entails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emulating-the-old-pixel-without-root&#34;&gt;Emulating the Old Pixel Without Root&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed my previous posts, you know that rooting was once the only method to emulate the old Pixel’s functionality. Today, patching offers a robust alternative. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/revanced/revanced-patches&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ReVanced Patches repository&lt;/a&gt; provides a comprehensive collection of smali patches that let you modify apps without needing root access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon these patches while exploring alternatives to YouTube Premium. After canceling my subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some controversy earlier in the ReVanced journey. The project initially faced criticism on GitHub for directly hosting mods, which led to pressure from the google and github. In response, the devs decided to split the project, hosting the patch files separately from the patched binaries. This move not only addressed the concerns but also streamlined the development process, keeping the patch logic distinct and easier to manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;downloading-the-patches-and-apk&#34;&gt;Downloading the Patches and APK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before patching, you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the Latest Google Photos APK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Make sure to obtain the standalone APK file rather than a bundled format. sites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apkmirror.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;APKMirror&lt;/a&gt; are a good source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the Latest ReVanced Patches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/revanced/revanced-patches&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ReVanced Patches repository&lt;/a&gt; to get the most recent version of the patch file (the &lt;code&gt;.rvp&lt;/code&gt; file). Using the latest patches ensures better compatibility with the app version you’re patching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patching-the-apk&#34;&gt;Patching the APK&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have both the APK and the patch file, you can patch the app using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;java -jar revanced-cli.jar patch --patches patches.rvp -o patched.apk my_app.apk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply replace &lt;code&gt;our_app.apk&lt;/code&gt; with the path to the downloaded APK (for example, my Google Photos APK). This command tells the Revanced CLI to apply the patches defined in &lt;code&gt;patches.rvp&lt;/code&gt; to my APK and output a patched version named &lt;code&gt;patched.apk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic happens in the &lt;code&gt;.rvp&lt;/code&gt; file—it acts as a manifest that lists all supported packages along with their corresponding patches. When you run the command, the tool detects the package name in my APK and applies only the relevant modifications. (A small caveat: the current patching process only works via the PC command-line interface; the Android-based ReVanced Patcher app has issues patching google photos app for years now..)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-the-patched-app&#34;&gt;Installing the Patched App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After patching, simply install the new APK on the device. On first launch, the app will prompt you to install ReVanced MicroG—a companion component needed for proper operation. For my convenience, I’m including download links for all the essential files at the end of this post. I’ll update this section as I patch new versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 12px; flex-wrap: wrap;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/jan2025/img1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:320px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/jan2025/img2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:320px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/jan2025/img3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:320px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;relocking-the-pixel-device&#34;&gt;Relocking the Pixel Device&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relocking Pixel device is a critical step if I want to revert my device back to its original, secure state. Whether we choose to relock via fastboot or by flashing the official ROM, please note that both methods will erase our device data. Make sure to backup all important files before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;method-1-fastboot-relock&#34;&gt;Method 1: Fastboot Relock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter Fastboot Mode:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power off device completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold the &lt;strong&gt;Power&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Volume Down&lt;/strong&gt; buttons simultaneously until the fastboot screen appears.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relock the Bootloader:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect my device to my computer using a USB cable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open a terminal (or Command Prompt) and execute the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;fastboot flashing lock
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; Some devices might require the command &lt;code&gt;fastboot oem lock&lt;/code&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disable OEM Unlocking:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the bootloader is relocked, navigate to &lt;strong&gt;Developer Options&lt;/strong&gt; on the device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable the &lt;strong&gt;OEM Unlocking&lt;/strong&gt; option to prevent unauthorized bootloader modifications in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;method-2-flashing-the-official-rom&#34;&gt;Method 2: Flashing the Official ROM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the Official ROM:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/android/images#lynx&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Official Pixel Devices Site&lt;/a&gt; to download the latest factory image for your specific model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flash the ROM:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the detailed instructions provided on the support site to flash the official ROM. This method restores the device to its factory state and automatically relocks the bootloader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the method that best fits your comfort level and requirements. Relocking via fastboot is generally quicker if you’re familiar with command-line operations, while flashing the official ROM provides a comprehensive reset to stock software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReVanced CLI&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/revanced/revanced-cli&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub - ReVanced CLI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReVanced Patches Repo&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/revanced/revanced-patches&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub - ReVanced Patches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReVanced GmsCore&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ReVanced/GmsCore/releases&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub - ReVanced GmsCore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Photos APK&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apkmirror.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;APKMirror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patched-files&#34;&gt;Patched Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Any future patches that I release will be updated in this section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patches-files&#34;&gt;Patches Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;File Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Download Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;gphotos-patched-jan-2025 (Part 1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/jan2025/gphotos-patched-jan-2025.apk.zip.001&#34;&gt;Download Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;gphotos-patched-jan-2025 (Part 2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/jan2025/gphotos-patched-jan-2025.apk.zip.002&#34;&gt;Download Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;gms-core-jan2025&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/jan2025/app.revanced.android.gms-240913008-signed.apk&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;gphotos-patched-aug-2025&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/aug2025/gphotos-patched-aug-2025.apk.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;code&gt;gphotos-patched-jan-2025&lt;/code&gt; file is split into parts using Keka on macOS with a 99MB split threshold to help manage file sizes and site tracking. After downloading both parts, simply extract the first file (with the &lt;code&gt;.zip.001&lt;/code&gt; extension) using your preferred archive tool (such as Keka, 7-Zip, or WinRAR..etc). The tool will automatically combine the parts and extract the complete APK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is taking over, wth! For historical matching… DeepSeek is released, competing with OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s latest thinking model. I&amp;rsquo;m sure OpenAI will have some response to it. &lt;!---I’ve enjoyed a 5-day vacation—it was pleasant and something I’ll remember for the upcoming days. (Spent with Vi, aka 3&#39;rd Frost.)---&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to go home and spend some time with family, and I have to set up Jio AirFibre, converting my SIMs to Jio for unlimited internet (you’ll see a post about this later). The broadband over there isn’t that good and the signal inside the home is weak; plus, it comes bundled with TV, movies, and disney+, discovery+,..etc I’m going to disconnect Airtel TV/DTH in favor of this since it works with just WiFi and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require routing everywhere. &lt;!---Since I&#39;m planning to vacate Chennai in March, after February (Frost&#39;s 3rd birthday), things are going well. I even decided to tell Mom and Dad about Vi and show them by taking them to our Chennai home. Currently, as of this writing, they are not in Chennai with me—they went hometown last time I visited for functions and to take care of Grandma.---&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Certbot Manual Hook – Automating Wildcard Domain Renewals</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/12/certbot-manual-hook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 03:02:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/12/certbot-manual-hook/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Securing my website with HTTPS is crucial, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://certbot.eff.org/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Certbot&lt;/a&gt; makes it straightforward for many domains. However, when it comes to wildcard domains (like &lt;code&gt;*.domain.com&lt;/code&gt;), there’s a bit more work involved—particularly if I want to automate renewals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post explains how I set up a &lt;strong&gt;manual DNS hook&lt;/strong&gt; for Certbot that integrates with my domain name provider’s API (in this example, GoDaddy), so I no longer have to manually add DNS TXT records every time I need to renew my wildcard certificate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-we-need-this&#34;&gt;Why Do We Need This?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certbot automates the HTTPS setup for many domain configurations. However, &lt;strong&gt;wildcard certificates&lt;/strong&gt; require DNS-based validation—meaning I must add a TXT record to prove domain ownership. Certbot does not automatically update DNS for every provider. Thus, without automation, I’d be forced to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Certbot.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab the &lt;code&gt;_acme-challenge&lt;/code&gt; TXT record details.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to my DNS panel and manually create the TXT record.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait for DNS to propagate.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resume the Certbot process.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, clean up the TXT record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this every few months quickly becomes tedious, especially if I manage multiple wildcard domains. Luckily, Certbot’s &lt;code&gt;--manual-auth-hook&lt;/code&gt; parameter can help me automate these steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-goal&#34;&gt;The Goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automate&lt;/strong&gt; the DNS validation process for wildcard certificate renewals using Certbot hooks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize my DNS provider’s API (in my case, &lt;strong&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/strong&gt;) to create and remove the required &lt;code&gt;_acme-challenge&lt;/code&gt; TXT record automatically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate this process into a &lt;code&gt;crontab&lt;/code&gt; so renewals happen on schedule without manual intervention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-manual-process&#34;&gt;Current (Manual) Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I was doing without automation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Certbot: &lt;code&gt;certbot certonly --manual ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certbot tells me which TXT record to create, e.g. &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;_acme-challenge.domain.com&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I log into GoDaddy (or another provider) and create the TXT record with the provided value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wait for DNS propagation (a few minutes).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certbot verifies and finalizes the certificate issuance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I remove or empty out the TXT record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process, while doable, is time-consuming and must be repeated every 60–90 days (depending on my renewal schedule).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;godaddy-api-endpoint&#34;&gt;Godaddy API endpoint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;automating-the-workflow&#34;&gt;Automating the Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To automate the renewal of my wildcard domain certificate, I leverage my domain provider&amp;rsquo;s API to manage DNS TXT records programmatically. I use &lt;strong&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Access:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure GoDaddy supports DNS management via API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API Credentials:&lt;/strong&gt; Obtain my API key and secret from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.godaddy.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GoDaddy Developer Portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;godaddy-api-endpoint-1&#34;&gt;GoDaddy API Endpoint&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the following endpoint to manage TXT records:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;https://api.godaddy.com/v1/domains/${GODADDY_DOMAIN}/records/TXT/${RECORD_NAME}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parameters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;${GODADDY_DOMAIN}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: My root domain (e.g., &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;${RECORD_NAME}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Typically &lt;code&gt;_acme-challenge&lt;/code&gt; for Certbot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-the-api&#34;&gt;Using the API&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;testing-create-update-txt-record-endpoints&#34;&gt;Testing Create/Update TXT Record Endpoints&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;curl -s -X PUT \
-H &amp;quot;Authorization: sso-key ${GODADDY_KEY}:${GODADDY_SECRET}&amp;quot; \
-H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application/json&amp;quot; \
-d &amp;quot;[{\&amp;quot;data\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;${CERTBOT_VALIDATION}\&amp;quot;, \&amp;quot;ttl\&amp;quot;: 600}]&amp;quot; \
&amp;quot;https://api.godaddy.com/v1/domains/${GODADDY_DOMAIN}/records/TXT/${RECORD_NAME}&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Headers:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Authorization&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;sso-key MY_API_KEY:MY_API_SECRET&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Content-Type&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;application/json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;: Validation string from Certbot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;ttl&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;: Time-to-live (e.g., &lt;code&gt;600&lt;/code&gt; seconds).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;remove-txt-record&#34;&gt;Remove TXT Record&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;curl -s -X PUT \
-H &amp;quot;Authorization: sso-key ${GODADDY_KEY}:${GODADDY_SECRET}&amp;quot; \
-H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application/json&amp;quot; \
-d &amp;quot;[]&amp;quot; \
&amp;quot;https://api.godaddy.com/v1/domains/${GODADDY_DOMAIN}/records/TXT/${RECORD_NAME}&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;integration-with-certbot-hooks&#34;&gt;Integration with Certbot Hooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auth Hook (&lt;code&gt;godaddy-auth.sh&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/strong&gt; Adds the TXT record before validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cleanup Hook (&lt;code&gt;godaddy-cleanup.sh&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/strong&gt; Removes the TXT record after validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ensure my scripts use the above &lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt; commands with the appropriate environment variables (&lt;code&gt;GODADDY_KEY&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;GODADDY_SECRET&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;GODADDY_DOMAIN&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;RECORD_NAME&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CERTBOT_VALIDATION&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-automated-solution&#34;&gt;The Automated Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certbot offers hooks that run custom scripts to automate these exact steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-command-with-hooks&#34;&gt;1. Command with Hooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;certbot certonly \
--manual \
--preferred-challenges dns \
--manual-auth-hook /etc/letsencrypt/scripts/godaddy-auth.sh \
--manual-cleanup-hook /etc/letsencrypt/scripts/godaddy-cleanup.sh \
--agree-tos \
-d &#39;*.wild.card.domain&#39; \
--preferred-chain &amp;quot;ISRG Root X1&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;--manual-auth-hook&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Runs a script before Certbot attempts to validate the domain (to set up the TXT record).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;--manual-cleanup-hook&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Runs a script after validation completes (to remove or clear the TXT record).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-godaddy-auth-script&#34;&gt;2. GoDaddy Auth Script&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following script (&lt;code&gt;godaddy-auth.sh&lt;/code&gt;) is triggered by the &lt;code&gt;--manual-auth-hook&lt;/code&gt;. It reads environment variables set by Certbot—like &lt;code&gt;CERTBOT_DOMAIN&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CERTBOT_VALIDATION&lt;/code&gt;—and then updates the DNS record via the GoDaddy API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env bash
# /etc/letsencrypt/scripts/godaddy-auth.sh
# Certbot environment variables:
# - CERTBOT_DOMAIN (the domain being authenticated)
# - CERTBOT_VALIDATION (the validation string for TXT record)
GODADDY_KEY=&amp;quot;domain_name_provider_key&amp;quot;
GODADDY_SECRET=&amp;quot;domain_name_provider_secret&amp;quot;
GODADDY_DOMAIN=&amp;quot;your_root_domain&amp;quot; # e.g., &amp;quot;example.com&amp;quot;
TTL=600
# Subdomain that needs to be updated
RECORD_NAME=&amp;quot;_acme-challenge&amp;quot;
# Build request payload
DATA=&amp;quot;[{\&amp;quot;data\&amp;quot;: \&amp;quot;${CERTBOT_VALIDATION}\&amp;quot;, \&amp;quot;ttl\&amp;quot;: ${TTL}}]&amp;quot;
curl -s -X PUT \
-H &amp;quot;Authorization: sso-key ${GODADDY_KEY}:${GODADDY_SECRET}&amp;quot; \
-H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application/json&amp;quot; \
-d &amp;quot;${DATA}&amp;quot; \
&amp;quot;https://api.godaddy.com/v1/domains/${GODADDY_DOMAIN}/records/TXT/${RECORD_NAME}&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;GoDaddy AUTH-HOOK: Created TXT record for ${CERTBOT_DOMAIN}.&amp;quot;
# Sleep to allow DNS propagation
sleep 60
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If I have a subdomain or different domain structure, I adjust &lt;code&gt;RECORD_NAME&lt;/code&gt; accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-godaddy-cleanup-script&#34;&gt;3. GoDaddy Cleanup Script&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script (&lt;code&gt;godaddy-cleanup.sh&lt;/code&gt;) runs after verification succeeds. It removes (or resets) the &lt;code&gt;_acme-challenge&lt;/code&gt; TXT record, keeping my DNS tidy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;#!/usr/bin/env bash
# /etc/letsencrypt/scripts/godaddy-cleanup.sh
# Certbot environment variables:
# - CERTBOT_DOMAIN (the domain being authenticated)
GODADDY_KEY=&amp;quot;domain_name_provider_key&amp;quot;
GODADDY_SECRET=&amp;quot;domain_name_provider_secret&amp;quot;
GODADDY_DOMAIN=&amp;quot;your_root_domain&amp;quot;
RECORD_NAME=&amp;quot;_acme-challenge&amp;quot;
# Empty the TXT record (or remove it altogether)
DATA=&amp;quot;[]&amp;quot;
curl -s -X PUT \
-H &amp;quot;Authorization: sso-key ${GODADDY_KEY}:${GODADDY_SECRET}&amp;quot; \
-H &amp;quot;Content-Type: application/json&amp;quot; \
-d &amp;quot;${DATA}&amp;quot; \
&amp;quot;https://api.godaddy.com/v1/domains/${GODADDY_DOMAIN}/records/TXT/${RECORD_NAME}&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;GoDaddy CLEANUP-HOOK: Removed TXT record for ${CERTBOT_DOMAIN}.&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scheduling-with-crontab&#34;&gt;Scheduling With Crontab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After confirming the manual hooks work, I automate the renewal checks using crontab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;10 0 * * * /usr/bin/certbot renew --preferred-chain &amp;quot;ISRG Root X1&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /folder/to/save/cronlog.log 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1
10 0 * * * /etc/letsencrypt/scripts/certbot-renew-dns.sh &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /folder/to/save/cronlog-manualhook.log 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pro-tips&#34;&gt;Pro Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNS Propagation&lt;/strong&gt;: Sometimes DNS changes can take longer than expected, especially if my DNS TTL is high. I might adjust my &lt;code&gt;sleep&lt;/code&gt; time or TTL in the script if validations fail.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permissions&lt;/strong&gt;: I ensure my hook scripts are &lt;strong&gt;executable&lt;/strong&gt; by using &lt;code&gt;chmod +x /path/to/script.sh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;: I keep my API keys secret. Storing them in environment variables or a secure file is best.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing&lt;/strong&gt;: I run &lt;code&gt;certbot renew --dry-run&lt;/code&gt; to verify that my hooks and scripts work before scheduling them in production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Certbot’s DNS challenge manual hook scripts, I can automate things, I never would have thought DNS provider would have full api access and are allowing acess to anyone who are buying domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas &amp;amp; A Happy New Year, See ya soon~&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Project IDX: A Look Into Google’s Cloud-Based Development Platform</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/11/project-idx/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/11/project-idx/</guid><description>
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://idx.dev/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project IDX&lt;/a&gt; lately, and it’s quite an intriguing solution for cloud-based development. In essence, Project IDX gives you an always-available coding environment running on Google Cloud. As long as you keep the instance running and remain active, you effectively have a &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; development machine at your disposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I primarily use Project IDX for Java and front-end development on my personal projects. One of the coolest parts of my setup is using it with &lt;strong&gt;Samsung DeX&lt;/strong&gt;. By simply connecting a mobile device, opening Project IDX in the browser, and plugging in a keyboard and mouse, you can achieve a desktop-like workflow from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-experience-with-project-idx&#34;&gt;My Experience with Project IDX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onboarding process is straightforward: sign in with your Google account, spin up an IDX instance, and you’re off to the races. Under the hood, Project IDX uses Nix to manage packages and dependencies, allowing you to define your environment as code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;System specs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/nov2024/project-idx-htop.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-nix&#34;&gt;Using Nix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nix is a functional package manager that ensures reproducible, declarative environments. Within Project IDX, you can configure all your tooling in a &lt;code&gt;dev.nix&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;below is my actual config file from a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nix&#34;&gt;{ pkgs, ... }: {
channel = &amp;quot;stable-24.05&amp;quot;;
packages = [
pkgs.docker-compose
pkgs.zulu17
pkgs.nodejs_20
pkgs.gradle
pkgs.htop
pkgs.sudo
pkgs.pnpm
pkgs.deno
pkgs.tmux
];
services.docker.enable = true;
services.postgres = {
enable = true;
};
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your workspace initializes, Project IDX automatically installs and configures everything specified in this file. It’s fast, consistent, and eliminates the classic “it works on my machine” problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ai-integration&#34;&gt;AI Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project IDX is essentially a modified version of open-source VS Code, but with &lt;strong&gt;deep integration of Google’s AI&lt;/strong&gt;. You can use conversational prompts to perform tasks like creating files, refactoring code, or running commands. This isn’t just code suggestions—Project IDX can physically change files based on your instructions in the integrated chat window. It’s wild to see in action! when it actually works, it still needs work, it will only get better from here? so its okey I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/nov2024/project-idx-usage-onproject-chat.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in the above image, when instructed to create a folder similar to an existing folder, it created the folder but the latest msg from the AI shows the command failed, the editor failed to parse the command. which resulted in an error. &amp;ldquo;user-management.scss&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;port-forwarding&#34;&gt;Port Forwarding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forwarding ports is also streamlined. When you start up a development server—say, a Java Spring Boot app on port 8080—it automatically detects the listening port and allows you to expose it publicly or keep it private. This is great if you’re running multiple services, like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spring Reactor app on port 8080&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front-end dev server on port 7173&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database on a dedicated port (e.g., 5432 or 27017)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A database manager like Adminer runnin inside docker and exposes port on 8181
..etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup makes it simple to preview projects from any device or share them with collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/nov2024/open-ports-porject-idx.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pros-and-cons-of-project-idx&#34;&gt;Pros and Cons of Project IDX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pros&#34;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;: No need for a powerful local machine; you can develop from virtually anywhere, even on a modest laptop or mobile device.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Driven&lt;/strong&gt;: Built-in AI assistance (sometimes referred to as “Gemini AI”) can refactor code, generate boilerplate, or provide debugging tips.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preconfigured Templates&lt;/strong&gt;: Supports a wide range of frameworks (React, Angular, Next.js, Flutter, Python, Go, etc.). You can quickly spin up a new project with minimal setup.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collaboration Features&lt;/strong&gt;: Real-time collaboration (shared terminals, pair debugging) is ideal for remote teams.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nix-Based Customization&lt;/strong&gt;: Define your entire dev environment in a single file for reproducibility across projects.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance Limits&lt;/strong&gt;: As of now, the default VM specs (currently as of writing 8GB RAM, 2 CPU cores) can feel slow when running multiple services in running parallel (docker db service, db viewer, node-frontend..etc) and heavy IDE tasks (like Java code completion).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beta Uncertainties&lt;/strong&gt;: Project IDX is still in beta, so things can change. There’s no official SLA, and certain features could be introduced or deprecated.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing Future&lt;/strong&gt;: Currently free, but Google may charge for more powerful machines or advanced features down the road.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependent on Internet&lt;/strong&gt;: You need a reliable internet connection. If you lose connectivity, you lose access to your dev environment.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growing Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;: While extensions exist, it’s not as mature as traditional VS Code.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-takeaways&#34;&gt;Personal Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite occasional slowdowns—especially with Java’s language server—I find Project IDX to be &lt;strong&gt;fast and reliable&lt;/strong&gt; for quick tests and collaborative workflows. If your instance gets messed up, you can simply reset the VM. Your user storage partition remains intact, meaning you don’t lose any data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, for heavier workloads or large multi-service applications, the 8GB RAM limit can become a bottleneck. If you find yourself needing more horsepower, you can request an increase from Google, but it’s not an automated process yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For developers curious about cloud-based workstations, Project IDX is worth exploring. It balances the convenience of a full Linux environment in your browser with advanced AI-driven coding tools. With Nix managing your dependencies, your environment is reproducible, shareable, and straightforward to set up. While the platform isn’t perfect—still in beta, with performance and resource constraints—it’s a promising glimpse into the future of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or experiences of your own, feel free to drop a comment or reach out. Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;References &amp;amp; Further Reading&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://idx.dev/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Official Project IDX Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/idx/guides&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project IDX Developers Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://nixos.org/manual/nix/stable/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nix Official Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.idx.dev/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project IDX Community Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: All information is based on personal experience and available details as of November 2024. Features and pricing may change as Project IDX evolves.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update-thoughts-on-life-edited-updated-on-jan24-2025&#34;&gt;Personal Update (Thoughts on Life (edited/updated on jan24/2025))&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, life presents crossroads where you wonder if it’s better to step aside so someone else can be happier—even if it stings. Is that genuine sacrifice, or is it avoidance? The line can be blurry, but the hope is that such tough decisions lead to growth or peace for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m planning for a bit of rest and enjoyment in December—a week unplugged from the world’s noise (work..).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rooting My Pixel For Unlimited gphotos backup</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/04/rooting-my-pixel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 03:14:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/04/rooting-my-pixel/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;All the previous android phones I had, I rooted them and used them with a custom ROM that had gphotos mod or used it with gphotos mod, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a pixel for android development as my second device..but all this time, it had stock android and not rooted with no modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what do I mean by gphotos mod..?
You get unlimited photos and videos backup in Google photos, the mod makes it seem like you&amp;rsquo;re using a pixel device. But I already have a pixel device..?.. Google previously had announced that their pixel phones will have unlimited backup, but they reverted this decision after thier initial announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;click image to enlarge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/pixel-unlimited-photos-google-help.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;google-pixel-phone-storage-offers&#34;&gt;Google Pixel Phone Storage Offers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlimited Storage Offer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original Pixel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unlimited Original quality (free)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No limits on photo and video storage.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unlimited Original quality (free)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Applies only to photos and videos taken before January 16, 2021.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unlimited Original quality (free)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Applies only to photos and videos taken before January 31, 2022.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pixel 3a and onwards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not available&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Instead, offers a 3-month trial for the 100 GB Google One plan (Pixel 4, 4a, 4a (5G), Pixel 5&amp;hellip;.etc)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;google-photos-storage-policy-changes&#34;&gt;Google Photos Storage Policy Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Announced end of free unlimited storage for High quality and Express quality starting June 1, 2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Users must use Storage saver or Original quality; new photos count towards the user&amp;rsquo;s shared storage quota.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 1, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Renamed &amp;ldquo;High quality&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Storage saver&amp;rdquo;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Existing photos remain unaffected; new uploads consume storage quota across Google Drive, Gmail, and Photos.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-June 1, 2021&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pixel smartphone owners up to Pixel 5 remain exempt from the storage changes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Owners can continue enjoying unlimited Original quality storage despite the policy changes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;click image to enlarge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/wikipedia-google-photos-storage.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read the support page or the wikipedia or any source, it is clear that you get original quaility backups for free for the original pixel device, which is the first pixel device, though im having a new pixel device if I emulate the first pixel device, I can get unlimited storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rooting-magisk&#34;&gt;Rooting &amp;amp; Magisk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2015.. along those times. Rooting was mainly SuperSU, you install a custom recovery and flash SuperSU, or install an apk like (kingRoot..or something similar..there was a long list, I remember this just because of the name, easy to remember). The apk way to root is bascailly the app tries the known os vulnerabilities to do previlege escaltion for that specific android version. Then you would have superSU installed on the device and use the app to grant permissions to any app that uses it. Some of the apps that I&amp;rsquo;ve used are app2sd, titanium backup, (backup any app with data)..2:22am and having hard time remembering the apps that i&amp;rsquo;ve used over the years.. those were the days, have fond memories now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays there&amp;rsquo;s just one main way.. and that is to use Magisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install magisk, follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://topjohnwu.github.io/Magisk/install.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;magisk official docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my device, which is a pixel, I need to get the original &lt;code&gt;boot&lt;/code&gt; img of the current firmware version I have, this we can check in About Phone or notification shade in android 13 and above(could be from before.. started noticing only it from then on). (&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/android/images#lynx&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Official pixel images&lt;/a&gt;) Once I downloaded the zip, extracted it and found the boot img, I then followed the following instructions from official manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;click image to enlarge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/patched_img_instructions.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;bluepie@dev-machine pixel backup % adb reboot bootloader
bluepie@dev-machine pixel backup % fastboot flashing unlock
OKAY [ 0.039s]
Finished. Total time: 0.039s
bluepie@dev-machine pixel backup % adb reboot bootloader
bluepie@dev-machine pixel backup % fastboot flashing unlock
OKAY [ 0.006s]
Finished. Total time: 0.006s
bluepie@dev-machine pixel backup % fastboot flash init_boot magisk_patched-27000_EyWu8.img
fastboot: error: cannot load &#39;magisk_patched-27000_EyWu8.img&#39;: No such file or directory
bluepie@dev-machine pixel backup % cd ..
bluepie@dev-machine Desktop % cd ..
bluepie@dev-machine ~ % fastboot flash init_boot magisk_patched-27000_EyWu8.img
Sending &#39;init_boot_b&#39; (8192 KB) OKAY [ 0.211s]
Writing &#39;init_boot_b&#39; OKAY [ 0.014s]
Finished. Total time: 0.228s
bluepie@dev-machine ~ % fastboot reboot
Rebooting OKAY [ 0.000s]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Magisk is installed and on reboot, you will see warning image that bootloader is unlocked saying device is insecure (which is true),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/magisk.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:480px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-software-for-gphotos&#34;&gt;Install software for Gphotos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Magisk is installed and phone is rooted, we need something called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rovo89/Xposed&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Xposed&lt;/a&gt; (it exposes/ enables/ writes ways for us to modify certain parts of the system by exposing them as API). Back.. early days Xposed was the king..(its archived and other projects took over). One such is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LSPosed/LSPosed&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LSPosed&lt;/a&gt; (but this only works till Android 13, again project archived). There is a fork of the lsposed which gives support for android 14. Since as of writing this.. I&amp;rsquo;m on Android 14..and this android version.. i.e. latest android 14..is not supported by lspoed because its archived by that point, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be flashing the latest lsposed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/re-zero001/LSPosed-Irena&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;v1.9.2&lt;/a&gt; inside magisk. Once installed..reboot the device. Now you have lsposed installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/lsposed.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:480px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pixelify-gphotos&#34;&gt;Pixelify gphotos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why we do all this because, for pixelify gphotos (to enable unlimited photos &amp;amp; video uploads), we need to install magisk and have lsposed (as of android 14). Just install the module and enable it for Google photos and reboot. Open the Pixelify gphotos app and set to spoof Pixel XL devices, thats the last step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/pixelify-gphotos.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:480px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get unlimited backups until this is patched.. I know irl friends that use this to upload xx gbs of photos. I&amp;rdquo;ve used before, since now that I enabled this, gonna upload all my photos from the gap (3 years of not using this) to backup using this mod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos uploaded through this mechanism do not take space on the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; gap: 12px; flex-wrap: wrap;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/photos-backed-up-for-free.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:480px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/magisk_modules.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:480px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/april2024/spoof_logs.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;height:480px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couple of other cool things with Xposed, can emulate an unrooted device with patches and make banking apps work, but I have a separate phone just for that. This pixel is just for development and photos backup (additional bonus)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been slipping on my dreams.. though I am happy on some parts of my life, &lt;!-- I found a special person, It happened in the new office, we were strangers first, I did not want to know them.. or wanted to have anything with them, then we became friends over video games and guitar, we became close friends over the months, then on feb 2024, we got together. Knowing we couldn&#39;t be together..I started to erase her in my life..how I did other, but she confronted me and got me into 2 days of love.. then asked for additional two days.. then additional 6 months, I asked what&#39;s after 6 months. she said.. that my birthday was in 6 months..(august 29). I gotta get back to the groove. --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whispers Between Strings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a place of new beginnings, under fluorescent glow,
I crossed paths with a soul I thought I’d never know.
A stranger in the crowd, I turned the other way,
No intentions in my heart for friendship’s gentle sway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fate had strings to strum, and games for us to play,
Through chords and pixels bright, we whiled hours away.
From strangers into friends, we wove a silent thread,
Months unfolded softly, with every word unsaid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come February’s whisper, we stepped across the line,
Entangled in a moment, pretending all was fine.
Yet shadows loomed around us, a truth we couldn’t flee,
I tried to fade her presence, like footprints in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But she held on with courage, refused to let it end,
“Just two more days,” she pleaded, “let hearts begin to mend.”
Then days turned into months, six circles ‘round the sun,
“What happens when time’s up?” I asked. She said, “We’ve just begun.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your birthday marks the turning,” she smiled with knowing eyes,
A hint of something deeper, a plan beneath disguise.
Now time’s a path before me, with rhythm to approve,
It’s time to find my footing, and get back in the groove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Echoes in the Labyrinth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the maze of new beginnings, I walked alone,
Content with solitary paths, untraveled and unknown.
But whispers of a melody, a song of strings and play,
Lured me toward a crossroads on an unexpected day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fellow traveler appeared, with laughter in her eyes,
We danced through hidden corridors beneath the open skies.
With every game and note we shared, the walls began to fade,
The labyrinth seemed less daunting, its edges softly frayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As winter turned to springtime, our footsteps fell in rhyme,
We found a secret clearing, a moment out of time.
But shadows loomed to tell us that our paths were not the same,
I tried to turn away to where no memory spoke her name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet she reached out and held my gaze, “Just stay a little more,”
Two days became a promise, then extended to a score.
“What’s beyond these winding trails?” I asked beneath the moon.
She smiled, “A new horizon comes with August’s afternoon.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the maze feels less confining, each step a subtle groove,
Embracing twists and turns ahead, I find my feet can move.
For in this intricate design, where every choice is free,
I’m learning that the journey means as much as destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Letter to the Universe:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Universe,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t plan for this convergence of souls. In the hustle of new surroundings, I was content navigating alone, charting my course without expectation. Then, unexpectedly, someone entered my orbit—a bright comet against the night sky of routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We connected over shared joys: the strategic thrill of games, the harmony of strings vibrating in unison. These simple pleasures wove threads between us, creating a tapestry I hadn’t anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time flowed, our paths aligned more closely than I thought possible. Yet, knowing the stars might pull us in different directions, I tried to drift away, to return to the solitude I once knew. But she reached out, her resolve unwavering, asking me to remain—not forever, just a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Stay for two more days,” she said, and then, “Let’s see where six months takes us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s at the end of that journey?” I wondered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She hinted at a milestone—my own revolution around the sun, a birthday that could mark new beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I stand, Universe, open to the possibilities you lay before me. I don’t know where this path leads, but perhaps that’s the point of the journey. I’m ready to embrace the rhythm you’ve set, to find my place within the greater symphony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guide me as I step back into the groove of life’s unfolding melody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With cautious hope,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Wanderer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Stab at Using Ai for Productivity</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/02/my-stab-at-using-ai-for-productivity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 21:56:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/02/my-stab-at-using-ai-for-productivity/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-ai-usecases&#34;&gt;My ai usecases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;purchasing-ai-using-it-as-api-vs-monthly-subscription-for-chatgpt-claude&#34;&gt;Purchasing AI - Using It as API vs Monthly Subscription for ChatGPT/Claude&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you need to buy monthly subscriptions? Take Copilot and other examples. To test this out, I bought $5 worth of usage from OpenAI, used an extension for VSCode for ai  operations, and used ai tools that require api token..like AI Commits. Did it work? Yes. Have I used all of those $5? No, it&amp;rsquo;s still there. Usually, the models I use for these kinds of tasks are very affordable and don&amp;rsquo;t accumulate significant costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time of updating this post, the pricing is as follows (I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the following as of November 2, 2024):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Pricing Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pricing&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Pricing with Batch API*&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;gpt-4o-mini&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.150 / 1M input tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.075 / 1M input tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.075 / 1M cached** input tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.600 / 1M output tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.300 / 1M output tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;gpt-4o-mini-2024-07-18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.150 / 1M input tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.075 / 1M input tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.075 / 1M cached** input tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.600 / 1M output tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$0.300 / 1M output tokens&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1M - 1Million, yea, there should be no pricing..but that pricing is low right??&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Following is the usage for a month, the usage does not exceep any high numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/feb-api-usage.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use AI, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay monthly. You can just buy API usage for $5 and start from there. That&amp;rsquo;s my current verdict, though it could change in the future&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To test whether AI increases productivity or not. I started using it and I have couple of workflows, let see one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-assistant-for-api-syntax-and-docs&#34;&gt;An Assistant for API Syntax and docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An assistant that just gives the command out for common usecases, these are stuff that I nornally would google and take some tiem doing the same, here I jsut ahve a static window open with custom instruction, if you have used chatgpt or claude or any other ai chatbots. it yaps a lot, or give unnecessary explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/chat-apt-api-window.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll open this floating sticky window to my desktop and I&amp;rsquo;ll start coding/ imeplenting what I needed to do, when doubts, I just type in this window ,I get answers. I wont ask anything I wont&amp;rsquo; know, I just ask stuff which i already know but dont remember. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend using output from this directly without research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zed&#34;&gt;Zed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://zed.dev&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;zed&lt;/a&gt;, I have configured it with open AI key and I can use these features with the help of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;inline-ai&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/zed-inline-ai.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;chat window&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/ai-chat-window-with-different-features.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;model selection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/model-selection.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-helper&#34;&gt;Git helper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using ai commits, configuring in terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/aicommits.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using ai commits, cuz a chatgpt window with custom instructions in much btter than this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/git_commit_message_helper.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again if you notice, chatgpt doesnot spew any additional information, its fed with instructions as should only give git commit messages. I just copy pasted the rules from this page &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.conventionalcommits.org/en/v1.0.0/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conventional commits.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again all these are open source projects of mine, so im pasting my git diff into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;# im using mac, for copying to clipboard pbcopy
git diff --staged | pbcopy
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-find-in-page-helper&#34;&gt;Advanced find in page helper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is powerful&amp;hellip;maybe its bad longterm? idk.. before I have to learn entire docs to find a specific information if I can&amp;rsquo;t find it with keywords with find in page. &lt;em&gt;NOW WE CAN SEARCH THE CONTENT WITH LOGIC, WITHOUT EXACT WORDS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what to do achive this? First select all content of the page and give it instructions to specifically find a info using logic, tell it to use information only provided in the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the example below, it greatly reduces my time for implementing and learning items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/advanced_find_in_page.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;phrases-english-helper&#34;&gt;Phrases - English - Helper&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self explanatory, I hear a lot of phrases from tv shows, utube, needed a explainer with custom instructions of using that in 2 sentences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/feb2024/phraes-english-helper.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There should be a continuation..to the post. obviously when I use more and more..I&amp;rsquo;ll find more stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create ai assistant based on your needs to reduce your time working on things and increase your productivity.. these are the usecases I find for now.. should find more ones in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found another frost, getting a lot of life experiences.. I know it will not work between surroundings and struggles for future, deciding on august 29th, hopefully they understand.. still want entire life. Suggestion from frost 2 is just live in the moment and enjoy?. Future me.. tell me how it is going?.. remember feb 2024?. Good luck, stay positive and have a little bit of hope!.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating and Publishing Chrome Extension in Chrome Store</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/01/creating-and-publishing-chrome-extension-in-chrome-store/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 14:31:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/01/creating-and-publishing-chrome-extension-in-chrome-store/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-motivation&#34;&gt;Why &amp;amp; Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanted an adblocker for accuradio website, I just need to silence the ads on this website. How can it be done? Custom script that get injected into the page by some extensions such as tamper monkey, the disadvantage is u gotta install tamper monkey. The other idea I have in my brain is I Wanted to try out chrome extesnion that specifically does this job, since my current work needs me work on chrome extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanted to do for a while, the ads on accuradio is annoying, I wanted to write a script to block it, i wanted to just install it and be done with it. Even if I use a new machine/laptop.. i dont have to set it up or anything, just install the extension and use the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-chrome-extensions-work&#34;&gt;How chrome extensions work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to publish chrome extenision, how chrome extensions work? why they are necessary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome extensions are essentially web apps that use web technologies but are limited to the Chrome browser. They run in a sandboxed environment, ensuring they don&amp;rsquo;t interfere with the webpage content unless explicitly designed to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background Scripts: Handle the behind-the-scenes logic, such as listening for specific browser events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Scripts: Injected into web pages to modify their content or behavior.
Popup HTML: Defines the UI, which appears when users click the extension icon.
Extensions: communicates with web pages through messages and shared storage, maintaining separation while enabling interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-publish-new-extensions&#34;&gt;To publish new extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To publish a Chrome extension, we must create a developer account on the Google Chrome Web Store. As of writing this post, Google requires a one-time registration fee of 5 USD for setting up this account. This fee is intended to verify the developer&amp;rsquo;s identity and to discourage spam and fraudulent extensions on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;extension-code&#34;&gt;Extension code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extension code that is responsible to detect the ads on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt; observer = new MutationObserver((mutations) =&amp;gt; {
mutations.forEach((mutation) =&amp;gt; {
// filter the target to contain only if it is adPlaying or not
if (
mutation &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
mutation.target &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
mutation.target.cloneNode().classList &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
mutation.target.classList.contains(&amp;quot;adPlaying&amp;quot;)
) {
// mute the tab
} else {
if (chrome &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chrome.runtime) {
// unmute the tab
}
}
});
});
observer.observe(accuradioPlayerControls, {
attributes: true,
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating Chrome extensions, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to handle permissions carefully. Given that Chrome is designed with a robust focus on security and user privacy, any extension listed on the Chrome Web Store is required to request only the permissions essential for its functions. The principle of &amp;ldquo;minimum necessary privileges&amp;rdquo; is not just a best practice in security; it is a fundamental requirement. This principle dictates that an extension should operate with the least amount of privileges it needs to function properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had this happen to me, more permission than I actaully needed, so my first submission was rejected, but then I re-submitted with the permissions fine grained, it got approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//bluepie.in/images/posts/jan2024/chrome-store-rejection.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;link-to-chrome-extension&#34;&gt;Link to chrome extension:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/mute-audio-ads-on-website/lhgmlkkpdhcgenmglmbomhemkkgccjef&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/mute-audio-ads-on-website/lhgmlkkpdhcgenmglmbomhemkkgccjef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-update&#34;&gt;Personal update:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brought my mom to chennai; im getting home food again. close friend left to hometown. Mom asking me to buy stuff for the new home; so doing that. Going pretty well~&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>