<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bluepie&#39;s update blog on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</title><link>//bluepie.in/</link><description>Recent content in Bluepie&#39;s update blog on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 04:55:51 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Reversing Part 3</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 04:55:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi!, Its nice to post weekely for a change, I never posted weekely before, anyway this might be a one time thing(posting weekely).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer-im-just-sharing-information-not-distrubuting-mod-files-here-this-is-strictly-for-learning-purposes-only&#34;&gt;Disclaimer : Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-start-why&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start &amp;amp; why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you forgot for some reason, this is part-3 of android reversing/modding, I recommend checking out the previous post &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Android Reversing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Android Reversing Part 2&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; in &amp;lsquo;reversing category&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our test subject for today will be Terria, Its a game costing &amp;ldquo;410 rupees&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;5.38&amp;rdquo; usd,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not a huge sum for a one time fee, but its some amount, and why pay if you have alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-this-game&#34;&gt;why this game?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this game on trending, after checking it out, I came to know it was a popular game with a large fanbase. Watching some gameplay made me hooked up to this game. I wanted to try it. (but not pay for it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-to-get-it-for-free-google-search-and-download-it&#34;&gt;How to get it for free?, google search and download it?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you know me I don&amp;rsquo;t trust the any sources other than google-play, since it is very easy to attach a backdoor to any apk, I do not want that..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-how&#34;&gt;So how?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incase you do not know, google has a 30 min window(atleast at the time of writing) (i.e.) if you buy anything on google-play store, within 30 minutes you can choose refund, refund will be provided no questions asked and app will be uninstalled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick here is to take a backup of the app before clicking the refund button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem with this method is that, some apps verify (license with google-play) whether if you have really bought the app. So when we try to install the app and open it, the app will not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so lets see how we can overcome this..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;continue-d&#34;&gt;continue..d&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said this section is just a continuation of the prevous posts titled &amp;lsquo;Android Reversing Part 2&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;android reversing&amp;rsquo;. The basics, installations, decompiling, recompiling and other stuff are in those post, check them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;patching&#34;&gt;Patching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/google/play/licensing&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;license verification&lt;/a&gt; is a library provided by google that comes packged with the app, using our tools, we can decompile and search the files for weak spots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You say license patching? Why not use lucky patcher, I dont want trust it/installn it/ risk being hit by malware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By analysing the files we find the following lines, they reveal the different codes used for mainting the license check, using these we can proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-smali&#34;&gt;
# static fields
...
.field private static final LICENSED:I = 0x0
.field private static final LICENSED_OLD_KEY:I = 0x2
.field private static final NOT_LICENSED:I = 0x1
.field private static final SIGNATURE_ALGORITHM:Ljava/lang/String; = &amp;quot;SHA1withRSA&amp;quot;
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by digging deeper, we come across an interesting method called &amp;ldquo;allowAccess&amp;rdquo;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-smali&#34;&gt;
invoke-interface {p2}, Lcom/google/android/vending/licensing/Policy;-&amp;gt;allowAccess()Z
move-result p2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by checking the source of the file &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/play-licensing/blob/master/lvl_library/src/main/java/com/google/android/vending/licensing/Policy.java&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github link&lt;/a&gt;, we can verify that this function does the magic work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
/**
* Policy used by {@link LicenseChecker} to determine whether a user should have
* access to the application.
*/
public interface Policy {
...
/**
* Provide results from contact with the license server. Retry counts are
* incremented if the current value of response is RETRY. Results will be
* used for any future policy decisions.
*
* @param response the result from validating the server response
* @param rawData the raw server response data, can be null for RETRY
*/
void processServerResponse(int response, ResponseData rawData);
/**
* Check if the user should be allowed access to the application.
*/
boolean allowAccess();
...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;override&#34;&gt;Override&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the java logic of our override is pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;original code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
if(mPolicyInterface.allowAccess()){
unlockApp();
} else{
lockApp();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;patched code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
if(true){ // we make this always true
unlockApp();
} else{
lockApp();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;the equivalent smali code will be&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;original smali code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-smali&#34;&gt;
invoke-interface {p2}, Lcom/google/android/vending/licensing/Policy;-&amp;gt;allowAccess()Z
move-result p2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;modified smali code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-smali&#34;&gt;
const p2, 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that is it, recompile, resign and install the app/game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;end&#34;&gt;End&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im not gona share the apk here, but I believe that I have shared the knowledge to do so. bye, see ya next time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Its Been Two Years..may</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/its-been-two-years/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 20:47:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/its-been-two-years/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi.. how are you, I am doing well, still doing work from home.. don&amp;rsquo;t know how long the work from home thing is going to continue. All my friends and family are good(no corona).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be a reminder for me in the future&amp;hellip; and also a milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;decision&#34;&gt;Decision&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well two years ago, exactly this week, I got an offer from a company in Chennai, at that time, I already had an offer from another company in Coimbatore that was close to my home with a nice package. I choose Chennai over Coimbatore because I wanted to leave my home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am after two years, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with my employer. I have my fair-share of cons, I&amp;rsquo;m sure everybody will have them, but the pros over-weigh the cons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lucky&#34;&gt;Lucky&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have joined them, they take such good care of me, I would argue that my team is the best of my company, Its a big team with a lot of talented people packed in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had the best team-lead unitll recently&amp;hellip;he left.., my piers are just awesome they can accomplism great things. The technical manager is also one of my team&amp;rsquo;s managers, he is a pretty good and can handle anything thrown at him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;one-complaint&#34;&gt;One complaint&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have good parents, friends, a job that I like in a place im in love with, All these excpet that one thing.. Of all these other things I have Im lost.. Im lost&amp;hellip; searching for something I can not find, distracting myself/ lying to myself, not enjoying/living in the movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things aside, &lt;em&gt;TO MY FUTURE SELF&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;two years went really fast didn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;hellip;always had the next thing to work on and you just looked away didn&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;, of all the things that happened over the last two years, from the bottom of my heart, I just wish I learned a lot more than I did..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I did in the past haunt me daily, those&amp;hellip;missed opportunities, those..fights, those&amp;hellip;bad decisions, those..misunderstandings. I guess its been a long time and I have to move on.. this month of may is something I should forget.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Github Workflow</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/github-workflow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 23:32:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/github-workflow/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi&amp;hellip; how ya been, its been a month already, gosh times flies by really fast. Status update: I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing good, When I am in home I complete the work that I plan&amp;hellip; far better than when I am in Chennai. The corona virus pandemic is still around the world at large, US right now is the largest affected country with over 70k dead people as of writing this. The lockdown in India has been extended
another 2 weeks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is going to be about github actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automate a process after commit, schedule a process to be done timely&amp;hellip;etc the possibililties are endless. A little background&amp;hellip; lastweek
github announced unlimited private colaborations and made a ton of premium features completely free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am going to use this feature entirely for a different purpose, It further backs-up my saying..literally anything can be done.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have this github repository which is XKCD viewer, which utilises api &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/info.0.json&#39;&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://xkcd.com/info.0.json&#39;&lt;/a&gt;. The api does not provide cors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to clone the api, (the clone must be updated daily).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;should provide cors support.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;should not contain any external dependencies like server to set it up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;github offers unlimited time constraint for github actions(public repository)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;using github actions I could setup a bot that runs timely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can mainatain a local copy of the api, compare it to the offical every day,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;if there is difference, then download the new contents and update the local state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;commit the changes directly to the repository.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;approach&#34;&gt;Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Im going with python in conjunction with workflow file, since I want to brush up my python skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The python logic will maintain a local state, add new contents, update itself i.e. the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am going to use json to maintain the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The api data will be stored under a folder with every entry having a unique folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use github actions to commit the changes to the directory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use github secrets to maintain a token, (token used to commit diretly to repository)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;Result.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coding away the mentioned logics above. I am left with this workflow file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34;&gt;
name: fetch new content from api
on:
schedule:
- cron: &#39;0 */8 * * *&#39;
jobs:
fetch-content:
if: github.repository == &#39;Gopinath001/xkcd-declutter&#39;
name: execute python logic
runs-on: ubuntu-latest
steps:
- uses: actions/checkout@v1
- name: install requests pip3
run: pip3 install requests
- name: run python logic
run: python3 ./.github/workflows/update_xkcd_official.py
- name: status of the new folder
run: git status xkcd-offline/ --porcelain
- name: add new files
run: |
git config --local user.name &amp;quot;xkcd-content-fetcher-bot&amp;quot;
git add xkcd-offline/
- name: commit new content
run: (awk &#39;{print &amp;quot;added content &amp;quot; substr($3, match($3,&amp;quot;\&amp;quot;&amp;quot;), match($3,&amp;quot;}&amp;quot;)-1) &amp;quot;.&amp;quot;}&#39; xkcd-offline/state.json) | git commit -F -
- name: push the new content
uses: ad-m/github-push-action@master
with:
github_token: ${{ secrets.TOKEN }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See it in action, downloads new content automatically and put it under the folder xkcd-offline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gopinath001/xkcd-declutter/tree/master/xkcd-offline/api&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Folder containing api content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;end&#34;&gt;End&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon, untill then hope you do well. - Gopinath aka aghontpi aka bluepie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Xkcd Declutter</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/04/xkcd-declutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:43:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/04/xkcd-declutter/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi, how are you doing&lt;/em&gt; Im doing good, the corona virus pandemic is everywhere! hope your survived the ordeal, its still going on as of writing this, Hope you survive this.. In my childhood after watching movies like &amp;lsquo;i am legend&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp; &amp;lsquo;the day that the earth stood still&amp;rsquo;, i always wanted to see the world in the situtation, oh booy, i did not expect them to happen irl, but it did anyway. Im saying this because in some wierd way dreams do come true.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-this-about&#34;&gt;What is this about?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I sometimes read xkcd, its not great but something that i occasionally checked, its a comic for programmers&amp;rsquo;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to lean angular for sometime (i only knew the basics, haven&amp;rsquo;t really done projects in them.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the xkcd site had a api for them!.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was no darkmode xkcd,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was ads in the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-plan&#34;&gt;The plan:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So i decided to do a xkcd viewer, (declutter) It will ads and unnecessary stuff from the site and just provide the comic.
It will have to have darkmode,
it will have to have an image viewer builtin for zooming in and out,
It should have a grid viewer to laod previous comics in a single page,
It should have a download option. both batch and single!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-did-conclusion&#34;&gt;what I did &amp;amp; Conclusion:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built a xkcd viewer app with the above requirements in angular, I tried to use much of the core functionality of angular
while building the requriements, I&amp;rsquo;ve also learnt about some interesting libraries, rxjs, imageViewer. Go checkout the repo for more info and demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Gopinath001/xkcd-declutter&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Link - xkcdViewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have kept this post short!. See you soon!. &amp;amp; About the name change!.. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen agontpi, hope i make up my mind soon. untill then -gopianth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Corona March 2020</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/03/corona-march-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 23:54:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/03/corona-march-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi guys, it&amp;rsquo;s been a month already??!&lt;/em&gt;. I had other plans for the update, this month but &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corona virus took over the entire Earth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, if me or anyone else reading this from the future search for &amp;lsquo;Corona virus March 2020&amp;rsquo; u&amp;rsquo;ll find about this disease. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;note that the status of the image in this psot is from march 30 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headpain&#34;&gt;headpain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some extra tests apart from last month, but everything came as normal, I still experience head ache&amp;rsquo;s, I have a fudge load of tablets to take for the headache, I am worried about my health, these many tablets can not do any good. wasted a ton of money tho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;virus&#34;&gt;virus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everything is shut down in India, all the tech companies give work from home including the one which I work, so its been a good couple of days working from home which I really like and by the way I came 7 days ago that is mid March.s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government announced 21 day Quarantine, which ends on April 15th. Hope everyone will survive through this ordeal. All my friends and family are doing fine at this moment but it may change at any point since the district I live in is one of the most affected in my state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;name-changing&#34;&gt;name changing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about changing my name I mean my online alis. from bluepie to something else. The name is not unique and also I chose this name when I was very young, making an anagram of my name would be really cool. I already have a few names that I have in mind but those are not anagram. The logical way is to go with anagram, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really like it. I just want to have it because it is an anagram of my name and also it resembles the current name i.e bluepie. I hope by next time i have chosen the right name,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So that is it for this month, hope we see soon. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;-Gopinath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Healthproblem Migraine</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/02/healthproblem-migraine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 03:51:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/02/healthproblem-migraine/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, this will be q quick update this month, Recently my health is deteriating, on the account of me moving to chennai, living alone, I lost a lot of weight almost 20 kilo&amp;rsquo;s to be exact. Adding to it, this month(february 2020) has seen a lof ot twist &amp;amp; turns mentally, to be from no issues with my health and to this(wow), all of this this quick is something to consider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-problem-is&#34;&gt;what the problem is?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been having constant headache&amp;rsquo;s recently, at first it was frequent, then came the continuous hail-marry of a strom, that lasted weeks,
at first me &amp;amp; my surrounding people thought it was just a eye problem, that is why I was just leaving it, without checking it out,
but the docter just gave me the finger &amp;amp; told to it was not the case, then i consulted a physican, took scans and fudge then the doctor told
me to consult a neurologist, which i did, then came the list of tests what burned my money to nothing, then the docter came to the conclusion that it was migrain, the tests showed me that i was sleep depraved, (which i dont agree), the docter in addition to prescribing
pills told me that I have &amp;ldquo;migraine&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; that I should maintain work life balance, meditate more, take breaks in between works,..and some usual bullcrap which I do not
buy at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later after all this mess I still have the problem, lost a lot of money, lost dignity(work place), added a ton of chemicals to my
body(still adding..), I have been asked to have an another appointment with them, Im already having a difficult time with managing time,
but this made it a lot worse. (with the constant pain in the back of my head).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Noises or Im Wrong</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/01/noises-or-im-wrong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 10:32:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/01/noises-or-im-wrong/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hi, How are you, I hope you are doing good, me? i&amp;rsquo;m good as well from the top down view, but if inspected carefully, im not so good. This post is not going to be about tech.. so skip this if you wish. note: this post was completed in the month of januray but only published it on feb.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-this-about&#34;&gt;what is this about&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lately i&amp;rsquo;ve been contemplating on a lot of things!, some of &amp;lsquo;em include, life goals, relationships, fiends, money, how we interact as human beings, etc&amp;hellip;all these are interconnected to one another, I have decided to share this today as im 23 years old, it would be fun to see how things change over the years when im 28, 33, .. so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;life-goals&#34;&gt;life goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I ask you something? what is your life goal, It should be either of two, &lt;em&gt;1. you have a defined life goal, 2. you do not have a life goal, you are going with a flow&lt;/em&gt;, I have experienced both of &amp;lsquo;em, so here is my take on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are moving towards a point and all actions that you make must be towards that point you belong to this category if you have a life goal, in-short: Short term goals that matter in the long run(to achieve a final goal).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You take decisions based on what you currently feel/have, short term goals that doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a third category that I did not mention, which is terrible of em all, which is you take decisions based on other people&amp;rsquo;s suggestion, it is bad beacuse u feel regrets after the decision is made and you realise that, you are responsible for your
current scenario by not taking your own decision.(confusing i know, but there it is)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my parents are both 2nd category from my point of view, atleast my father is.. I strieve to be the first category&amp;hellip; but I am weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;relationships&#34;&gt;relationships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my openion when i was in my 10th grade, 11th &amp;amp; 12th, love is a beautiful thing, is a necessity, is a social status, you are a if you are not currently in a loving relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an anwser of mine before 3 years ago, when i was asked a question &amp;ldquo;what do you think about love?&amp;rdquo; in a group gathering of my peers, teachers &amp;amp; parents, &amp;lsquo;is just a distraction, a mixture of chemical compounds in brain is to be blamed for it.&amp;rsquo; So my openion is little changed, i&amp;rsquo;ve removed &amp;ldquo;its just a distraction part&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;friendships&#34;&gt;friendships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when i was young(upuntill 12th) I had a lot of friends, it was a social status, I dont care about it anymore(was not selfaware at that time, more about this maybe in a different post),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-belief-s&#34;&gt;core-belief&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thing dawned on me few months ago &amp;amp; once in a while i&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about it ever since, what am i talking about here?,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well it is about &amp;ldquo;everyone has their own belief such as what makes one&amp;rsquo;s action differ from right and
wrong, what is considered humiliation, what is considered success, sadness, depression&amp;hellip;etc.&amp;rdquo; these belief&amp;rsquo;s come from either through
parents or from movies/shows(mostly), talking with others(mostly), (rarely) from books, and very rare from own experience. since we
do not in-herit these belief&amp;rsquo;s from own experience/thoughts, it will not be useful for you &amp;amp; if you make decisions its gona 70% of the time
fail for you(if you belong to the minority category of different people).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my conclusion from all this is &amp;ldquo;unless you are absolutely sure about your core belief, do not think over it of the outcomes&amp;rdquo;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-utopian-dream&#34;&gt;my utopian dream&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So from my childhood i have seen my surroundings &amp;amp; i dreamt I would go in a different path, Which is &amp;ldquo;People become thick friends, go out, , fall in love, get married to people in the circle only they interact with/ their neighbours.&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; I wanted this to be opposite of that, but right untill now i&amp;rsquo;ve had chances to claim my dream but I did not do so, (mmo&amp;rsquo;s, guild&amp;rsquo;s, discord, tele, communi..onli..).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;anyway these are my present thoughts, see ya soon!. hope u do well untill then -gopinath.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Custom Dns Server With Adblock</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/custom-dns-server-with-adblock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 14:15:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/custom-dns-server-with-adblock/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hello guys, as of writing this post this is christmas of 2019 (25 dec 2019), gosh time really goes fast!. How was the holidays? personal update: I have sevre cold &amp;amp; fever as of writing this, hope i&amp;rsquo;ll get better soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;today-im-going-to-share-my-method-of-adblocking-with-custom-dns-servers&#34;&gt;Today im going to share my method of adblocking with custom dns servers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-requiremets&#34;&gt;my requiremets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want adblocking solution without any addons &amp;amp; applications for laptops/desktops/mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want it universal (meaning it has to work outside of my home network)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should not waste time setting it up (should be quick and simple to setup)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should be configurable (easy to configure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should work perfectly &amp;amp; should not cost me anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;explanation&#34;&gt;explanation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound pretty simple ain&amp;rsquo;t it? we&amp;rsquo;ll it ain&amp;rsquo;t easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;crossplatform-laptop-mobile-anydevice-that-has-access-to-internet&#34;&gt;crossplatform (laptop/mobile/..anydevice that has access to internet)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requirement rules out addons, applications on all devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;work-outside-of-my-home-network&#34;&gt;work outside of my home network)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requirement rules out private adblocking solutions, so a server is need for this, luckly, I have server on aws,
&lt;em&gt;but that server is already being used for a different purpose, so it has to be minimal impact on the cpu and memory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;obvious anwser would be to use pi-hole &lt;a href=&#34;work outside of my home network&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pie-hole&lt;/a&gt;), my experience with pie-hole is not good, let me explain what i mean by that, I had problems trying to install it(the automated script did not work for me), it took me so much time to debug the error, second is it had a extra bit of cpu load compared to my other options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;should-be-quick-and-simple-to-setup&#34;&gt;should be quick and simple to setup)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should not waste time learning a new tool,(don&amp;rsquo;t a industrial level dns server, I just need a simple solution), plus if any error, it should be easy for me to debug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;configurable-easy-to-configure&#34;&gt;configurable (easy to configure)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some things i looked for, should be
* able to mention, forward dns vendor (google/opendns)
* easy to install
* easy to add adblocking lists (just add files from differnet adblock sources)
* easy to add whitelists
* i should have a log, to inspect if anything is not working&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;should-not-cost-me-anything&#34;&gt;should not cost me anything&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes the solution to be open source, I already have a server that i am paying for so i&amp;rsquo;ll just add this to it, So there is no additional cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hidden-gem-the-solution&#34;&gt;Hidden gem - The solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after trying several solutions(trust me i wasted a lot of time, installing &amp;amp; uninstalling) I arrived at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/looterz/grimd&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;grimd&lt;/a&gt;, an opensource project written in go. It had all the capabilities that I mentioned above(checkout the grimd&amp;rsquo;s page), It even comes in prebuilt binaries, So i do not even have to compile anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-it-to-myserver&#34;&gt;Installing it to myserver&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;download the binary from the release page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run it on the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open port 51 (udp &amp;amp; tcp) on firewall inside cloud instance &amp;amp; vendor firewall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add my custom adblock list to the config file (grimd.toml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change default nameserver to google dns in config file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;change the dns server on my laptops &amp;amp; mobiles, that is it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that is it, that is all i have to do, here is the log where it is in action&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
20:29:01.341 DEBU handler.go:252 ▶ 103c insert d.joinhoney.com IN A into cache with ttl 140
20:29:11.361 INFO handler.go:102 ▶ 103d 219.91.177.2 lookup　vortex.data.microsoft.com IN AAAA
20:29:11.361 DEBU cache.go:208 ▶ 103e KeyGen: vortex.data.microsoft.com IN AAAA 6210738ab9fea7763f2ba8ec16beb2c3
20:29:11.361 DEBU cache.go:123 ▶ 103f Cache: Key expired 6210738ab9fea7763f2ba8ec16beb2c3
20:29:11.361 DEBU cache.go:133 ▶ 1040 Cache: Cannot find key 6210738ab9fea7763f2ba8ec16beb2c3
20:29:11.361 DEBU handler.go:124 ▶ 1041 vortex.data.microsoft.com IN AAAA didn&#39;t hit cache
20:29:11.361 NOTI handler.go:180 ▶ 1042 vortex.data.microsoft.com found in blocklist
20:29:11.362 INFO handler.go:102 ▶ 1043 219.91.177.2 lookup　vortex.data.microsoft.com IN A
20:29:11.362 DEBU cache.go:208 ▶ 1044 KeyGen: vortex.data.microsoft.com IN A 87ca3e2c1cf9d028f97ce6794f963327
20:29:11.362 DEBU cache.go:123 ▶ 1045 Cache: Key expired 87ca3e2c1cf9d028f97ce6794f963327
20:29:11.362 DEBU cache.go:133 ▶ 1046 Cache: Cannot find key 87ca3e2c1cf9d028f97ce6794f963327
20:29:11.362 DEBU handler.go:124 ▶ 1047 vortex.data.microsoft.com IN A didn&#39;t hit cache
20:29:11.362 NOTI handler.go:180 ▶ 1048 vortex.data.microsoft.com found in blocklist
20:29:30.496 INFO handler.go:102 ▶ 1049 219.91.177.2 lookup　vortex.data.microsoft.com IN A
20:29:30.496 DEBU cache.go:208 ▶ 104a KeyGen: vortex.data.microsoft.com IN A 87ca3e2c1cf9d028f97ce6794f963327
20:29:30.496 DEBU cache.go:123 ▶ 104b Cache: Key expired 87ca3e2c1cf9d028f97ce6794f963327
20:29:30.496 DEBU cache.go:133 ▶ 104c Cache: Cannot find key 87ca3e2c1cf9d028f97ce6794f963327
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-might-argue-that-this-is-not-a-dns-server-it-is-a-proxy-server-for-dns-well-it-depends-up-how-you-see-it&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; You might argue that, this is not a dns server, it is a proxy server for dns. Well it depends up how you see it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my experience, its simple, awsome &amp;amp; works great, No ads system wide! on all networks! on all devices!,
My very own private dns server..XD.If you have any doubts, just dm me!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Liunx LD_PRELOAD</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:28:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hello me, this is going to be a short post that is very interesting to me and I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I have missed this all this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve known to break binary files directly by directly debugging them, mostly the windows files are binary extensions, I have worked even on dll files, which is somewhat similar to .so files on linux, both perform the same functions except that linux part is open source, and i&amp;rsquo;ve seen many articles using this partuclar approrach in many different ways(ofcourse after knowing about this only, I searched for those articles), A bit of personal update - so its been a tough month actually, progress interms of self development is zero, progress in terms of social level is a wip, but still a development. So you understand this right!. anyway the memorable thing that i did this month is going on a office trip to kerala, personally i would prefer to go alone, (only a few people accompanying me!) but gosh dang it!, anyway lets not talk about it. :(. In terms of development work (tech related) that is big zero on the professional side as well as personal side, except a few python scripts &amp;amp; spjs(that is a different topic to discuss entirely)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ld_preload is actually pretty basic if you think about it, ld_preload is a linux feature of linux, which is for? so u take a library for example &amp;ldquo;lib that resolves ip address for hostname&amp;rdquo; - lib_curl , get the source, modfify the source for evil purposes, compile it and then load that library for the application you want to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;actually this could go south even if a small mistake is made, the development process looks like this, okey take an example of some app or a program, ex: ping, ping google.com -&amp;gt; gives you the ip address, time delay etc. You do strace ping somewebsite then you get all the system calls that the ping binary makes, you could theoritcally make a list of method calls that the app makes to system, write a custom implementation of the system calls probally malicious and take over the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;system calls that ping made during ping google.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
execve(&amp;quot;/bin/ping&amp;quot;, [&amp;quot;ping&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;google.com&amp;quot;], 0x7fffe83a4978 /* 62 vars */) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/suid-debug&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
brk(NULL) = 0x559075d1a000
fcntl(0, F_GETFD) = 0
fcntl(1, F_GETFD) = 0
fcntl(2, F_GETFD) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/suid-debug&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.nohwcap&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.preload&amp;quot;, R_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.cache&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=113810, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 113810, PROT_READ, MAP_PRIVATE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76c189a000
close(3) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.nohwcap&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libcap.so.2&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
read(3, &amp;quot;\177ELF\2\1\1\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\3\0&amp;gt;\0\1\0\0\0\20\30\0\0\0\0\0\0&amp;quot;..., 832) = 832
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=22768, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 8192, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0) = 0x7f76c1898000
mmap(NULL, 2117976, PROT_READ|PROT_EXEC, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76c1489000
mprotect(0x7f76c148d000, 2097152, PROT_NONE) = 0
mmap(0x7f76c168d000, 8192, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0x4000) = 0x7f76c168d000
close(3) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.nohwcap&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libidn.so.11&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
read(3, &amp;quot;\177ELF\2\1\1\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\3\0&amp;gt;\0\1\0\0\0\0+\0\0\0\0\0\0&amp;quot;..., 832) = 832
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=206872, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 2302000, PROT_READ|PROT_EXEC, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76c1256000
mprotect(0x7f76c1288000, 2093056, PROT_NONE) = 0
mmap(0x7f76c1487000, 8192, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0x31000) = 0x7f76c1487000
close(3) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.nohwcap&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libnettle.so.6&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
read(3, &amp;quot;\177ELF\2\1\1\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\3\0&amp;gt;\0\1\0\0\0\340\200\0\0\0\0\0\0&amp;quot;..., 832) = 832
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=219304, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 2314384, PROT_READ|PROT_EXEC, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76c1020000
mprotect(0x7f76c1054000, 2093056, PROT_NONE) = 0
mmap(0x7f76c1253000, 12288, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0x33000) = 0x7f76c1253000
close(3) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.nohwcap&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libresolv.so.2&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
read(3, &amp;quot;\177ELF\2\1\1\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\3\0&amp;gt;\0\1\0\0\00008\0\0\0\0\0\0&amp;quot;..., 832) = 832
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=101168, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 2206336, PROT_READ|PROT_EXEC, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76c0e05000
mprotect(0x7f76c0e1c000, 2097152, PROT_NONE) = 0
mmap(0x7f76c101c000, 8192, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0x17000) = 0x7f76c101c000
mmap(0x7f76c101e000, 6784, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0) = 0x7f76c101e000
close(3) = 0
access(&amp;quot;/etc/ld.so.nohwcap&amp;quot;, F_OK) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/lib/x86_64-linux-gnu/libc.so.6&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
read(3, &amp;quot;\177ELF\2\1\1\3\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\0\3\0&amp;gt;\0\1\0\0\0\260\34\2\0\0\0\0\0&amp;quot;..., 832) = 832
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0755, st_size=2030544, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 4131552, PROT_READ|PROT_EXEC, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76c0a14000
mprotect(0x7f76c0bfb000, 2097152, PROT_NONE) = 0
mmap(0x7f76c0dfb000, 24576, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_DENYWRITE, 3, 0x1e7000) = 0x7f76c0dfb000
mmap(0x7f76c0e01000, 15072, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_FIXED|MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0) = 0x7f76c0e01000
close(3) = 0
mmap(NULL, 8192, PROT_READ|PROT_WRITE, MAP_PRIVATE|MAP_ANONYMOUS, -1, 0) = 0x7f76c1896000
arch_prctl(ARCH_SET_FS, 0x7f76c1896f00) = 0
mprotect(0x7f76c0dfb000, 16384, PROT_READ) = 0
mprotect(0x7f76c101c000, 4096, PROT_READ) = 0
mprotect(0x7f76c1253000, 8192, PROT_READ) = 0
mprotect(0x7f76c1487000, 4096, PROT_READ) = 0
mprotect(0x7f76c168d000, 4096, PROT_READ) = 0
mprotect(0x559075bcc000, 4096, PROT_READ) = 0
mprotect(0x7f76c18b6000, 4096, PROT_READ) = 0
munmap(0x7f76c189a000, 113810) = 0
brk(NULL) = 0x559075d1a000
brk(0x559075d3b000) = 0x559075d3b000
capget({version=_LINUX_CAPABILITY_VERSION_3, pid=0}, NULL) = 0
capget({version=_LINUX_CAPABILITY_VERSION_3, pid=0}, {effective=0, permitted=0, inheritable=0}) = 0
capget({version=_LINUX_CAPABILITY_VERSION_3, pid=0}, NULL) = 0
capset({version=_LINUX_CAPABILITY_VERSION_3, pid=0}, {effective=0, permitted=0, inheritable=0}) = 0
prctl(PR_SET_KEEPCAPS, 1) = 0
getuid() = 1000
setuid(1000) = 0
prctl(PR_SET_KEEPCAPS, 0) = 0
getuid() = 1000
geteuid() = 1000
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/lib/locale/locale-archive&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=10756928, ...}) = 0
mmap(NULL, 10756928, PROT_READ, MAP_PRIVATE, 3, 0) = 0x7f76bffd1000
close(3) = 0
capget({version=_LINUX_CAPABILITY_VERSION_3, pid=0}, NULL) = 0
capget({version=_LINUX_CAPABILITY_VERSION_3, pid=0}, {effective=0, permitted=0, inheritable=0}) = 0
socket(AF_INET, SOCK_DGRAM, IPPROTO_ICMP) = -1 EACCES (Permission denied)
socket(AF_INET, SOCK_RAW, IPPROTO_ICMP) = -1 EPERM (Operation not permitted)
socket(AF_INET6, SOCK_DGRAM, IPPROTO_ICMPV6) = -1 EACCES (Permission denied)
socket(AF_INET6, SOCK_RAW, IPPROTO_ICMPV6) = -1 EPERM (Operation not permitted)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/locale.alias&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
fstat(3, {st_mode=S_IFREG|0644, st_size=2995, ...}) = 0
read(3, &amp;quot;# Locale name alias data base.\n#&amp;quot;..., 4096) = 2995
read(3, &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, 4096) = 0
close(3) = 0
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/en_IN.UTF-8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/en_IN.utf8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/en_IN/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/en.UTF-8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/en.utf8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale/en/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale-langpack/en_IN.UTF-8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale-langpack/en_IN.utf8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale-langpack/en_IN/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale-langpack/en.UTF-8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale-langpack/en.utf8/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
openat(AT_FDCWD, &amp;quot;/usr/share/locale-langpack/en/LC_MESSAGES/libc.mo&amp;quot;, O_RDONLY) = -1 ENOENT (No such file or directory)
write(2, &amp;quot;ping: socket: Operation not perm&amp;quot;..., 38ping: socket: Operation not permitted
) = 38
exit_group(2) = ?
+++ exited with 2 +++
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a similar implementation recently that looks really awsome, that made me write about this, i have known this for some time now, but i can not just let it go, the repository link is this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abba23/spotify-adblock-linux&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ld_preload&lt;/a&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;m not supporting this particular implementation (adblock) to be used everywhere, im just curious!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the source its very facinating how things are done in the linux world, how come i never knew about this untill a few months ago, obviously you can argue that you can make a custom network filter in the linux machine to achieve this (only allow certain apps to make api calls), there are several apps that do this, I&amp;rsquo;m not disaggreing with you on that matter, but you can not deny this also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to make something similar with this usecase, &amp;ldquo;lp_preload to make life better!&amp;ldquo;, If you have any ideas just throw them in the comment section, or dm me personlly!. I&amp;rsquo;d love to do it. Anyway see ya next time &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;And Merry Christmas, And a happy new year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Game Dev</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/11/game-dev/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 11:46:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/11/game-dev/</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hey!, hope you are doing well!, im good, This post should have gone up in the month of august and this post should
have been a follow-up, anyway never too late. Update: Im following a tight schedule for the past few weeks, tight-schedule
in the sense &amp;ldquo;wake-up -&amp;gt; commute-to-office -&amp;gt; professional code-&amp;gt; aftier-office -&amp;gt; passion code -&amp;gt; sleep&amp;rdquo; throw in breaks, travel,
and Personal hygene time in there, at-first it was awful, but after some while got the hang of it,Infact it became like addiction
to me at this point &amp;amp; im craving for more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-what&#34;&gt;why &amp;amp; what&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in the month of september a friend of mine asked me whether I can Join him in making game, till that point in time,
I haven&amp;rsquo;t done game development. So the gamejam was js13kgames, though it ran for a month we went into working only in the
last seven days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;development-stack&#34;&gt;development stack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;javascript,
gulp for automated tasks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;apart from the time constraint of a month to finish, this also included a constraint which is, the total size of the
game must be less than 13 kilobytes and a topic to develop unde, which is not quite a lot. Everything developed for the competition was from scratch except the sound library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the gamejam was for a month, the actual dev period was for 7 days, to be honest it was more like 2-3 days of dev.
(Project mate) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FR0ST1N/Pew-Pew/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FR0ST1N&lt;/a&gt; was sick during the last few days so the game was not complete, I made the decision to submit
it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is gona be the disection of different parts of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ui&#34;&gt;UI&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pixel art for game images, since we were limited on the size aspect of the game, we could not have high res image assets.Spritesheets were used for the development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a seperate class for parsing the spriteSheet &amp;amp; maintining it states based on the sprite attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
/*
* Porperties the sprite has to manipulate it
*/
const image = new Image();
image.src = &#39;images/&#39; + imagename;
this.image = image;
this.rows = rows;
this.columns = columns;
this.individualSpriteSize = individualSpriteSize;
this.totalSpriteSize = totalSpriteSize;
this.position = position;
this.scaleFactorX = scaleFactorX;
this.scaleFactorY = scaleFactorY;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;animation&#34;&gt;animation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bare api calls, small framework that can be used in future projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explanation on how that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core is based on values defined by you, fps is set accordingly &amp;amp; callbacks are called,
these callbacks are responsilbe for object-animation &amp;amp; object movement, all logic should be done with those callbacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;following this principle, animation was done to the most part, code for the same is below&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main callbacks from the animation class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
/*
* Animation properties that all object in canvas should have,
* ex |------------------------| represent total time
* |-----x------x------x-----| represent time to next frame.
*/
/**
* reset the animation timer,
* @return {void}
*/
_resetAnimationTimer() {
this.animationTimer = 0;
}
/**
* reset the animation timer,
* @return {void}
*/
_resetMotionTimer() {
this.motionTimer = 0;
}
/**
* @return {void}
*/
stepTimer() {
if (this.timeToChangeAnimation != 0) {
this.animationTimer += 1;
} if (this.timeToChangeMotion != 0) {
this.motionTimer += 1;
}
}
/**
* @return {boolean}
*/
isTimeToAnimate() {
if (this.timeToChangeAnimation == 0) {
return true;
} if (this.animationTimer == this.timeToChangeAnimation) {
this._resetAnimationTimer();
return true;
}
return false;
}
/**
* @return {boolean}
*/
isTimeToMove() {
if (this.timeToChangeMotion == 0) {
return true;
} if (this.motionTimer == this.timeToChangeMotion) {
this._resetMotionTimer();
return true;
} else {
return false;
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main callbacks from timer&lt;low-level&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
/**
* wrapper Draw.
*/
wDraw() {
this.context.drawImage(
this.sprite.image,
this.sprite.position.x,
this.sprite.position.y,
this.sprite.individualSpriteSize,
this.sprite.individualSpriteSize,
this.position.x, this.position.y,
this.sprite.individualSpriteSize * this.sprite.scaleFactorX,
this.sprite.individualSpriteSize * this.sprite.scaleFactorY
);
}
/**
* override this method in child classe, for animation logic.
* when it is time for next frame, this method will be called.
*/
objectUpdate() {
}
/**
* makes decisions whether to redraw,
* based on the fps defined.
*/
postObjectUpdate() {
this.stepTimer();
if (this.isTimeToMove()) {
this._Movement();
} if (this.isTimeToAnimate()) {
this.objectUpdate();
} this.objectAnimation();
}
/**
* object movement loop
*/
objectAnimation() {
this.animationTimerId = setTimeout(() =&amp;gt; {
this.postObjectUpdate();
}, 1);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;where-i-struggled&#34;&gt;Where I struggled&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level designing was the part that i struggled the most, since from what we had to work with, I was finding it hard to come up with a good gameplay anyhow based on the time constraint (two hours before deadline for the game), I came up with a level design involving two fire-animations (straight pattern &amp;amp; follow pattern)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;following is the level logic that I cameup &amp;amp; implemented in 15min.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
//@level logic from class level
/**
* design
* level one:
* one enemy, straight bullet, health = 1, rateOfFire = (1000-100/level=1)
* level two:
* two enemy:
* 1st enemy: straight bullet, health = 2, rateOfFire = (1000-100/level=2)
* last enemy: follow bullet, health,rateOfFire=same as 1st enemy
* ... progressive, all the last enemy has the follow bullet
*/
levelTrigger() {
for (let enemyCounter = 1; enemyCounter &amp;lt;= this.level;
enemyCounter++ ) {
const enemy = this.enenmyOneFactory(
new Position(800, enemyCounter * 50 + 100),
this.level,
(1000 - 100) / this.level);
enemy.startAnimation(this.context);
enemy.autoshoot = true;
if (this.level != 1 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; enemyCounter == this.level) {
enemy.setBulletPattern(BulletPattern.FOLLOW);
}
enemy.shoot();
this.currentLevelEnemies.push(enemy);
this.drawableObjects.push(enemy);
}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;collision-detection&#34;&gt;collision Detection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collision detection was straight forward too, you just compare the two rectangles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
/**
* collideDetect of enemyObject with given bullet
* @param {Bullet} bullet
* @return {boolean}
*/
collideDetect(bullet) {
if (this.position == null || bullet.position == null ) {
return false;
}
const bulletObject = {&#39;x&#39;: bullet.position.x,
&#39;y&#39;: bullet.position.y,
&#39;width&#39;: bullet.sprite.individualSpriteSize * bullet.sprite.scaleFactorX,
&#39;height&#39;: bullet.sprite.individualSpriteSize * bullet.sprite.scaleFactorY,
};
const EnemyObject = {
&#39;x&#39;: this.position.x,
&#39;y&#39;: this.position.y,
&#39;width&#39;: this.sprite.individualSpriteSize * this.sprite.scaleFactorX,
&#39;height&#39;: this.sprite.individualSpriteSize * this.sprite.scaleFactorY,
};
return CollisionDetection.detect(bulletObject, EnemyObject);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sound&#34;&gt;Sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small library extending from previous year&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FR0ST1N/Pew-Pew/blob/develop/src/js/audio/audioEffects.js&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AudioEffects.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fonts&#34;&gt;Fonts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Even using texts take a huge hit on the size of the game, we found a custom font implementation &amp;amp; modified it to fit our usecase, since the font class mainly contains hardcoded values for drawing fonts to the canvas, I have linked just the source below.
[font.js](https://github.com/FR0ST1N/Pew-Pew/blob/develop/src/js/font/font.js)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the fonts can be used by the following way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
this.ctx.fillStyle = &#39;#00bff3&#39;;
const CORRECTION = (value.length - 1) * 20;
Font.draw(value, size, this.ctx, 775 - CORRECTION, 10);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;build&#34;&gt;Build&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For automating the build process gulp was used, the commands from gulp are pretty straight forward, can be understood just from telling the commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;
gulp.task(&#39;cssLint&#39;, function() {
return gulp.src(&#39;src/css/*.css&#39;)
.pipe(cssLint({
reporters: [{formatter: &#39;string&#39;, console: true}],
}));
});
gulp.task(&#39;jsLint&#39;, function() {
return gulp.src(&#39;src/js/**/*.js&#39;)
.pipe(concat(&#39;main.js&#39;))
.pipe(jsLint())
.pipe(jsLint.format())
.pipe(jsLint.failAfterError());
});
gulp.task(&#39;htmlBuild&#39;, function() {
return gulp.src(&#39;src/index.html&#39;)
.pipe(htmlMin({
collapseWhitespace: true,
removeComments: true,
html5: true,
}))
.pipe(gulp.dest(&#39;build&#39;));
});
gulp.task(&#39;cssBuild&#39;, function() {
return gulp.src(&#39;src/css/*.css&#39;)
.pipe(concat(&#39;style.min.css&#39;))
.pipe(cssMin())
.pipe(gulp.dest(&#39;build/css&#39;));
});
gulp.task(&#39;jsBuild&#39;, function() {
return gulp.src(jsConcat, {allowEmpty: true})
.pipe(concat(&#39;main.js&#39;))
.pipe(jsMin({
noSource: true,
ext: {
min: &#39;.min.js&#39;,
},
}))
.pipe(gulp.dest(&#39;build/js&#39;));
});
gulp.task(&#39;imageMin&#39;, function() {
return gulp.src(&#39;src/images/*&#39;)
.pipe(imageMin({optimizationLevel: 5}))
.pipe(gulp.dest(&#39;build/images&#39;));
});
gulp.task(&#39;zip&#39;, function() {
const maxSize = 1024 * 13;
return gulp.src(&#39;build/**&#39;)
.pipe(zip(&#39;Pew-Pew.zip&#39;))
.pipe(gulp.dest(&#39;zip&#39;))
.pipe(checkSize({fileSizeLimit: maxSize}));
});
gulp.task(&#39;lint&#39;, gulp.parallel(
&#39;htmlLint&#39;,
&#39;cssLint&#39;,
&#39;jsLint&#39;
));
gulp.task(&#39;build&#39;, gulp.series(
&#39;lint&#39;,
&#39;clean&#39;,
&#39;htmlBuild&#39;,
&#39;cssBuild&#39;,
&#39;jsBuild&#39;,
&#39;jsfxr&#39;,
&#39;imageMin&#39;,
&#39;zip&#39;,
&#39;genDocs&#39;
));
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;submission-conclusion&#34;&gt;submission - conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last day, 80% of the game was completed, everything was to be put together, except that my team mate was very ill &amp;amp; could not work on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We almost did not submit because the game cuz &amp;lsquo;incomplete, except we did submit the game that was too because I insisted on submitting,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend &amp;amp; partner in the project.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FR0ST1N/Pew-Pew/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FR0ST1N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, It was fun..&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 19:30:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;hey, how ya been. so this is a another reversing post (reverse engineering android mod). So before some months,
I gave some basic info to reversing android apps with a practical example(ttorrent). This post is gona build on
top of that post. basically pretty advanced version of that post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-just-sharing-information-not-distrubuting-mod-files-here-this-is-strictly-for-learning-purposes-only&#34;&gt;Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-off&#34;&gt;Starting off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just continue where we left off shall we. Today the practical example that we are gona use is Spotify lite,
this at the time of writing, is newly repleased, with version &amp;lsquo;0.13.13.6&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;why spotify? Cause i love the app, but too broke to pay for subscription and the ads are just painful, i just want
to remove the ads. You could ask the question &amp;ldquo;bu..but there are always mods available in the outside market?&amp;rdquo; Yea
those are available, but my simple answer is trust, especially nowadays it very easy to
attach a backdoor in any app, and also the fact that I love doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we train by making the ads stop and add premium features to it, keep in-mind we converting only the client to
be premium, server assisted premium features won&amp;rsquo;t work here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so here we go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;continue-d&#34;&gt;continue..d&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said this section is just a continuation of the prevous post titled &amp;lsquo;android reversing&amp;rsquo;, starting things up with
decompiling and recompiling are in that post,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;errors&#34;&gt;errors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the errors encountered are during the decompilaton shows up only during the recompiling phase and launching
app phase, hopefully there are extra options during decompilation which can fix most errors encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the following options are available in decompilation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;
when to use -r option,
if launch causes crashes in relation to resources
you can find this out in logcat and try this option
when to use --no-assets option,
the same reason as -r option
when to use -d flag,
debug flag, adds debug to manifest enabling debug output
utilize logcat
when to use customFranework/update framework,
would not build or recompile, so install new framework with
apktool.jar -if framework-file.apk
framework files from android device:
usually inside /system/framework.
adb pull to get the apk then do if framework
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;more-about-frameworks&#34;&gt;more about frameworks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases there may be recompiling and rebuilding errors from apktool,
this can be either fixed by -r param while decompiling(keep resources intact) or by installing latest framework
with the command, multiple frameworks can be used too, or even pull a framework file from your Android device,
more about it here, so if you are using miui like me, use the command below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;
ex:(current device miui)
adb pull /system/framework/framework-res.apk
adb pull /system/framework/framework-ext-res/framework-ext-res.apk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastet framework files can be taken from Android build tools. At the time of writing this Android api 29 is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;the above will fix about 90% of the problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;working-with-practical-example&#34;&gt;working with practical example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install the latest version of spotify lite from playstore and extract the apk from the device and decompile it
using the guide from part 1, solve the problems you face by the above methods. after decompile take some time to
go through the app structure and keep note of key parts of the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;also launch jadx_gui side by side to get a better idea. (you can find this in part 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launch the app on your device and check the app structure (always keep notes on interesting places) for example
(hint) the settings has a section called account type. This practical example wont be simple as changing the
return value of a function like previous post, we has an attack vector specific to that app, but here its a
different story, &lt;em&gt;analysing the app structure and finding potential spots is the key step.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hints&#34;&gt;hints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;smali modifications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
I use this site a lot &lt;a href=&#34;http://pallergabor.uw.hu/androidblog/dalvik_opcodes.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dalvik_opcodes&lt;/a&gt; , as mentioned in
the part 1. Here we want to replace section&amp;rsquo;s of byte code, thus make use of this, here to I wont say the exact-way
to mod since that would be illegal, you can find this out on your own, ill just share the gist of the byte code
necessary to do the trick and show code sample&amp;rsquo;s for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you browse through the decompiled files you might stumble upon a enumerator that is referenced everywhere,
yeah, of course this can be exploited indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Im gona explain with Java code instead of the dalvik opcodes, since that is much more easier to unserstand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
enum Account{
PREMIUM,
FREE
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-trick&#34;&gt;The trick&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the app launches (MainActivity), app makes an api call to get the type of user and save&amp;rsquo;s it as a local reference,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
# sudocode
AnnonymousCall_to_apiToRetreiveUserType(...){
//make the call
//parse the call
return Account (response);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;check the sudocode, if you are able to change the response of the annoymous call to always send use PREMIUM,then we
can call it a day!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Java you use enumerator.valueOf(&amp;ldquo;fname_here&amp;rdquo;) to get the value of the enum. so we change the above code to something like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
# sudocode
AnnonymousCall_to_apiToRetreiveUserType(...){
//make the call EVEN THIS ARE NOT NECESSARY HERE
//parse the call EVEN THIS ARE NOT NECESSARY HERE
return Account.valueOf(&amp;quot;PREMIUM&amp;quot;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;here is the dalvik opcode equivalent for the above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;
//storage
const-string p2, &amp;quot;PREMIUM&amp;quot;
//valueOf from storage
invoke-static {p2}, Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;-&amp;gt;valueOf(Ljava/lang/String;)Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;
//move the result object into p2
move-result-object p2
//move the same into class object
iput-object p2, p0, Ldlc;-&amp;gt;b:Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;
//return the object
return-object Ldlc;-&amp;gt;b:Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;the same but for lambda functins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;original: api_call -&amp;gt; retrun cast(response)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;
.method public final apply(Ljava/lang/Object;)Ljava/lang/Object;
.locals 0
check-cast p1, Lcjl;
invoke-virtual {p1}, Lcjl;-&amp;gt;b()Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;
move-result-object p1
return-object p1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;patched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;
.registers 2
.line 47
const-string p1, &amp;quot;PREMIUM&amp;quot;
invoke-static {p1}, Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;-&amp;gt;valueOf(Ljava/lang/String;)Lcom/spotify/lite/productstate/Product;
move-result-object p1
return-object p1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some additional interesting patch sections, go through this too, latest verisons of the app need this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;
player util
player restriction
resolve player
skipToFutureTrack
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the given patch work, it is all that you will need to enable premium features, just recompile, sign and install the app.
follow part 1 for recompiling, sign and installing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;end&#34;&gt;End&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps some one else other than me, I&amp;rsquo;m not gona share the recompiled apk for obvious reasons(legal), But I feel you should
be able to do so, with the information you have now. peace! seeya next time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Docker to Make Life Easier</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/09/docker-to-make-life-easier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 09:17:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/09/docker-to-make-life-easier/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, it&amp;rsquo;s been two months since last update. Anyway the August month I was pretty busy, to be honest, I was involved in a old project of mine that I had to revist, in order to get more productive and flexibility in developing the application I chose to use docker. So this post is going to be about docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Status Update:The month of August also had something interesting in it, which is my birthday. There was a plan to go a special temple so I took some leave from office, during that time another holiday was also just around the corner, so on the whole I had about 5 days of stay in my house, which is a lot considering I only have a two or three days leave if I had leave my office. This was the first time after a year that I have been staying in home for a long time. During that time I spent some minimal time developing and I found out that I had so much productivity in home then in my chennai room or my office and I was learning new things, so that is that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;will-reference-everything-with-the-assumption-you-are-on-the-linux-platform-too-it-ll-be-only-slightly-different-on-windows&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will reference everything with the assumption you are on the linux platform too, it&amp;rsquo;ll be only slightly different on windows.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro-to-docker&#34;&gt;Intro to docker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend installation with the prebuilt packages from the docker link instead of your flavour&amp;rsquo;s package (debian[ubunut..], arch..).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;
# use the following path while navigating through to get the download links.
pool/dist/package
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(or)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you insist on installing with apt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
# installation with apt / apt-get
sudo apt-get install \
apt-transport-https \
ca-certificates \
curl \
gnupg-agent \
software-properties-common
gpg key:
curl -fsSL https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg | sudo apt-key add -
check fingerprint:
sudo apt-key fingerprint 0EBFCD88
pub rsa4096 2017-02-22 [SCEA]
9DC8 5822 9FC7 DD38 854A E2D8 8D81 803C 0EBF CD88
uid [ unknown] Docker Release (CE deb) &amp;lt;docker@docker.com&amp;gt;
sub rsa4096 2017-02-22 [S]
#choosing stable release for docker:
sudo add-apt-repository \
&amp;quot;deb [arch=amd64] https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu \
$(lsb_release -cs) \
stable&amp;quot;
#installing latest docker from ubuntu.
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install docker-ce docker-ce-cli containerd.io
#deb is even simpler in my openion (example for debian):
sudo dpkg -i /path/to/package.deb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basics&#34;&gt;basics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;the following are true for linux based distros&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To put it simple terms&lt;/em&gt;
Docker is like a virtualMachine except it&amp;rsquo;s not resource hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To not put in simple terms&lt;/em&gt;
Docker shares the same kernel as the host, while VirtualMachine rewrites low-level instructions &amp;amp; executes them on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;image&#34;&gt;image&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;images are like iso images burnt to a cd/usb ready to be installed,
things you can do with it,
* use prebuilt images from market, (both official and user created)
* build an image with customisations on top of an official image form market
* publish the images you are using/ publish images that you built&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;container&#34;&gt;container&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image u have a fresh HardDisk, you installed a OS(operating system) of your liking in it,
what do you have left in it?
Free space after the o-files, which u can use to store anything,
what can you install on the os?
basically any software,
so next time if you take that particular hardDisk will you get, basically above right?
This is what a container is, replace HardDisk with container and os with prebuilt/customImage.
you can attach external HardDrive to it, which in our case is volume, &amp;hellip;etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;basic-commands&#34;&gt;basic commands&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
#list local images/containers
docker image ls
#only running containers
docker container ls
#list all (even turned off containers)
docker contaienr ls -a
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;custom-image-creation-section&#34;&gt;custom image creation section&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some commands to help you(addressig myslef), for custom images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
# dockerfile
FROM &amp;lt;imagename&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;tagfortheimage&amp;gt;
COPY &amp;lt;src&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dest&amp;gt;
WORKDIR further interaction will start from this directory.
EXPOSE port to be exposed.
# installed additioal/required programs from below commands
RUN commands to run
CMD commands to run
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;build the image, filename for the file should be &amp;lsquo;Dockerfile&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
docker-build -f PathToFile -t nameOfTheBuildImage
#ex:
docker build -t phpserver:0.0.2 phpServer/
docker image ls phpserver
REPOSITORY TAG IMAGE ID CREATED SIZE
phpserver 0.0.2 5f7b4c7374b5 About a minute ago 416MB
#another way of representing, httpd/somefeature:tagHere, httpd/somefeature (tag assumed as latest here), user/httpd-imageName:taghere
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;running a image which you built locally or from the official image,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
docker-run -d run-container-in-background -v specify-volume / --mount --mount=&#39;-type=bind,src=path_here,dst=path_here&#39; (path must be absolute --name=&#39;&#39; -p [] (port) -p [] (port)
ex:
docker run -d -p 80:80 --mount=&#39;src=//bluepie.in/home/path/to/folder/,dst=/var/www/html/,type=bind&#39; --name phpserver phpserver:0.0.2
docker ps
CONTAINER ID IMAGE COMMAND CREATED STATUS PORTS NAMES
5f7b4c7374b5 phpserver:0.0.2 &amp;quot;docker-php-entrypoi…&amp;quot; 10 seconds ago Up 9 seconds 0.0.0.0:80-&amp;gt;80/tcp phpserver
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after starting the container, some commands to help you,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
docker-container start name
docker-container stop name
docker-container restart name
docker-container stat
docker-container inspect name
docker-container ls -a
docker-container la
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to interact with running containers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;
#run single instance command
docker-exec -i image command-here params-if-command-has-it
#ex: install php inside a conainer and use it like binary like this
docker run \
--rm \
-i \
--network=host \
-v &amp;quot;$HOME&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;$HOME&amp;quot;:ro \
-u $(id -u) \
-w &amp;quot;$PWD&amp;quot; \
php:7.3-alpine \
php &amp;quot;$@&amp;quot;
#run interactive shell command
docker-exec -it image
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;docker-compose&#34;&gt;docker compose&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wana start a bunch of container&amp;rsquo;s each serving its own purpose,
for eg: one container for running server, another for databse, another for running waf, another for running microService ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;install docker-compose, downlaod the docker-compose binary and include it in your environment variable, and build a docker-compose.yml for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bye-see-ya-soon-sorry-for-missing-out-last-month&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;bye, see ya soon, sorry for missing out last month&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 22:40:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello! me and others reading this from the future. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Status Update:So, this month I have lost a companion that was with me for the past 4 years, he is not entirely dead but let&amp;rsquo;s say is not the same person he once was&amp;hellip;.wait wait wait! I am talking about my laptop. I was doing an all-nighter &amp;amp; I think it was about 4 a.m. or so I was planning to go to sleep, so so while I was cleaning up &amp;amp; I dropped the laptop from my waist height, I was one of the tallest persons in my class so that explains a lot. I should have cleaned everything in the morning. Anyway after that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t work on my projects for sometime, but I fixed it to a point where it is somewhat workable, bit its not the same, I have to buy a new one. Next time when I make a post it will be on a new laptop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been away from reversing, ctf and modding, basically my hobbies from my University days. but occasionally I do some reversing and CTF&amp;rsquo;s, &lt;em&gt;because of course I don&amp;rsquo;t want to forget everything.&lt;/em&gt; I was busy with my office work but in the back of my mind there was always thoughts about reversing apps again usually to find bugs and exploit in myself for fun. That is the GOAL!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivaation&#34;&gt;Motivaation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing that Lead me to writing this post is that I use torrents sometimes and i mostly do it in my phone. Out of all the Torrent clients I used, ttorrent is the best(phone). I use it but not to the point of im going to buy it(the premium app without adds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately ads are just awefull, full-blown full screen ads with full audio and you cannot even skip the video. So in one weekend I decided to reverse it, because at this point you cannot use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;question&#34;&gt;Question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not use mods/cracks from the internet,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;answer: easy, since I&amp;rsquo;m also in the security community I know for a fact that almost every other mod has some Trojan linked with it and the other reason is I am paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;warning-or-notice-whatever-you-want-to-call-it&#34;&gt;WARNING OR NOTICE WHATEVER YOU WANT TO CALL IT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am going to share below is purely for myself to remind me(future me) that at some point in life I did this and is purely for learning purposes for anyone else that might stumbled upon this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;decompiling&#34;&gt;Decompiling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fun-part&#34;&gt;Fun part&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: I have already done this before and I have a personal preference of tools that I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing that you need is the decompiler, at the time of writing this post I have seen around 15 or so decompilers online and offline for android ofcourse personally i have been fan of APK tool its just perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/iBotPeaches/apktool/downloads&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;apktool download link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the Honorable mentions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cfr decompiler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jd-gui&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jadx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apktool-usage&#34;&gt;Apktool usage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;its-simple-apktool-d-for-decompile-o-outputdirectory&#34;&gt;its simple. apktool d(for decompile) -o(outputdirectory)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;
java -jar apktook_2.4.0.jar d -o output_dir/ apkfile.apk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after you decompile the APK. Explore the decompiled folder for some time.
If you want to to change the app flow or know its secrets, you have to to change those files so you need a text editor with find in files feature. My personal preference for this is Sublime course you can use anything you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Android apps are basically written in Java and kotlin from native app standpoint. So the files that you saw in those folders are just the compiled versions of the source. For seeing the source code of apps, you cannot see the exact source code from Java everything will be obfuscated and a lot of it will not make any sense to you if you don&amp;rsquo;t have any experience at first so don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of it. Be very vigilant here I am talking about two things one is the Java source files and the other is the compiled .smali files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;.smali modifications are the most imporatant one, that matters in this post. since that will be used to change the app flow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modding&#34;&gt;Modding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;smali-modifications&#34;&gt;smali modifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the tough spot. I have previous experience with assembly(x86 and dex) but for other people you have to learn to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;viewing-logic-and-instructions&#34;&gt;viewing logic and instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;personally, i use jadx for viewing the java code(obfuscated and confusing) and viewing the smali code at the same time and make changes with text editors on .smali files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skylot/jadx&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jadx link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;for smali modifications to understand the instructions.i&amp;rsquo;ve found this to be useful than the google one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pallergabor.uw.hu/androidblog/dalvik_opcodes.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dalvik_opcodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-structure-and-finding-things-to-be-changed-to-suit-our-needs&#34;&gt;Understanding structure and finding things to be changed to suit our needs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the command form the apktool part, you would have decompiled the apk, with the help of tools provided above you can also now just view the source and hopefully understand the logic. I am going to tell what i changed after analysing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hint: ttorrent lite can be converted to premium if you have a code, that might be exploitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt; .locals 0
.line 1
iput-object p1, p0, Lhu/tagsoft/ttorrent/serial/a;-&amp;gt;c:Lhu/tagsoft/ttorrent/serial/SerialActivity;
iput-boolean p2, p0, Lhu/tagsoft/ttorrent/serial/a;-&amp;gt;a:Z
&amp;gt;.local 0, means no extra variables will be included,
to make conditions true, set variable true,
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;basically-what-u-have-to-do-in-terms-of-java-code-is-below-this-is-one-of-the-common-modding-pattern&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;basically what u have to do in terms of java code is below&lt;/em&gt; this is one of the common modding pattern&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;
public Boolean isLicenseVerified{
this.licenseCheck = getLicenseCheck();
return this.licecseCheck //true if bought the license.
}
public Boolean isLicenseVerified{
this.licenseCheck = true;
return this.licecseCheck //always true.
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;in-smali-code-that-would-translate-to-actual-change-made-in-code&#34;&gt;in smali code that would translate to, actual change made in code.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt; ex:
.local 1 //now one extra variable can be created.
const/4 v0, 0x1
iput-boolean v0, p0, Lhu/tagsoft/ttorrent/serial/a;-&amp;gt;a:Z //the variable was set to true.
!imp calling to check if serial registered, always return true. successful patch!.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: this is not an easy to do at the begining, I was at that point myself so just dont give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recompiling&#34;&gt;Recompiling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that you have to recompile the app, There are several ways to do this, I am gonna go with removing the original signature of the app creating a new key and then signing the app with your key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;removemeta-inf-folder-to-remove-original-signatures&#34;&gt;removemeta inf folder to remove original signatures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;
java -jar apktool b -o outputdir/filename.apk decompiledDirectory/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resigning&#34;&gt;Resigning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;creating-key-and-signing-with-it&#34;&gt;creating key and signing with it&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;
keytool -genkey -v -keystore ck-release-key.keystore -alias ck -keyalg RSA -keysize 2048 -validity 10000
//resign the apk
jarsigner -verbose -sigalg SHA1withRSA -digestalg SHA1 -keystore ck-release-key.keystore my_application.apk ck
//be sure to verify it there might be some errors.
jarsigner -verify -verbose recompiledApk.apk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;there-is-also-another-way-of-disabling-ads-simpler-very-much-simpler-by-disabling-the-activity-from-manifest-but-what-is-the-fun-in-that&#34;&gt;there is also another way of disabling ads simpler(very much simpler) by disabling the activity from manifest but what is the fun in that&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now got rid of the pesky fullScreen ads, I am not gona share the apk here, cuz reasons duh&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;but I taught u the necessary stuff to do so, you should do fine on your own&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Google Ctf 2019</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 18:35:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hey!. future me,(addressing myself)
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Status Update:So its been almost a year since i joined a company and having my career growing, but my personal goals are just at the same position when i left my student life. Gosh wish things where different, So another long time since i made my last post. time really flies by, so the most part im ok i guess with inner conflicts, mental forgetfullness, slow motion, slow thinking. For the past some weeks everything around me feels like it has been sped up, but i am still moving slowly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thing-that-got-me-interested-google-capture-the-flag&#34;&gt;Thing that got me interested - Google Capture the flag.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As i said, i haven&amp;rsquo;t given up all my hobbies, recently i was eager to participate in the capture the flag conducted by google, because i was free during that time cuz that was on a saturday and sunday, (not office hours,). So this post will cover that, i wont be writing everything, since this is ultimately for the sake of me that i am doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenges&#34;&gt;challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Im going to be vague about most of the things, except the ones i felt where challenging and interesitng to me.
so the first challenge was a binary challenge, that was pretty easy a 30 second view and string analysis of the file gave me the flag, &amp;ldquo;CTF{welcome_to_googlectf}&amp;rdquo; it was the beginning after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next part was also a binay involved, but that binary was connecting to the internet to communicat, wireshark can be used for instance but using wireshark for this beginner task is an overkill, what i did was found out the server ip from the binary, connected to the server directly, got the flag, bypassing the protection from the binary,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next part is a two parter, first you have to find the ip address of the server, then after connecting to the server, you have limited access, you do not have any permission what so ever, the flag is there in a file with no permission set to it, but you can access &amp;ldquo;bin/&amp;rdquo; directory with exec permissions to some of the executables, but no exec permissions to busybox binary, with some tweaking and wandering around this round is also simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next round you are presented boot sector ntfs file. the file contains the details to the flag apparently, so we mount the ntfs file, find all the files that are likely to be the flag, apparently all the files are empty with 0 bytes,by filtering the files which are above 1kb, the results shows up as only one, we get a hint that the flag is stored in pic directory on the file&amp;rsquo;s extra attribute section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the next level was an xss injection, that is pretty easy i guess, basically you have to get the admin&amp;rsquo;s cookies and session id to get the flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some of the challenges are very easy so I am not going to cover them, if you know basic reverse engineering and cyber security, you could solve them easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;a challenge that was fresh and I have not seen anything like that challenge before, I am going to write about how I managed to solve that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-challenge-that-was-interesting-to-me&#34;&gt;A challenge that was interesting to me.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so here comes the big thing that took me a lot of time to figure this out, It was a reversing challenge, it consisted of a python program with a file as argument to it, the argument file consist of emojis, python program emulates stack based vm with the smiles as instructions, Im gona walk through how i was able to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source of the program was given, it was just a python program, but it was quite hard to understand what they where doing at first, the link to the files are below, check them out, you have to run them on python3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/vmbackup.py&#34; title=&#34;python Source code&#34;&gt;vmbackup.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/program&#34; title=&#34;python Source code&#34;&gt;program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-problem-with-this&#34;&gt;the problem with this?.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So pretty much it prints a url, letter by letter, but gradually it slows down and at some point it stops, so the algorithm they are using might be the issue here, so when opening the program file you will find smiles inside of it, and the python program uses those smiles one by one as instrcutions and runs them. just like a modern cpu running the binary file. i was twisting my head around replacing smilies to understand the program, i could idenify pattersn but nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little later I tried a different approach, which is print statements, the python progrm is still python right, so made some print statements in different places, then ran the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;where-i-made-the-comments&#34;&gt;where I made the comments.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;
def xor(self):
a = self.stack.pop()
b = self.stack.pop()
print(&amp;quot; xor:: a:&amp;quot; + str(a) +&amp;quot; b:&amp;quot;+ str(b) +&amp;quot;\n&amp;quot;)
self.stack.append(b ^ a)
def print_top(self):
print(self.stack);
sys.stdout.write(chr(self.stack.pop()))
sys.stdout.flush()
def push(self):
if self.rom[self.instruction_pointer] == &#39;🥇&#39;:
self.stack.append(self.accumulator1)
print(&amp;quot;accumulator1 :&amp;quot; + str(self.accumulator1) )
elif self.rom[self.instruction_pointer] == &#39;🥈&#39;:
self.stack.append(self.accumulator2)
print(&amp;quot;accumulator2 :&amp;quot; + str(self.accumulator1) )
else:
raise RuntimeError(&#39;Unknown instruction {} at position {}&#39;.format(
self.rom[self.instruction_pointer], str(self.instruction_pointer)))
self.instruction_pointer += 1
def load(self):
num = 0
if self.rom[self.instruction_pointer] == &#39;🥇&#39;:
acc = 1
elif self.rom[self.instruction_pointer] == &#39;🥈&#39;:
acc = 2
else:
raise RuntimeError(&#39;Unknown instruction {} at position {}&#39;.format(
self.rom[self.instruction_pointer], str(self.instruction_pointer)))
self.instruction_pointer += 1
while self.rom[self.instruction_pointer] != &#39;✋&#39;:
num = num * 10 + (ord(self.rom[self.instruction_pointer][0]) - ord(&#39;0&#39;))
print(&amp;quot;rom: &amp;quot;+str(ord(self.rom[self.instruction_pointer][0])) +&amp;quot; ord:&amp;quot;+ str((ord(self.rom[self.instruction_pointer][0]) - ord(&#39;0&#39;)) ))
self.instruction_pointer += 1
if acc == 1:
self.accumulator1 = num
else:
self.accumulator2 = num
self.instruction_pointer += 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After making the comments things were much clearer to me, all the comments that I made in the above program I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it in one instance and run the program, I made some comments in the program run at and check the weather it make sense and added some more comments and then run it again and again&amp;hellip; I have also attached the log files which was generated from the different runs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/output.txt&#34; title=&#34;run#1&#34;&gt;output.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/outputWithXor.txt&#34; title=&#34;run#2&#34;&gt;outputWithXor.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/outputWithXorWithAccumulator.txt&#34; title=&#34;run#3&#34;&gt;outputWithXorWithAccumulator.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//bluepie.in/attachments/outputWithXorWithRom.txt&#34; title=&#34;run#4&#34;&gt;outputWithXorWithRom.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;solving-thought-process&#34;&gt;solving thought process&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download and check the different log files from above, analysing each of those health individually will give you an idea, well it give me an idea, all the different mechanics in the program were making sense to me now, the accumulator 1, accumulator 2, push instructions, pop instructions, load instructions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see when the program first runs, it just load the bunch of numbers into the memory after that it performs mathematical operations to find prime numbers, on the moment it finds a prime number it performs an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;XOR operation on a number that was initially loaded(a number that is in the top of the stack)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this produces an integer value, this integer value corresponds to an ASCII character.. yeah! integer values are converted to ASCII character and then print out. This is the basis of the URL generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have the encoded URL as numbers in memory, you can easily find this out in the log files that I have attach, so we can easily extract those numbers, find the prime numbers ourselves and then perform xor operation and get the URL, easy right? .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I cooked a a Python program that finds a series of prime numbers and then performs XOR operation. Running that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the URL it was printing random rubbish things. After inspecting closely I found out that the prime numbers or not in a series, are they were using some logic or or some other thing and only using certain prime numbers. This was the part where I was stuck and couldn&amp;rsquo;t get my brain around this. I was literally stuck for 45 minutes and clearly missed out the clue that was in front of me, maybe my office activities made my brain dull.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out that the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;prime numbers are in-fact in series, but the series contained only prime numbers that where palindromic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. So I did some tweaks to my program and then executed it. Vola! I got the URL in an instant, with that URL I solved that challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;solution.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;
# Make sure to run the program in Python 3, I cooked up this program quickly so forgive my bad code,
import operator
toDecode = [17488, 16758, 16599, 16285, 16094, 15505, 15417, 14832, 14450, 13893, 13926, 13437, 12833, 12741, 12533, 11504, 11342, 10503, 10550, 10319, 975, 1007, 892, 893, 660, 743, 267, 344, 264, 339, 208, 216, 242, 172, 74, 49, 119, 113, 119,106]
def checkprime(num):
flag=True
for x in range(3,(int(num/2))+1):
if(num%x==0):
flag=False
return flag
def primeNumberGenerator():
primeNumberArr = [2,3,5,7]
for x in range(10,17488):
if(checkprime(x)):
primeNumberArr.append(x)
return primeNumberArr
def filterPalindromeFromPrime(primeNumberArr):
primePalindrome = []
for x in primeNumberArr:
if (str(x) == str(x)[::-1]):
primePalindrome.append(x)
return primePalindrome
def decode(PrimePalindromeArr):
toDecode.reverse()
url = []
print(&amp;quot;toDecode Count:&amp;quot; +str(len(toDecode)))
print(&amp;quot;PrimePalindromeArr Count:&amp;quot; +str(len(PrimePalindromeArr)))
for index, value in enumerate(toDecode):
character = operator.xor(PrimePalindromeArr[index],value)
print(&amp;quot;palindromeValue:&amp;quot;+str(PrimePalindromeArr[index]))
print(&amp;quot;value:&amp;quot;+str(value))
print(&amp;quot;character:&amp;quot;+chr(character))
url.append(chr(character))
print(&amp;quot;url:&amp;quot;+&amp;quot;&amp;quot;.join(url))
if __name__ == &#39;__main__&#39;:
primeArr = primeNumberGenerator()
PrimePalindromeArr = filterPalindromeFromPrime(primeArr)
decode(PrimePalindromeArr)
# Also forgot to mention there where three batches of toDecode, join them entirely to get the complete URL
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I did manage to solve the challenges, but for the sake of this post I am gonna keep this short, already the post is very huge and it took me so long to write this. I know I am a bad typer(could not type very fast). I promise you that I will post all the challenges that were challenging to me. Bye See ya soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>ModSecurity</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/05/modsecurity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 23:32:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/05/modsecurity/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so hello.. how are you doing..? how is life? im good, thank you!.
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Status Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen better days tbh, i&amp;rsquo;ve faced a lot of challenges this month, im having burnout? wtf! what is that? you ask&amp;rsquo;? just google it.. In the entirety of my life, i never hated computers and programming/ developing in general, but recently i grown a haterd to computers and coding disgusts me.. like WTH? im like the polar opposite of myself, i never thought i would reach this moment in life, funny is&amp;rsquo;nt it? plus i&amp;rsquo;ve been going to my old happits - i blame being human for that.. i can never forget something and get over it can&amp;rsquo;t I.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thankfully for burnout I got people on my back, with their help and advice, i&amp;rsquo;ve been taking breaks but the breaks are not enough, goto go to work?!! i miss old days.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-ve-had-a-chance-to-work-on-modsecurity-and-im-greatfull-for-that-i-gained-a-new-skill-kudos&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to work on modSecurity and im greatfull for that! I gained a new skill! kudos!!.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what is modSec? modSecurity is a waf, waf is like anti virus for servers, controls how the servers responds to requests and what responses are sent out. modSecurity is openSource so using is completely free and it is a must in pci compliance, modSec works based on rules that fine tuned, identified as malicious and are wrote down, the rules are the building blocks of modsecurity. a better rule set equals better protection, this is why you see many vendors who branched out from modSecurity and provide their own set of rules as their enterprise solutions like for example: atomicorp, mlware expert, Trustwave, trend micro, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you want to know about modsecurity you should know a little bit of history of mod security, the rule set history, the latest in the rules of modSecurity is the core rule set 3.0+, before this release, the modSecrity rules create many false positives, but after update some big changes are the new blocking mode, curated rule-set and better detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-is-the-new-blocking-mode&#34;&gt;So what is the new blocking mode?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default the anomaly scoring mode(new blocking mode) is activated, with
&amp;ldquo;SecRuleEngine DetectionOnly&amp;rdquo;, you have to turn this to &amp;ldquo;SecRuleEngine On&amp;rdquo;
to block the malicious requests. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(first of all you install modSecurity, leave the detection phase on, collect some logs - analyse them - tweak the rules - then turn on the secRuleEngine..)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if SecDefaultAction is set to “phase:2,deny,log&amp;rdquo; then modSecurity is working by anomaly scoring mode. next thing you must know about is &amp;ldquo;Anomaly scoring severity levels&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo; Anomaly scoring threshold levels&amp;rdquo; (for blocking mostly)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-it-does&#34;&gt;what it does?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not block the request immediately but allows the request to pass through after assigning a score to the request, if the request any other rules another score is added to it, so there are 5 different levels where the rules are applied to the request, the scores are evaluated at the phase 3 for Inbound rules and 4 for outbound requests, yea you are right modsec scans the output content too and slaps score on it, if it sees something malicious.
the rules are present in the rule-set too as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;SecAction “phase:1,id:’981208’,t:none,nolog,pass,\
setvar:tx.inbound_anomaly_score_level=5”
SecAction “phase:1,id:’981209’,t:none,nolog,pass,\
setvar:tx.outbound_anomaly_score_level=4”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the inbound rules files are present in the file named along the line of &amp;ldquo;inbound_blocking.conf&amp;rdquo; and same as for the outbound request &amp;ldquo;outbound_blocking.conf&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on severity anomaly scoring mode has different levels with scores by default&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;CRITICAL with a score of 5
Error with 4,
warning with 3,
notice with 2,
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note-modsecurity-must-be-tweaked-to-individual-applications-not-just-install-the-default-configuration-infact-the-authors-of-modsecurity-strongly-advice-this-too&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;Note: modSecurity must be tweaked to individual applications, not just install the default configuration, infact the authors of modsecurity strongly advice this too.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-audit-logs-someother-aspects&#34;&gt;About audit logs - SomeOther aspects.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audit logs provide the entire traffic data &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;if &amp;ldquo;logging is enabled that is&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-response-code-is-500-we-are-logging-that&#34;&gt;if response code is 500 we are logging that.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;SecAuditLogRelevantStatus “^(?:5|4(?!04))”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-following-parts-contain-the-necessary-information-for-each-request&#34;&gt;the following parts contain the necessary information for each request.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;SecAuditLogParts ABCEFHZ
• A: Audit log header
• B: Request headers
• C: Request body
• E: Intended response body
• F: Response headers
• H: Audit log trailer
• Z: Audit log footer
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;while-logging-sensitive-data-in-logs&#34;&gt;While logging - Sensitive Data in Logs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful while logging the data, sensitive data are captured in logs too like passwords, creditcard numbers, you dont want that do you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the below log you see credit card number captured in part c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;--8472b290-C--
paymentType=default&amp;amp;_D%3ApaymentType=+&amp;amp;
creditCardNumber=***************&amp;amp;_D%3AcreditCardNumber=+&amp;amp;cid=6802
&amp;amp;_D%3Acid=+&amp;amp;selCreditCardType=Visa&amp;amp;_D%3AselCreditCardType
=+&amp;amp;_D%3AexpirationMonth=+&amp;amp;expirationMon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can mitigate this with a rule like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;SecRule &amp;amp;ARGS:password “@eq 1” “phase:5,t:none,id:’901’,nolog,pass,\
sanitiseInput:pwd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;now in audit log c section,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;--c983684a-C--
log=admin&amp;amp;password=********&amp;amp;submit=Login+%C2%BB&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with the rule applied the password is now obscured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vitual-patching&#34;&gt;vitual Patching&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So ModSecurity has a ton of features you should not miss out is virtual patching, where would you use this you ask? well.. you found a vulnerability in your application and while you wait for the developers to fix that you could do virutual patching with the wide variety of rules available in modSecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The post is getting huge and I find writing blogs tiresome (bad at typing i guess). but i still do it cuz its for the future me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;nt cover everything and i assumed u knew little about modSecurity during halfway, I just couln&amp;rsquo;t type the whole entirety, just contact me if you want to know more&amp;hellip;bye!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>