<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/categories/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 18:35:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.live/blog/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Ctf 2019</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 18:35:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</guid><description>hey!. future me,(addressing myself) Status Update:So its been almost a year since i joined a company and having my career growing, but my personal goals are just at the same position when i left my student life. Gosh wish things where different, So another long time since i made my last post. time really flies by, so the most part im ok i guess with inner conflicts, mental forgetfullness, slow motion, slow thinking.</description></item><item><title>ModSecurity</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/05/modsecurity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 23:32:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/05/modsecurity/</guid><description>so hello.. how are you doing..? how is life? im good, thank you!. Status Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen better days tbh, i&amp;rsquo;ve faced a lot of challenges this month, im having burnout? wtf! what is that? you ask&amp;rsquo;? just google it.. In the entirety of my life, i never hated computers and programming/ developing in general, but recently i grown a haterd to computers and coding disgusts me.. like WTH?</description></item><item><title> ssh tunnel</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/01/ssh-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 06:00:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/01/ssh-tunnel/</guid><description>hey there!
How are you guys doing, hope everyone is doing good, im doing great btw, So today i wana talk about something that i have been using a lot lately in work and personal use, the thing that i wana talk about is ssh tunneling, its a huge topic, i have been using it ever since i learned about ssh in college, So what is this?</description></item></channel></rss>