<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Non tech on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/non-tech/</link><description>Recent content in Non tech on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:23:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/non-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Touch Typing.</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/11/touch-typing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 06:23:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/11/touch-typing/</guid><description>Hi there,
Reality is way different - Update on current things. I know i&amp;rsquo;ve been busy, but i can make up to it. Status update First: The last few weeks,infact the last month is very odd and had a busy schedule. I could&amp;rsquo;nt concentrate on few other projects, Office work took over my life, to be exact!.I&amp;rsquo;ve been the preacher of saying Complete office work early as possible and leave office by 8pm, later spend time for yourself(doing your own thing) like for an example updating blog.</description></item><item><title> Fixing bricked Mobile device</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/06/fixing-bricked-mobile-device/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 01:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/06/fixing-bricked-mobile-device/</guid><description>My friend asked me if i could fix his _(picture attached is the actual device) _old android mobile and i said yeah.. ill try.. then this journey started.
i didnt take notes of the form link..cuz im writing this 2 days after everything happed.
Identifying problem: The problem was that..the phone would not boot up or anything.. wont even go to the recovery mode.. but there is a catch when it is plugged into a charger outlet only the led link will blink.</description></item><item><title>corrupt card..contd</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/06/corrupt-card-contd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 04:15:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/06/corrupt-card-contd/</guid><description>Well how you&amp;rsquo;ll doin.. im gona continue the post that i left some days earlier.. Mind you i might have forgotten.. ill post the updates in the comments as updates..
So i was talking about looking into docs of packages, you need to know that the format of the card was &amp;lsquo;exfat&amp;rsquo;check about exfat.
i was looking into exfat related packages. Experimented with some of the packages and i was going nowhere regarding the card-solving&amp;hellip; then suddenly i landed in github issue tracker.</description></item><item><title> Data Loss - Corrupt card</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/06/data-loss-corrupt-card/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 01:40:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/06/data-loss-corrupt-card/</guid><description>Hye there.. well lets begin as you can guess from the title.. I can assure you that it was completely my fault.. About the sd card its the one that you see in the image, so lets get into more detail shall we..
why?.. you may ask i was experimenting with some stuff relating to sim card tray.. that involved removing and inserting the micro sd card rapidly.</description></item></channel></rss>