<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reversing on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/reversing/</link><description>Recent content in reversing on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:21:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/reversing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Reversing Part 4</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:21:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</guid><description>Hi me!, how are you doing, how is the future holding up?
Personal Update: It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple weeks since the last post, Covid-19 has shown no rate of slowing down. Nothing been around my mind lately just junk&amp;hellip; a lot of junk I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about. To many frequent decisions, Once a friend told me Self control over your thoughts is very important. No matter what I do, It seems I can not achieve it.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 3</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 04:55:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</guid><description>Hi!, Its nice to post weekely for a change, I never posted weekely before, anyway this might be a one time thing(posting weekely).
Disclaimer : Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Let&amp;rsquo;s start &amp;amp; why If you forgot for some reason, this is part-3 of android reversing/modding, I recommend checking out the previous post &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing Part 2&amp;rdquo; in &amp;lsquo;reversing category&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Liunx LD_PRELOAD</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:28:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</guid><description>Hello me, this is going to be a short post that is very interesting to me and I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I have missed this all this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve known to break binary files directly by directly debugging them, mostly the windows files are binary extensions, I have worked even on dll files, which is somewhat similar to .so files on linux, both perform the same functions except that linux part is open source, and i&amp;rsquo;ve seen many articles using this partuclar approrach in many different ways(ofcourse after knowing about this only, I searched for those articles), A bit of personal update - so its been a tough month actually, progress interms of self development is zero, progress in terms of social level is a wip, but still a development.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 19:30:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</guid><description>hey, how ya been. so this is a another reversing post (reverse engineering android mod). So before some months, I gave some basic info to reversing android apps with a practical example(ttorrent). This post is gona build on top of that post. basically pretty advanced version of that post.
Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Starting off Let&amp;rsquo;s just continue where we left off shall we.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 22:40:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</guid><description>Hello! me and others reading this from the future. Status Update:So, this month I have lost a companion that was with me for the past 4 years, he is not entirely dead but let&amp;rsquo;s say is not the same person he once was&amp;hellip;.wait wait wait! I am talking about my laptop. I was doing an all-nighter &amp;amp; I think it was about 4 a.m. or so I was planning to go to sleep, so so while I was cleaning up &amp;amp; I dropped the laptop from my waist height, I was one of the tallest persons in my class so that explains a lot.</description></item></channel></rss>