<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Server on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/server/</link><description>Recent content in Server on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:49:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Set Up Nginx and SSL for My Media Server and Torrent</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/12/how-i-configure-nginx-for-my-server-and-torrent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:49:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/12/how-i-configure-nginx-for-my-server-and-torrent/</guid><description>Context This post is a nginx configurations of my How I replaced Netflix and started using my media server for over 2 years now
config of jellyfin We already run jellyfin inside podman and expose the service on port 8096, so we use nginx to handle requests to domain &amp;lsquo;media.bluepie.in&amp;rsquo;, which connects to jellyfin podman instance.
I point my domain (through domain provider) to the ip address of the server im running my jellyfin instance, then use nginx to serve the requests, the nginx configs are located inside config folders and are included in main file.</description></item><item><title>How I Replaced Netflix and Have Been Using My Media Server for Over 2 Years</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/11/self-hosted-netflix-replacer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/11/self-hosted-netflix-replacer/</guid><description>Feasibility Can I host Netflix on my own? of course yes, many open source software offers similar functionality, you can set it to work only inside your home network or make it available throughout the internet.
I already own a server, I rent out a server for hosting my development activities, so why not use that server as a media server, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to run just inside the home LAN, I want it to be exposed to the internet, of course with required security measures.</description></item><item><title>Updating Dns Servers for Ads and Tracking Protection in 2023</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/01/updating-dns-servers-for-ads-and-tracking-protection-in-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 06:02:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/01/updating-dns-servers-for-ads-and-tracking-protection-in-2023/</guid><description>Upgrading PI hole Once every year, I do server maintainence (during Dec-Jan), this year I updated the our dns server from pi-hole to AGH (both are open source projects..) Just wanted to try an alternative, after using it for a while, the UI &amp;amp; Features on AGH is much better than pi-hole.
Why a custom dns server? All websites/apis are just ip addresses (just numbers). Nameservers maintains a mapping of the domain names to the ip addresses, so when we make a request, we get the appropriate ip address.</description></item><item><title>Custom Dns Server With Adblock</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/custom-dns-server-with-adblock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 14:15:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/custom-dns-server-with-adblock/</guid><description>hello guys, as of writing this post this is christmas of 2019 (25 dec 2019), gosh time really goes fast!. How was the holidays? personal update: I have sevre cold &amp;amp; fever as of writing this, hope i&amp;rsquo;ll get better soon.
Today im going to share my method of adblocking with custom dns servers my requiremets I want adblocking solution without any addons &amp;amp; applications for laptops/desktops/mobile.</description></item></channel></rss>