<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nginx on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/nginx/</link><description>Recent content in nginx on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:49:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/nginx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Set Up Nginx and SSL for My Media Server and Torrent</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/12/how-i-configure-nginx-for-my-server-and-torrent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 20:49:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/12/how-i-configure-nginx-for-my-server-and-torrent/</guid><description>Context This post is a nginx configurations of my How I replaced Netflix and started using my media server for over 2 years now
config of jellyfin We already run jellyfin inside podman and expose the service on port 8096, so we use nginx to handle requests to domain &amp;lsquo;media.bluepie.in&amp;rsquo;, which connects to jellyfin podman instance.
I point my domain (through domain provider) to the ip address of the server im running my jellyfin instance, then use nginx to serve the requests, the nginx configs are located inside config folders and are included in main file.</description></item><item><title>Express Api Server</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/02/express-api-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 10:54:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/02/express-api-server/</guid><description>After a hectic past two months, hope I get some free time in the upcomming months.
What is this? This is a backend, written for one of my projects. This was originally developed to be a private repository, I made it public this month. And this was my first time using typescript 100 percent for backend, my experience with it is pretty cool.
Stack express server mongodb nginx pm manager Framework model view controller Folder structure Name Description src Source files of the server src/public Static files to be used on client side src/models Storing and retrieving datails from different schema, not using mongoose models src/controllers Controllers define functions that respond to various http requests src/server.</description></item></channel></rss>