<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Teach on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/teach/</link><description>Recent content in Teach on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 19:10:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/teach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modding a macOS App</title><link>//bluepie.in/2022/02/modding-a-macos-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 19:10:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2022/02/modding-a-macos-app/</guid><description>Intro This post is about reversing.. but for a MACOS binary. Lets drive straight into it.
Modding in macOS is fairly new to me, but a binary is a binary and it can be modded!. I started to daily drive macOS a month or two ago, the why and what&amp;rsquo;s is a whole different story to post about.
Like I have said previously in my other re posts, &amp;ldquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t trust mods from the internet&amp;rdquo; If I can mod it then its fine, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m paying for it.</description></item><item><title>&#34;F-droid&#34; vs the pain that is &#34;Google PlayStore&#34;</title><link>//bluepie.in/2022/01/publishing-to-fdroid-google-play/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 21:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2022/01/publishing-to-fdroid-google-play/</guid><description>How you doing? hope you are doing well. I missed to post on december because I was juggling too much things at once and needed a break
Fdroid? Fdroid is a free and open source Android application repository. You can use Fdroid via the F-Droid client or the F-Droid website. It is similar to the Google Play Store, but with a few key differences:
is free and open source contains only open source applications is not a commercial service all google play dependencies are stripped out when publishing goes through a series of automated tests &amp;amp; manual reviews before being accepted How do I add a new app to Fdroid?</description></item><item><title>Accuradio, Spotify...etc Adblocker in Kotlin</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/11/accuradio-spotify-adblocker-in-kotlin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/11/accuradio-spotify-adblocker-in-kotlin/</guid><description>Hello how you been?, hope everything is going well.
I wanted to learn Kotlin for native Android development, I already knew how to do it with java, so the only obstacle for me is learning Kotlin.
Kotlin Kotlin trello board that I used to track progress. After learning the basics for Kotlin, Kotlin koans is a great place for practice (beginner to advanced). Chosing what to do with Kotlin I use Accuradio android app to stream music, but it does not have a paid tear, So the ads are not skippable and there was no existing adblocker that does this(which is a pain).</description></item><item><title>Why I Choose Typescript</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/10/why-i-choose-typescript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 21:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/10/why-i-choose-typescript/</guid><description>Hello, we meet again!, how was the week? hope you are well and gud!, This post will be about typescript, I&amp;rsquo;m not explaining what it is, but rather why i choose to use it.
TypeScript was everywhere - background First of all, I want to clear some air by opening up, In in past, I hated typescript with a passion, Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve grown a lot as a person, lol.</description></item><item><title>Rinku</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/07/rinku/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 19:22:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/07/rinku/</guid><description>Hi! hope you are doing well future me!,
I&amp;rsquo;m well in the comfort of my home, the pandemic isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet, the cases are increasing day by day, infact today, as I am wiriting this, newly infected patients is over 6.5k. The past few weeks has been productive, I&amp;rsquo;m loving what I am doing, learning new stuff, doing a little of reversing at times, Oh snap, I forgot, my harddisk died on me, it was not fun(thank god important stuff were already on a server backed up), had to replace that with an ssd.</description></item><item><title>Custom Dns Server With Adblock</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/custom-dns-server-with-adblock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 14:15:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/custom-dns-server-with-adblock/</guid><description>hello guys, as of writing this post this is christmas of 2019 (25 dec 2019), gosh time really goes fast!. How was the holidays? personal update: I have sevre cold &amp;amp; fever as of writing this, hope i&amp;rsquo;ll get better soon.
Today im going to share my method of adblocking with custom dns servers my requiremets I want adblocking solution without any addons &amp;amp; applications for laptops/desktops/mobile.</description></item></channel></rss>