<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</title>
    <link>//bluepie.live/blog/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bluepie.live/blog/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Service Binders</title>
      <link>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/04/android-service-binders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/04/android-service-binders/</guid>
      <description>hola amigos&amp;rsquo;, how are you guys doing? im fine thank you!. Status Update: About last week, I have covered some ground interms of development in old passion projects, the start of the week was great, but at the end of the week it got worse, nevertheless im happy that i survived this week &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;. Saw avengers end game the other day which was cool, during part-I I was studying, but for part-II -an adult going to office (feels wierd even to think, So much change in just one year), Personally nothing great happened, because of the mind that i have, I had the same bs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A peek into my yunger self.		</title>
      <link>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 14:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey guys how y&amp;rsquo;all been,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve been good, in fact i am happy after a long time, So im gona love talking about this, so here is the thing before like 7-8 months (before i got my job) i was fully involved in reverse engineering, modding mostly windows, but also old linux machines with security flaws to train for some capture the flags and the plain curisity of &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> file Manager contd..		</title>
      <link>//bluepie.live/blog/2018/10/file-manager-contd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 20:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2018/10/file-manager-contd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;a little update: Though i made a promise to post every two weeks, its been 4 weeks, why? ..is this&amp;hellip; i was going in a flow, but things started affecting.. rather i let things affect me, lately lot of things happened personally, lot of things reminded of the past, that made me avoid _________ in the present,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuation&#34;&gt;Continuation.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick up where i left off from previous post: Let me explain the way of approach i wanted to do, i wanted to access all the files of the server, like i wanted to go back to the root directory, back before that,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> file manager development		</title>
      <link>//bluepie.live/blog/2018/10/file-manager-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 19:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2018/10/file-manager-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;why this all of a sudden? I was introduced to php development for a little while now, and i had this in mind with several other things, this would also be a good point to start explaining with code, So where to start. let us define? It starts with what is the requirement? It is&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>