<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/categories/android/</link><description>Recent content in android on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.live/blog/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Service Binders</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/04/android-service-binders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2019/04/android-service-binders/</guid><description>hola amigos&amp;rsquo;, how are you guys doing? im fine thank you!. Status Update: About last week, I have covered some ground interms of development in old passion projects, the start of the week was great, but at the end of the week it got worse, nevertheless im happy that i survived this week &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;. Saw avengers end game the other day which was cool, during part-I I was studying, but for part-II -an adult going to office (feels wierd even to think, So much change in just one year), Personally nothing great happened, because of the mind that i have, I had the same bs.</description></item><item><title>About android services</title><link>//bluepie.live/blog/2018/07/about-android-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.live/blog/2018/07/about-android-services/</guid><description>Recently i was involved in android dev..So im gona share a short struggle in android services.
Why So i was targeting android 5.1 and the basic feature was setting up and do some action for every % minutes, so this varies.. below 6.0 everything was fine and was working flawlessly but i was testing it on a mobile with android 6.1.
Doze Since the new android versions comes with android doze enabled, and every manufacturer has their own implementation of doze enabled with custom implementations starting from android 6.</description></item></channel></rss>