<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/android/</link><description>Recent content in android on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:11:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unlimited Photos Storage Without Root - Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/01/unlimited-photos-storage-without-root/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 18:11:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/01/unlimited-photos-storage-without-root/</guid><description>Overview This post is a continuation of my Rooting My Pixel. Over the past months, I’ve been using my rooted phone to bypass storage limits and enjoy unlimited Google Photos storage. However, using a rooted device isn’t without its challenges—if someone gains physical access to my phone, my data becomes vulnerable. Banking appsa and even general purpose applications refuse to run on rooted devices because they detect system tampering. In some cases, the Play Store won’t allow you to install certain apps at all.</description></item><item><title>Rooting My Pixel For Unlimited gphotos backup</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/04/rooting-my-pixel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 03:14:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/04/rooting-my-pixel/</guid><description>All the previous android phones I had, I rooted them and used them with a custom ROM that had gphotos mod or used it with gphotos mod, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a pixel for android development as my second device..but all this time, it had stock android and not rooted with no modifications.
But what do I mean by gphotos mod..? You get unlimited photos and videos backup in Google photos, the mod makes it seem like you&amp;rsquo;re using a pixel device.</description></item><item><title>Android CI on Github</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/03/android-ci/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:08:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/03/android-ci/</guid><description>Been busy, its not like I lost interest in posting here, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t allocate time for writing here, which is the opposite of what I set out to do.. which in turn does not track my progress at all, I should be held accountable for my progress. ~pff I hate it.
A friend told me in the time that I did not post, not necessarily everything should be a progress, maybe this is right or maybe wrong.</description></item><item><title>Accuradio, Spotify...etc Adblocker in Kotlin</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/11/accuradio-spotify-adblocker-in-kotlin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/11/accuradio-spotify-adblocker-in-kotlin/</guid><description>Hello how you been?, hope everything is going well.
I wanted to learn Kotlin for native Android development, I already knew how to do it with java, so the only obstacle for me is learning Kotlin.
Kotlin Kotlin trello board that I used to track progress. After learning the basics for Kotlin, Kotlin koans is a great place for practice (beginner to advanced). Chosing what to do with Kotlin I use Accuradio android app to stream music, but it does not have a paid tear, So the ads are not skippable and there was no existing adblocker that does this(which is a pain).</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 5 But With Frida</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/08/android-reversing-part-5-with-frida/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 07:25:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/08/android-reversing-part-5-with-frida/</guid><description>Why Frida? Becase it can be many things, know more. Its is,
easy, sure learning curve takes some time, but it pays off spectacularly. efficient, a rough estimate for the modification took 30 min in frida vs 2 hours in traditional methods, its way more flexible. elegant when compared to traditional ways. you get creative new ideas and implement them easily (implementating manually takes way longer). My setup Genymotion, but why?</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 5</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/07/android-reversing-part-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 15:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/07/android-reversing-part-5/</guid><description>Contents Why &amp;amp; Motivation Decompiling Finding where to patch Patching, recompiling and installing it on device App&amp;rsquo;s premium features does not work fully Finding integrity checks, digging deeper for final patch. End Why &amp;amp; Motivation I wanted to monitor my mobile network traffic after I found some wierd dns logs in my custom dns server, I could not figure out which app made that request thus I found out this app in playstore called &amp;lsquo;No Root Firewall, Internet Data Blocker Protection&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 4</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:21:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</guid><description>Hi me!, how are you doing, how is the future holding up?
Personal Update: It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple weeks since the last post, Covid-19 has shown no rate of slowing down. Nothing been around my mind lately just junk&amp;hellip; a lot of junk I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about. To many frequent decisions, Once a friend told me Self control over your thoughts is very important. No matter what I do, It seems I can not achieve it.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 3</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 04:55:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</guid><description>Hi!, Its nice to post weekely for a change, I never posted weekely before, anyway this might be a one time thing(posting weekely).
Disclaimer : Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Let&amp;rsquo;s start &amp;amp; why If you forgot for some reason, this is part-3 of android reversing/modding, I recommend checking out the previous post &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing Part 2&amp;rdquo; in &amp;lsquo;reversing category&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 19:30:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</guid><description>hey, how ya been. so this is a another reversing post (reverse engineering android mod). So before some months, I gave some basic info to reversing android apps with a practical example(ttorrent). This post is gona build on top of that post. basically pretty advanced version of that post.
Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Starting off Let&amp;rsquo;s just continue where we left off shall we.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 22:40:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</guid><description>Hello! me and others reading this from the future. Status Update:So, this month I have lost a companion that was with me for the past 4 years, he is not entirely dead but let&amp;rsquo;s say is not the same person he once was&amp;hellip;.wait wait wait! I am talking about my laptop. I was doing an all-nighter &amp;amp; I think it was about 4 a.m. or so I was planning to go to sleep, so so while I was cleaning up &amp;amp; I dropped the laptop from my waist height, I was one of the tallest persons in my class so that explains a lot.</description></item><item><title>Android Service Binders</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/04/android-service-binders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/04/android-service-binders/</guid><description>hola amigos&amp;rsquo;, how are you guys doing? im fine thank you!. Status Update: About last week, I have covered some ground interms of development in old passion projects, the start of the week was great, but at the end of the week it got worse, nevertheless im happy that i survived this week &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;. Saw avengers end game the other day which was cool, during part-I I was studying, but for part-II -an adult going to office (feels wierd even to think, So much change in just one year), Personally nothing great happened, because of the mind that i have, I had the same bs.</description></item><item><title>About android services</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/about-android-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/about-android-services/</guid><description>Recently i was involved in android dev..So im gona share a short struggle in android services.
Why So i was targeting android 5.1 and the basic feature was setting up and do some action for every % minutes, so this varies.. below 6.0 everything was fine and was working flawlessly but i was testing it on a mobile with android 6.1.
Doze Since the new android versions comes with android doze enabled, and every manufacturer has their own implementation of doze enabled with custom implementations starting from android 6.</description></item></channel></rss>