<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chrome Extension on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/chrome-extension/</link><description>Recent content in Chrome Extension on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 21:22:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/chrome-extension/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MVP vs SLC - Fixing Duplicate Tabs</title><link>//bluepie.in/2025/05/fixing-duplicate-tabs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 21:22:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2025/05/fixing-duplicate-tabs/</guid><description>Intro I’ve been running into duplicate-tab problems across both my personal and office browsers. I needed a simple application that can detect duplicates and show a minimal UI to merge, close, or keep them.
MVP vs SLC I’ve followed the MVP approach for years, but this time I went with SLC: Simple, Lovable, Complete. Rather than shipping a bare-bones, bug-ridden MVP, I wanted something small and meaningful that people genuinely love—and that feels complete out of the box.</description></item><item><title>Creating and Publishing Chrome Extension in Chrome Store</title><link>//bluepie.in/2024/01/creating-and-publishing-chrome-extension-in-chrome-store/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 14:31:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2024/01/creating-and-publishing-chrome-extension-in-chrome-store/</guid><description>Why &amp;amp; Motivation Wanted an adblocker for accuradio website, I just need to silence the ads on this website. How can it be done? Custom script that get injected into the page by some extensions such as tamper monkey, the disadvantage is u gotta install tamper monkey. The other idea I have in my brain is I Wanted to try out chrome extesnion that specifically does this job, since my current work needs me work on chrome extensions.</description></item></channel></rss>