<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Bluepie&#39;s Journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I replaced Netflix and using my media server for over 2 years now</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/11/self-hosted-netflix-replacer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/11/self-hosted-netflix-replacer/</guid><description>Feasibility Can I host Netflix on my own? of course yes, many open source software offers similar functionality, you can set it to work only inside your home network or make it available throughout the internet.
I already own a server, I rent out a server for hosting my development activities, so why not use that server as a media server, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to run just inside the home LAN, I want it to be exposed to the internet, of course with required security measures.</description></item><item><title>Overcoming a limitation in Electron</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/09/electron-views/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 06:03:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/09/electron-views/</guid><description>Hey, what&amp;rsquo;s going on with you, hopefully good things, a small personal update, I think I lost focus on my goals for almost a 1.6 years, right after I joined vz, maybe its beause this is the first ime I ever switched my official day time job, wtf, time..time..time it moves soo fast, nowadays literally everthing takes soo much time in this attention seeking nightmare.. wtf, you can not even ignore most of the things, otherwise you will be an outcast, Something happened and it gave me a wakeup call on why I wanted my life goals on the first place, then I realized, &amp;ldquo;you are the person shaped by your memories, at least your behaviour should reflect it&amp;rdquo;, because If I still had my old memories and experiences I would have not changed courses?</description></item><item><title>Android CI on Github</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/03/android-ci/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:08:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/03/android-ci/</guid><description>Been busy, its not like I lost interest in posting here, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t allocate time for writing here, which is the opposite of what I set out to do.. which in turn does not track my progress at all, I should be held accountable for my progress. ~pff I hate it.
A friend told me in the time that I did not post, not necessarily everything should be a progress, maybe this is right or maybe wrong.</description></item><item><title>Updating Dns Servers for Ads and Tracking Protection in 2023</title><link>//bluepie.in/2023/01/updating-dns-servers-for-ads-and-tracking-protection-in-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 06:02:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2023/01/updating-dns-servers-for-ads-and-tracking-protection-in-2023/</guid><description>Upgrading PI hole Once every year, I do server maintainence (during Dec-Jan), this year I updated the our dns server from pi-hole to AGH (both are open source projects..) Just wanted to try an alternative, after using it for a while, the UI &amp;amp; Features on AGH is much better than pi-hole.
Why a custom dns server? All websites/apis are just ip addresses (just numbers). Nameservers maintains a mapping of the domain names to the ip addresses, so when we make a request, we get the appropriate ip address.</description></item><item><title>Modding a macOS App</title><link>//bluepie.in/2022/02/modding-a-macos-app/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 19:10:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2022/02/modding-a-macos-app/</guid><description>Intro This post is about reversing.. but for a MACOS binary. Lets drive straight into it.
Modding in macOS is fairly new to me, but a binary is a binary and it can be modded!. I started to daily drive macOS a month or two ago, the why and what&amp;rsquo;s is a whole different story to post about.
Like I have said previously in my other re posts, &amp;ldquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t trust mods from the internet&amp;rdquo; If I can mod it then its fine, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;m paying for it.</description></item><item><title>&#34;F-droid&#34; vs the pain that is &#34;Google PlayStore&#34;</title><link>//bluepie.in/2022/01/publishing-to-fdroid-google-play/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 21:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2022/01/publishing-to-fdroid-google-play/</guid><description>How you doing? hope you are doing well. I missed to post on december because I was juggling too much things at once and needed a break
Fdroid? Fdroid is a free and open source Android application repository. You can use Fdroid via the F-Droid client or the F-Droid website. It is similar to the Google Play Store, but with a few key differences:
is free and open source contains only open source applications is not a commercial service all google play dependencies are stripped out when publishing goes through a series of automated tests &amp;amp; manual reviews before being accepted How do I add a new app to Fdroid?</description></item><item><title>Open Source Dnd Email Editor</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/10/open-source-dnd-email-editor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 10:48:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/10/open-source-dnd-email-editor/</guid><description>I created a drag and drop email editor, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on it for the past month. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun to work on, I completed it for first release, I&amp;rsquo;ll shed some light on the challenges I faced and how I solved them.
Why&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; What&amp;rsquo;s why build this?
No free editors/open source editors that does the job,
but why not profit?
Not interested, I believe in Open Source.</description></item><item><title>Html to React</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/09/html-to-react/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 10:22:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/09/html-to-react/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing new development in my offtime and i&amp;rsquo;m totally enjoying the challenges and hurdles. I wanted to share an interesting problem that I solved, it is a small part on a project that is not public yet (as of 2021 SEP).
Problem I have a htmlString that I have to convert to react elements.
but why?&amp;hellip; the main reasons were
I have a react wrapper, that enhances the dom-elements.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 5 But With Frida</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/08/android-reversing-part-5-with-frida/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 07:25:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/08/android-reversing-part-5-with-frida/</guid><description>Why Frida? Becase it can be many things, know more. Its is,
easy, sure learning curve takes some time, but it pays off spectacularly. efficient, a rough estimate for the modification took 30 min in frida vs 2 hours in traditional methods, its way more flexible. elegant when compared to traditional ways. you get creative new ideas and implement them easily (implementating manually takes way longer). My setup Genymotion, but why?</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 5</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/07/android-reversing-part-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 15:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/07/android-reversing-part-5/</guid><description>Contents Why &amp;amp; Motivation Decompiling Finding where to patch Patching, recompiling and installing it on device App&amp;rsquo;s premium features does not work fully Finding integrity checks, digging deeper for final patch. End Why &amp;amp; Motivation I wanted to monitor my mobile network traffic after I found some wierd dns logs in my custom dns server, I could not figure out which app made that request thus I found out this app in playstore called &amp;lsquo;No Root Firewall, Internet Data Blocker Protection&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Frontend Updates &amp; Rinku Project Upgrade</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/05/react-updates-rinku-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 20:21:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/05/react-updates-rinku-upgrade/</guid><description>Hi!, Like I mentioned in my last update, I took a break from everything ( a month and 3 weeks), the reason behind me missing my post on past month(april). I still had to do office work though, but its&amp;rsquo; alright because it was fun. The time off that I took was the best decision in a while, It helped me rethink priorities.
Like I said in march post 2021, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting with new Time management in mind.</description></item><item><title>Firebase-RealtimeDatabase &amp; Self-assesment</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/03/firebase-realtimedatabase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 19:08:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/03/firebase-realtimedatabase/</guid><description>Hi!, its been a wild month, jumping all over the places, future me reading!, keep your composure. Coming to other things, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing work from home for the past year, but recently (the past 3 months) I was asked to come office atleast a week or two. Although some of my friends are still doing WFM, I had to go chennai, Which I felt was bad, but this is not a major consern.</description></item><item><title>Express Api Server</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/02/express-api-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 10:54:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/02/express-api-server/</guid><description>After a hectic past two months, hope I get some free time in the upcomming months.
What is this? This is a backend, written for one of my projects. This was originally developed to be a private repository, I made it public this month. And this was my first time using typescript 100 percent for backend, my experience with it is pretty cool.
Stack express server mongodb nginx pm manager Framework model view controller Folder structure Name Description src Source files of the server src/public Static files to be used on client side src/models Storing and retrieving datails from different schema, not using mongoose models src/controllers Controllers define functions that respond to various http requests src/server.</description></item><item><title>Preconfigured Binary and Installer script through Docker</title><link>//bluepie.in/2021/01/preconfigured-binary-using-docker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 08:23:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2021/01/preconfigured-binary-using-docker/</guid><description>How&amp;rsquo;s it going, good I hope!, Hope this year is a blast for you.
What is this? Creating a preconfigured container for a precompiled binary utilizing docker.
Reason / Motivation: I&amp;rsquo;ve been using hugo, even since my blog migration post, the one problem that I am facing with hugo is that,
whenever I run update os host system,hugo version also updates, the problem with that is some features are deprecated in the new release, my site design depends upon those features.</description></item><item><title>AdventOfCode-2020</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/12/adventofcode-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 23:02:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/12/adventofcode-2020/</guid><description>This month was quite interesting, I stopped all developemt (except office work, which is still sad, imo I should have taken a break from that too) and focused my attention towards coding challenges, by newyear have to go chennai for resuming my work life, the timing for it was the worst.
what is advent of code? AOC is a series of programming challenges, two problems unlock each day, till christmas, i.</description></item><item><title>Publishing Npm Package</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/11/publishing-npm-package/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 11:47:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/11/publishing-npm-package/</guid><description>Personal Update: I finally managed to change my github username with all its dependencies to aghontpi, it was less work than I expected. Gosh, Its been 6 months already..since I decided to change my username. Incase my future self is wondering, its still work from home, probablly will go chennai after new years&amp;rsquo; i.e 2021.
This month was boring as hell in terms of office work, since I had to work on Extjs, I introduced some flare into it, but making it similar to react, because of this, it much easier to work on.</description></item><item><title>Gatsby Experiment</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/09/gatsby-experiment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 22:26:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/09/gatsby-experiment/</guid><description>Hi, how did the day go?, what about the week? what about the month?, Good I hope!. Personal update: I almost bought a guitar, But then I realised something and stopped, the decision correct or wrong? the future holds the truth, hope you got the answer with you! future me reading this.
Pew!&amp;hellip; I almost did not post this month, although I completed the project/experiment in the middle of the month.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 4</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:21:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</guid><description>Hi me!, how are you doing, how is the future holding up?
Personal Update: It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple weeks since the last post, Covid-19 has shown no rate of slowing down. Nothing been around my mind lately just junk&amp;hellip; a lot of junk I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about. To many frequent decisions, Once a friend told me Self control over your thoughts is very important. No matter what I do, It seems I can not achieve it.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 3</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 04:55:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</guid><description>Hi!, Its nice to post weekely for a change, I never posted weekely before, anyway this might be a one time thing(posting weekely).
Disclaimer : Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Let&amp;rsquo;s start &amp;amp; why If you forgot for some reason, this is part-3 of android reversing/modding, I recommend checking out the previous post &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing Part 2&amp;rdquo; in &amp;lsquo;reversing category&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Github Workflow</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/github-workflow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 23:32:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/github-workflow/</guid><description>Hi&amp;hellip; how ya been, its been a month already, gosh times flies by really fast. Status update: I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing good, When I am in home I complete the work that I plan&amp;hellip; far better than when I am in Chennai. The corona virus pandemic is still around the world at large, US right now is the largest affected country with over 70k dead people as of writing this. The lockdown in India has been extended another 2 weeks.</description></item><item><title>Xkcd Declutter</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/04/xkcd-declutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:43:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/04/xkcd-declutter/</guid><description>Hi, how are you doing Im doing good, the corona virus pandemic is everywhere! hope your survived the ordeal, its still going on as of writing this, Hope you survive this.. In my childhood after watching movies like &amp;lsquo;i am legend&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp; &amp;lsquo;the day that the earth stood still&amp;rsquo;, i always wanted to see the world in the situtation, oh booy, i did not expect them to happen irl, but it did anyway.</description></item><item><title>Liunx LD_PRELOAD</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:28:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</guid><description>Hello me, this is going to be a short post that is very interesting to me and I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I have missed this all this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve known to break binary files directly by directly debugging them, mostly the windows files are binary extensions, I have worked even on dll files, which is somewhat similar to .so files on linux, both perform the same functions except that linux part is open source, and i&amp;rsquo;ve seen many articles using this partuclar approrach in many different ways(ofcourse after knowing about this only, I searched for those articles), A bit of personal update - so its been a tough month actually, progress interms of self development is zero, progress in terms of social level is a wip, but still a development.</description></item><item><title>Game Dev</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/11/game-dev/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 11:46:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/11/game-dev/</guid><description>Hey!, hope you are doing well!, im good, This post should have gone up in the month of august and this post should have been a follow-up, anyway never too late. Update: Im following a tight schedule for the past few weeks, tight-schedule in the sense &amp;ldquo;wake-up -&amp;gt; commute-to-office -&amp;gt; professional code-&amp;gt; aftier-office -&amp;gt; passion code -&amp;gt; sleep&amp;rdquo; throw in breaks, travel, and Personal hygene time in there, at-first it was awful, but after some while got the hang of it,Infact it became like addiction to me at this point &amp;amp; im craving for more.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 19:30:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</guid><description>hey, how ya been. so this is a another reversing post (reverse engineering android mod). So before some months, I gave some basic info to reversing android apps with a practical example(ttorrent). This post is gona build on top of that post. basically pretty advanced version of that post.
Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Starting off Let&amp;rsquo;s just continue where we left off shall we.</description></item><item><title>Docker to Make Life Easier</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/09/docker-to-make-life-easier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 09:17:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/09/docker-to-make-life-easier/</guid><description>Hello, it&amp;rsquo;s been two months since last update. Anyway the August month I was pretty busy, to be honest, I was involved in a old project of mine that I had to revist, in order to get more productive and flexibility in developing the application I chose to use docker. So this post is going to be about docker.
Status Update:The month of August also had something interesting in it, which is my birthday.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 22:40:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</guid><description>Hello! me and others reading this from the future. Status Update:So, this month I have lost a companion that was with me for the past 4 years, he is not entirely dead but let&amp;rsquo;s say is not the same person he once was&amp;hellip;.wait wait wait! I am talking about my laptop. I was doing an all-nighter &amp;amp; I think it was about 4 a.m. or so I was planning to go to sleep, so so while I was cleaning up &amp;amp; I dropped the laptop from my waist height, I was one of the tallest persons in my class so that explains a lot.</description></item><item><title>Google Ctf 2019</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 18:35:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</guid><description>hey!. future me,(addressing myself) Status Update:So its been almost a year since i joined a company and having my career growing, but my personal goals are just at the same position when i left my student life. Gosh wish things where different, So another long time since i made my last post. time really flies by, so the most part im ok i guess with inner conflicts, mental forgetfullness, slow motion, slow thinking.</description></item><item><title>ModSecurity</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/05/modsecurity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 23:32:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/05/modsecurity/</guid><description>so hello.. how are you doing..? how is life? im good, thank you!. Status Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen better days tbh, i&amp;rsquo;ve faced a lot of challenges this month, im having burnout? wtf! what is that? you ask&amp;rsquo;? just google it.. In the entirety of my life, i never hated computers and programming/ developing in general, but recently i grown a haterd to computers and coding disgusts me.. like WTH?</description></item><item><title>Android Service Binders</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/04/android-service-binders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/04/android-service-binders/</guid><description>hola amigos&amp;rsquo;, how are you guys doing? im fine thank you!. Status Update: About last week, I have covered some ground interms of development in old passion projects, the start of the week was great, but at the end of the week it got worse, nevertheless im happy that i survived this week &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;. Saw avengers end game the other day which was cool, during part-I I was studying, but for part-II -an adult going to office (feels wierd even to think, So much change in just one year), Personally nothing great happened, because of the mind that i have, I had the same bs.</description></item><item><title>Blog Migration</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/04/blog-migration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 03:02:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/04/blog-migration/</guid><description>heya!, this wont be a rant..trust me!, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I lost my cool in the last few posts, well thats aside, let me begin.
migration so i have been planning to migrate my blog from aws to replace it with jekyll, hexo,..etc, The main reason being, i run my blog in php and thus intend to replace it with the mentioned above, The another this that I keep pondering over and over is that, if i abandon my aws blog, I have to convert my previous post from the blog to the new version, reformat, reupload the images as well.</description></item><item><title>C# - A peek into my yunger self.</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</guid><description>Hey guys how y&amp;rsquo;all been,
i&amp;rsquo;ve been good, in fact i am happy after a long time, So im gona love talking about this, so here is the thing before like 7-8 months (before i got my job) i was fully involved in reverse engineering, modding mostly windows, but also old linux machines with security flaws to train for some capture the flags and the plain curisity of&amp;hellip; lets say how to break stuff.</description></item><item><title> AI - with algorithms.(Rant mostly)</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/03/ai-with-algorithms-rant-mostly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:27:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/03/ai-with-algorithms-rant-mostly/</guid><description>Well hello guys! How yr&amp;rsquo; been.
what is going on. i have never thought of me doing this in my life, but this situation has come, so in the past month i have been trying to post and update whats been going on. But i am unable to complete what i started and it is bothering me still now, after that happened i stumbled upon an another old project of mine, which i cleaned up and finished it in a short span and btw this is the project that i am talking about that i didn&amp;rsquo;t complete.</description></item><item><title> ssh tunnel</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/01/ssh-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 06:00:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/01/ssh-tunnel/</guid><description>hey there!
How are you guys doing, hope everyone is doing good, im doing great btw, So today i wana talk about something that i have been using a lot lately in work and personal use, the thing that i wana talk about is ssh tunneling, its a huge topic, i have been using it ever since i learned about ssh in college, So what is this?</description></item><item><title> file Manager contd..</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-contd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 20:56:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-contd/</guid><description>a little update: Though i made a promise to post every two weeks, its been 4 weeks, why? ..is this&amp;hellip; i was going in a flow, but things started affecting.. rather i let things affect me, lately lot of things happened personally, lot of things reminded of the past, that made me avoid _________ in the present,
Continuation. Pick up where i left off from previous post: Let me explain the way of approach i wanted to do, i wanted to access all the files of the server, like i wanted to go back to the root directory, back before that, basically anywhere where i wanted, So DirectoryIterator seemed the best choice, We are in a directory, we have to list all the files and folders in the directory, how would you do that?</description></item><item><title> file manager development</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 19:21:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-development/</guid><description>why this all of a sudden? I was introduced to php development for a little while now, and i had this in mind with several other things, this would also be a good point to start explaining with code, So where to start. let us define? It starts with what is the requirement? It is
I want to view files in the server, I can traverse through the files with forward and backward traversing, i can see the file modification date I can see the file ownership information, I can see file icons and folder icons.</description></item><item><title> MVC pattern</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/09/mvc-pattern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 01:18:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/09/mvc-pattern/</guid><description>Dear Internet I didn&amp;rsquo;t blog for 2 weeks and it feels weird. i promise to write within every two weeks from here on now&amp;hellip; i am terribly sorry!.This post is to clear up the silence that stagnated over the past 2 weeks. sry btw.
Today I would like to share a thing (to tell my future self) that I learned in the recent weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s MVC. I was introduced to MVC pattern for developing applications.</description></item><item><title> Tamper Monkey</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/08/tamper-monkey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:04:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/08/tamper-monkey/</guid><description>Hi again, Today I am going to share something that is somewhat related to reverse engineering. Well I was working on a project, at one point of time I was working on wireframes, since I was only doing the initial design and it would be just used as a reference by the design team so my senior adviced me to use mockup.
Mockup So what is mockup you ask?</description></item><item><title> Software engineering and backend design</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/08/software-engineering-and-backend-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 21:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/08/software-engineering-and-backend-design/</guid><description>Today I wanna share something that I found was very useful in the recent times, which is ofcourse software engineering and backend design When I started developing.. at first I was a noob &amp;lsquo;as people would call&amp;rsquo; I would do random sh**&amp;hellip; I can explain this in more detail.. which is I would go straight to coding, learning the concepts that I need to implement a certain feature.. sometimes I would chase a particular feature first for the first day.</description></item><item><title>About android services</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/about-android-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/about-android-services/</guid><description>Recently i was involved in android dev..So im gona share a short struggle in android services.
Why So i was targeting android 5.1 and the basic feature was setting up and do some action for every % minutes, so this varies.. below 6.0 everything was fine and was working flawlessly but i was testing it on a mobile with android 6.1.
Doze Since the new android versions comes with android doze enabled, and every manufacturer has their own implementation of doze enabled with custom implementations starting from android 6.</description></item><item><title> Php Contd..</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/php-contd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:48:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/php-contd/</guid><description>As i mentioned in the previous post.. i choose php and ignored rest of them because i wanted to do a project in php for a long time and i choose to use this as an opportunity.
So i&amp;rsquo;m going to walk through the thought process.
So i needed to do a application basically (webapp) with user login, registration, with admin privilages, then with adding item, updating the item, deleting the item, assigning the item, reassign the item etc.</description></item><item><title> My experience with php</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/my-experience-with-php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:19:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/my-experience-with-php/</guid><description>Heya&amp;hellip; ow are you doing? During the shot intervel between my last post and this post i did something interesting,, a guess???
I got addicted to php
I was assigned to do a task for some reason and it involved doing things with php. ofcourse i could have done the same with let us see&amp;hellip;what are the options available.
i could have went with firebase as i already have prior experience, but nah went with node and all its glory.</description></item></channel></rss>