<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Bluepie's update blog</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Bluepie's update blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:21:31 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android Reversing Part 4</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:21:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/06/android-reversing-part-4/</guid><description>Hi me!, how are you doing, how is the future holding up?
Personal Update: It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple weeks since the last post, Covid-19 has shown no rate of slowing down. Nothing been around my mind lately just junk&amp;hellip; a lot of junk I don&amp;rsquo;t want to think about. To many frequent decisions, Once a friend told me Self control over your thoughts is very important. No matter what I do, It seems I can not achieve it.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 3</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 04:55:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/android-reversing-part-3/</guid><description>Hi!, Its nice to post weekely for a change, I never posted weekely before, anyway this might be a one time thing(posting weekely).
Disclaimer : Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Let&amp;rsquo;s start &amp;amp; why If you forgot for some reason, this is part-3 of android reversing/modding, I recommend checking out the previous post &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Android Reversing Part 2&amp;rdquo; in &amp;lsquo;reversing category&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Github Workflow</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/05/github-workflow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 23:32:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/05/github-workflow/</guid><description>Hi&amp;hellip; how ya been, its been a month already, gosh times flies by really fast. Status update: I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing good, When I am in home I complete the work that I plan&amp;hellip; far better than when I am in Chennai. The corona virus pandemic is still around the world at large, US right now is the largest affected country with over 70k dead people as of writing this. The lockdown in India has been extended another 2 weeks.</description></item><item><title>Xkcd Declutter</title><link>//bluepie.in/2020/04/xkcd-declutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:43:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2020/04/xkcd-declutter/</guid><description>Hi, how are you doing Im doing good, the corona virus pandemic is everywhere! hope your survived the ordeal, its still going on as of writing this, Hope you survive this.. In my childhood after watching movies like &amp;lsquo;i am legend&amp;rsquo; &amp;amp; &amp;lsquo;the day that the earth stood still&amp;rsquo;, i always wanted to see the world in the situtation, oh booy, i did not expect them to happen irl, but it did anyway.</description></item><item><title>Liunx LD_PRELOAD</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 17:28:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/12/linux-ld_preload/</guid><description>Hello me, this is going to be a short post that is very interesting to me and I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I have missed this all this time, I&amp;rsquo;ve known to break binary files directly by directly debugging them, mostly the windows files are binary extensions, I have worked even on dll files, which is somewhat similar to .so files on linux, both perform the same functions except that linux part is open source, and i&amp;rsquo;ve seen many articles using this partuclar approrach in many different ways(ofcourse after knowing about this only, I searched for those articles), A bit of personal update - so its been a tough month actually, progress interms of self development is zero, progress in terms of social level is a wip, but still a development.</description></item><item><title>Game Dev</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/11/game-dev/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 11:46:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/11/game-dev/</guid><description>Hey!, hope you are doing well!, im good, This post should have gone up in the month of august and this post should have been a follow-up, anyway never too late. Update: Im following a tight schedule for the past few weeks, tight-schedule in the sense &amp;ldquo;wake-up -&amp;gt; commute-to-office -&amp;gt; professional code-&amp;gt; aftier-office -&amp;gt; passion code -&amp;gt; sleep&amp;rdquo; throw in breaks, travel, and Personal hygene time in there, at-first it was awful, but after some while got the hang of it,Infact it became like addiction to me at this point &amp;amp; im craving for more.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing Part 2</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 19:30:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/10/android-reversing-part-2/</guid><description>hey, how ya been. so this is a another reversing post (reverse engineering android mod). So before some months, I gave some basic info to reversing android apps with a practical example(ttorrent). This post is gona build on top of that post. basically pretty advanced version of that post.
Im just sharing information &amp;amp; not distrubuting mod files here! this is strictly for learning purposes only. Starting off Let&amp;rsquo;s just continue where we left off shall we.</description></item><item><title>Docker to Make Life Easier</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/09/docker-to-make-life-easier/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 09:17:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/09/docker-to-make-life-easier/</guid><description>Hello, it&amp;rsquo;s been two months since last update. Anyway the August month I was pretty busy, to be honest, I was involved in a old project of mine that I had to revist, in order to get more productive and flexibility in developing the application I chose to use docker. So this post is going to be about docker.
Status Update:The month of August also had something interesting in it, which is my birthday.</description></item><item><title>Android Reversing</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 22:40:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/07/android-reversing/</guid><description>Hello! me and others reading this from the future. Status Update:So, this month I have lost a companion that was with me for the past 4 years, he is not entirely dead but let&amp;rsquo;s say is not the same person he once was&amp;hellip;.wait wait wait! I am talking about my laptop. I was doing an all-nighter &amp;amp; I think it was about 4 a.m. or so I was planning to go to sleep, so so while I was cleaning up &amp;amp; I dropped the laptop from my waist height, I was one of the tallest persons in my class so that explains a lot.</description></item><item><title>Google Ctf 2019</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 18:35:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/06/google-ctf-2019/</guid><description>hey!. future me,(addressing myself) Status Update:So its been almost a year since i joined a company and having my career growing, but my personal goals are just at the same position when i left my student life. Gosh wish things where different, So another long time since i made my last post. time really flies by, so the most part im ok i guess with inner conflicts, mental forgetfullness, slow motion, slow thinking.</description></item><item><title>ModSecurity</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/05/modsecurity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 23:32:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/05/modsecurity/</guid><description>so hello.. how are you doing..? how is life? im good, thank you!. Status Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve seen better days tbh, i&amp;rsquo;ve faced a lot of challenges this month, im having burnout? wtf! what is that? you ask&amp;rsquo;? just google it.. In the entirety of my life, i never hated computers and programming/ developing in general, but recently i grown a haterd to computers and coding disgusts me.. like WTH? im like the polar opposite of myself, i never thought i would reach this moment in life, funny is&amp;rsquo;nt it?</description></item><item><title>Android Service Binders</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/04/android-service-binders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:24:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/04/android-service-binders/</guid><description>hola amigos&amp;rsquo;, how are you guys doing? im fine thank you!. Status Update: About last week, I have covered some ground interms of development in old passion projects, the start of the week was great, but at the end of the week it got worse, nevertheless im happy that i survived this week &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;. Saw avengers end game the other day which was cool, during part-I I was studying, but for part-II -an adult going to office (feels wierd even to think, So much change in just one year), Personally nothing great happened, because of the mind that i have, I had the same bs.</description></item><item><title>Blog Migration</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/04/blog-migration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 03:02:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/04/blog-migration/</guid><description>heya!, this wont be a rant..trust me!, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I lost my cool in the last few posts, well thats aside, let me begin.
migration so i have been planning to migrate my blog from aws to replace it with jekyll, hexo,..etc, The main reason being, i run my blog in php and thus intend to replace it with the mentioned above, The another this that I keep pondering over and over is that, if i abandon my aws blog, I have to convert my previous post from the blog to the new version, reformat, reupload the images as well.</description></item><item><title> A peek into my yunger self.</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</guid><description>Hey guys how y&amp;rsquo;all been,
i&amp;rsquo;ve been good, in fact i am happy after a long time, So im gona love talking about this, so here is the thing before like 7-8 months (before i got my job) i was fully involved in reverse engineering, modding mostly windows, but also old linux machines with security flaws to train for some capture the flags and the plain curisity of&amp;hellip; lets say how to break stuff.</description></item><item><title> AI - with algorithms.(Rant mostly)</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/03/ai-with-algorithms-rant-mostly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:27:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/03/ai-with-algorithms-rant-mostly/</guid><description>Well hello guys! How yr&amp;rsquo; been.
what is going on. i have never thought of me doing this in my life, but this situation has come, so in the past month i have been trying to post and update whats been going on. But i am unable to complete what i started and it is bothering me still now, after that happened i stumbled upon an another old project of mine, which i cleaned up and finished it in a short span and btw this is the project that i am talking about that i didn&amp;rsquo;t complete.</description></item><item><title> ssh tunnel</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/01/ssh-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 06:00:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/01/ssh-tunnel/</guid><description>hey there!
How are you guys doing, hope everyone is doing good, im doing great btw, So today i wana talk about something that i have been using a lot lately in work and personal use, the thing that i wana talk about is ssh tunneling, its a huge topic, i have been using it ever since i learned about ssh in college, So what is this?
Info, Scenario and usage You guys might have heard about vpn, nowadays its everywhere it is basically that except that its done via ssh.</description></item><item><title> file Manager contd..</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-contd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 20:56:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-contd/</guid><description>a little update: Though i made a promise to post every two weeks, its been 4 weeks, why? ..is this&amp;hellip; i was going in a flow, but things started affecting.. rather i let things affect me, lately lot of things happened personally, lot of things reminded of the past, that made me avoid _________ in the present,
Continuation. Pick up where i left off from previous post: Let me explain the way of approach i wanted to do, i wanted to access all the files of the server, like i wanted to go back to the root directory, back before that, basically anywhere where i wanted, So DirectoryIterator seemed the best choice, We are in a directory, we have to list all the files and folders in the directory, how would you do that?</description></item><item><title> file manager development</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 19:21:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/10/file-manager-development/</guid><description>why this all of a sudden? I was introduced to php development for a little while now, and i had this in mind with several other things, this would also be a good point to start explaining with code, So where to start. let us define? It starts with what is the requirement? It is
I want to view files in the server, I can traverse through the files with forward and backward traversing, i can see the file modification date I can see the file ownership information, I can see file icons and folder icons.</description></item><item><title> MVC pattern</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/09/mvc-pattern/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 01:18:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/09/mvc-pattern/</guid><description>Dear Internet I didn&amp;rsquo;t blog for 2 weeks and it feels weird. i promise to write within every two weeks from here on now&amp;hellip; i am terribly sorry!.This post is to clear up the silence that stagnated over the past 2 weeks. sry btw.
Today I would like to share a thing (to tell my future self) that I learned in the recent weeks. It&amp;rsquo;s MVC. I was introduced to MVC pattern for developing applications.</description></item><item><title> Tamper Monkey</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/08/tamper-monkey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:04:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/08/tamper-monkey/</guid><description>Hi again, Today I am going to share something that is somewhat related to reverse engineering. Well I was working on a project, at one point of time I was working on wireframes, since I was only doing the initial design and it would be just used as a reference by the design team so my senior adviced me to use mockup.
Mockup So what is mockup you ask?</description></item><item><title> Software engineering and backend design</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/08/software-engineering-and-backend-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 21:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/08/software-engineering-and-backend-design/</guid><description>Today I wanna share something that I found was very useful in the recent times, which is ofcourse software engineering and backend design When I started developing.. at first I was a noob &amp;lsquo;as people would call&amp;rsquo; I would do random sh**&amp;hellip; I can explain this in more detail.. which is I would go straight to coding, learning the concepts that I need to implement a certain feature.. sometimes I would chase a particular feature first for the first day.</description></item><item><title>About android services</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/about-android-services/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:15:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/about-android-services/</guid><description>Recently i was involved in android dev..So im gona share a short struggle in android services.
Why So i was targeting android 5.1 and the basic feature was setting up and do some action for every % minutes, so this varies.. below 6.0 everything was fine and was working flawlessly but i was testing it on a mobile with android 6.1.
Doze Since the new android versions comes with android doze enabled, and every manufacturer has their own implementation of doze enabled with custom implementations starting from android 6.</description></item><item><title> Php Contd..</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/php-contd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 16:48:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/php-contd/</guid><description>As i mentioned in the previous post.. i choose php and ignored rest of them because i wanted to do a project in php for a long time and i choose to use this as an opportunity.
So i&amp;rsquo;m going to walk through the thought process.
So i needed to do a application basically (webapp) with user login, registration, with admin privilages, then with adding item, updating the item, deleting the item, assigning the item, reassign the item etc.</description></item><item><title> My experience with php</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/07/my-experience-with-php/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 17:19:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/07/my-experience-with-php/</guid><description>Heya&amp;hellip; ow are you doing? During the shot intervel between my last post and this post i did something interesting,, a guess???
I got addicted to php
I was assigned to do a task for some reason and it involved doing things with php. ofcourse i could have done the same with let us see&amp;hellip;what are the options available.
i could have went with firebase as i already have prior experience, but nah went with node and all its glory.</description></item></channel></rss>