<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cracks and patches on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</title><link>//bluepie.in/categories/cracks-and-patches/</link><description>Recent content in Cracks and patches on Bluepie&#39;s update blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bluepie.in/categories/cracks-and-patches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> A peek into my yunger self.</title><link>//bluepie.in/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2019/03/a-peek-into-my-yunger-self/</guid><description>Hey guys how y&amp;rsquo;all been,
i&amp;rsquo;ve been good, in fact i am happy after a long time, So im gona love talking about this, so here is the thing before like 7-8 months (before i got my job) i was fully involved in reverse engineering, modding mostly windows, but also old linux machines with security flaws to train for some capture the flags and the plain curisity of&amp;hellip; lets say how to break stuff.</description></item><item><title> Tamper Monkey</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/08/tamper-monkey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 03:04:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/08/tamper-monkey/</guid><description>Hi again, Today I am going to share something that is somewhat related to reverse engineering. Well I was working on a project, at one point of time I was working on wireframes, since I was only doing the initial design and it would be just used as a reference by the design team so my senior adviced me to use mockup.
Mockup So what is mockup you ask?</description></item><item><title> Contd..of Initial release of idm patcher</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/06/contd-of-initial-release-of-idm-patcher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 14:10:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/06/contd-of-initial-release-of-idm-patcher/</guid><description>Hi, well yesterday i didnt post due to unforseen circumstances, thats that.. i would like to continue the previous post.. well lets get into it.
I made an api and deployed it.. here is the demo link of the api incase you want to test it. api &amp;lt;----- [highlight color=&amp;ldquo;yellow&amp;rdquo;]Well the reason for this whole thing is that i wanted to refresh my memory in c#[/highlight]
Below is the application in action.</description></item><item><title> idm patcher initial release</title><link>//bluepie.in/2018/05/idm-patcher/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 01:22:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bluepie.in/2018/05/idm-patcher/</guid><description>MainIdeacreating a simple working patcher for all people. [divider style=&amp;ldquo;solid&amp;rdquo; top=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; bottom=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo;] Well the idea was there to create a new patch for almost 2 years, but never really acted on it, since I wrote a custom AOB patcher and that worked for my personal use without any errors.Pirating way of life.[/caption] Since the non tech peeps and other wild creatures of the human species often look for a elegant solution.</description></item></channel></rss>